<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <channel>
        <title>Phys.org - latest science and technology news stories</title>
        <link>https://phys.org/</link>
        
        <item>
            <id>news666625151</id>
            <title>First successful demonstration of quantum error correction of qudits for quantum computers</title>
            <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-05-successful-quantum-error-qudits.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">news666625151</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 12:00:01 EDT</updated>
                
            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/first-successful-exper.jpg"/>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    In the world of quantum computing, the Hilbert space dimension—the measure of the number of quantum states that a quantum computer can access—is a prized possession. Having a larger Hilbert space allows for more complex quantum operations and plays a crucial role in enabling quantum error correction (QEC), essential for protecting quantum information from noise and errors.
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>news666605522</id>
            <title>Nanoparticle-cell interface enables electromagnetic wireless programming of mammalian transgene expression</title>
            <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-05-nanoparticle-cell-interface-enables-electromagnetic.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">news666605522</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 08:20:01 EDT</updated>
                
            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/a-nanoparticle-cell-in-2.jpg"/>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    Recent technological advances are fueling the development of cutting-edge technologies that can monitor and control physiological processes with high precision. These include devices that could control the expression of genes within living organisms, without requiring invasive surgeries or procedures.
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>news666686156</id>
            <title>3D modeling demystifies the Parthenon's lighting conditions in ancient Greece</title>
            <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-05-3d-demystifies-parthenon-conditions-ancient.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">news666686156</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 07:40:01 EDT</updated>
                
            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/parthenon.jpg"/>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    The Parthenon, a mid-5th-century temple atop the hill of the Acropolis, is dedicated to Athena, the Greek deity of wisdom and the patron goddess of Athens. Despite enduring damage, that masterpiece remains a quintessential example of Classical Greek architecture, celebrated for the impressive 40-foot-tall chryselephantine (inlaid gold-and-ivory) statue of Athena housed within.
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>news666767273</id>
            <title>Tunisian 'revolution oasis' palm grove thrives on self-rule</title>
            <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-05-tunisian-revolution-oasis-palm-grove.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">news666767273</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 06:07:59 EDT</updated>
                
            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/tahar-ettahri-we-came.jpg"/>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    Since the inhabitants of Jemna in southern Tunisia wrested control of their 100-year-old palm grove from the state during the 2011 Revolution, residents say their lives have radically improved.
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>news666767136</id>
            <title>Indian space agency's satellite mission fails due to technical issue in launch vehicle</title>
            <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-05-indian-space-agency-satellite-mission.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">news666767136</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 06:05:40 EDT</updated>
                
            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/indian-space-agencys-s.jpg"/>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    The Indian space agency's mission to launch into orbit a new Earth observation satellite failed after the launch vehicle encountered a technical issue during the third stage of flight, officials said Sunday.
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>news666767055</id>
            <title>Severe storms, tornadoes kill more than 25 in south-central US</title>
            <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-05-severe-storms-tornadoes-south-central.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">news666767055</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 06:04:22 EDT</updated>
                
            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/the-storm-destroyed-hu.jpg"/>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    Severe storms that tore through the US states of Missouri, Kentucky and Virginia left more than 25 people dead, leveling homes and businesses while knocking out power for tens of thousands, authorities say.
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>news666544191</id>
            <title>Scientists rediscover orange tree variety that may be tolerant to greening disease</title>
            <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-05-scientists-rediscover-orange-tree-variety.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">news666544191</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 00:59:11 EDT</updated>
                
            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/orange-you-glad-that-r.jpg"/>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    ARS scientists made a "sweet" discovery that may be important to solving a major problem within the citrus industry.
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>news666710524</id>
            <title>Tornadoes kill more than 20 in south-central US</title>
            <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-05-tornadoes-south-central.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">news666710524</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sat, 17 May 2025 14:22:08 EDT</updated>
                
            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/local-residents-search.jpg"/>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    Severe storms swept through the US states of Missouri and Kentucky, leaving at least 21 people dead, laying waste to local communities and cutting off electricity to nearly 200,000 people, authorities said Saturday.
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>news666625088</id>
            <title>Ancient cemeteries and rock art discovered on Morocco's Tangier Peninsula</title>
            <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-05-ancient-cemeteries-art-morocco-tangier.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">news666625088</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sat, 17 May 2025 11:00:01 EDT</updated>
                
            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/ancient-cemeteries-fou.jpg"/>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    A trio of archaeologists from the University of Barcelona and the University of Castilla-La Mancha, both in Spain, and the National Institute of Archaeology and Heritage in Morocco have discovered three ancient cemeteries on the Tangier Peninsula. In their study, published in the journal African Archaeological Review, Hamza Benattia, Jorge Onrubia-Pintado and Youssef Bokbot conducted fieldwork on the peninsula.
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>news666608803</id>
            <title>Australian researchers use a quantum computer to simulate how real molecules behave</title>
            <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-05-australian-quantum-simulate-real-molecules.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">news666608803</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sat, 17 May 2025 10:50:01 EDT</updated>
                
            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/australian-researchers-1.jpg"/>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    When a molecule absorbs light, it undergoes a whirlwind of quantum-mechanical transformations. Electrons jump between energy levels, atoms vibrate, and chemical bonds shift—all within millionths of a billionth of a second.
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>news666447144</id>
            <title>Twin spacecraft mission reveals there might be a 'hot' side of the moon</title>
            <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-05-twin-spacecraft-mission-reveals-hot.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">news666447144</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sat, 17 May 2025 10:20:01 EDT</updated>
                
            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/there-might-be-a-hot-s.jpg"/>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    The moon's nearside (that is, the side facing Earth) is dark-colored and dominated by ancient lava flows, whereas the farside is more rugged—and NASA researchers now suggest it's due to a wonky lunar interior. Using data from twin spacecraft named Ebb and Flow, they found a 2–3% difference in the moon mantle's ability to deform on each side. They say this data could be explained by the nearest hemisphere's insides being up to 170°C hotter than the farside.
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>news666588036</id>
            <title>Living beings emit a faint light that extinguishes upon death, according to a new study</title>
            <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-05-emit-faint-extinguishes-death.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">news666588036</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sat, 17 May 2025 10:00:01 EDT</updated>
                
            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/living-beings-emit-a-f-3.jpg"/>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    The light of someone's life might not be just another person, but light in the literal sense. According to a recent study by researchers from University of Calgary, every living system emits light without requiring external excitation due to a biological phenomenon known as ultraweak photon emission (UPE).
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>news666617318</id>
            <title>Saturday Citations: Protoplanetary cornucopia; trees abound; the importance of diversity in corporate boards</title>
            <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-05-saturday-citations-protoplanetary-cornucopia-trees.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">news666617318</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sat, 17 May 2025 08:30:01 EDT</updated>
                
            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/saturday-citations-pro.jpg"/>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    This week, paleontologists reported finding new details in an Archaeopteryx fossil via CT scanning and UV light exposure. NASA engineers revived a set of thrusters aboard Voyager 1 that had been considered inoperable in 2004. And researchers are challenging a set of evolutionary assumptions regarding the importance of an ancient protein motif.
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>news666685169</id>
            <title>Angler fishing in Lake Michigan fog discovers remains of abandoned tugboat J.C. Ames</title>
            <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-05-angler-fishing-lake-michigan-fog.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">news666685169</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sat, 17 May 2025 07:19:39 EDT</updated>
                
            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/angler-fishing-in-lake.jpg"/>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    A Wisconsin angler fishing in the fog this week discovered the wreck of an abandoned tugboat submerged in the waters of Lake Michigan for more than a century, state officials announced Friday.
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>news666684774</id>
            <title>'Alpha predator' sharks and humans clash on an Israeli beach</title>
            <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-05-alpha-predator-sharks-humans-clash.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">news666684774</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sat, 17 May 2025 07:13:01 EDT</updated>
                
            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/sharks-getting-closer.jpg"/>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    With its golden sand and blue waters, the beachfront in central Israel looks much like any other stretch of Mediterranean coast, but a closer look reveals something unusual peeking through the rippling surf: black shark fins.
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>news666617396</id>
            <title>Study calls for greater coordination between the European Central Bank and national fiscal policies</title>
            <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-05-greater-european-central-bank-national.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">news666617396</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sat, 17 May 2025 03:30:02 EDT</updated>
                
            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/european-central-bank.jpg"/>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    Researchers at the University of Seville have analyzed interdependencies between fiscal and monetary policies and economic growth in Eurozone countries. The study highlights the need for greater coordination between the monetary policy of the European Central Bank (ECB) and national fiscal policies.
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>news666510910</id>
            <title>Life, death and mowing: Study reveals Britain's poetic obsession with the humble lawnmower</title>
            <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-05-life-death-reveals-britain-poetic.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">news666510910</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Fri, 16 May 2025 19:00:01 EDT</updated>
                
            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/life-death-and-mowing-1.jpg"/>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    Over the last half-century, British poets including Philip Larkin and Andrew Motion have driven a "lawnmower poetry microgenre," using the machine to explore childhood, masculinity, violence, addiction, mortality and much more, new research shows.
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>news666625566</id>
            <title>Synthetic materials mimic seashells to enhance energy absorption</title>
            <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-05-synthetic-materials-mimic-seashells-energy.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">news666625566</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Fri, 16 May 2025 14:50:01 EDT</updated>
                
            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/study-finds-that-indiv.jpg"/>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    Millions of years of evolution have enabled some marine animals to grow complex protective shells composed of multiple layers that work together to dissipate physical stress. In a new study, engineers have found a way to mimic the behavior of this type of layered material, such as seashell nacre, by programming individual layers of synthetic material to work collaboratively under stress. The new material design is poised to enhance energy-absorbing systems such as wearable bandages and car bumpers with multistage responses that adapt to collision severity.
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>news666625056</id>
            <title>Low-emission zones linked to improved air quality in Belgian cities</title>
            <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-05-emission-zones-linked-air-quality.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">news666625056</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Fri, 16 May 2025 14:37:45 EDT</updated>
                
            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/low-emission-zones-fou-1.jpg"/>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    A team of health and environmental researchers affiliated with multiple institutions in Belgium, working together due to a request from health insurer Mutualités Libres, has found that converting parts of cities to low-emission zones (LEZs) improves air quality. In their study, published in the journal Environment International, the group compared air quality samples in LEZs with similar sites in other cities without LEZs.
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>news666624935</id>
            <title>Microbial monitoring in reef waters offers accessible tool for ecosystem management</title>
            <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-05-microbial-reef-accessible-tool-ecosystem.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">news666624935</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Fri, 16 May 2025 14:35:43 EDT</updated>
                
            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/seawater-microbes-are.jpg"/>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    Corals everywhere on the planet live in harmony with microscopic organisms. Many corals get their vivid colors from microscopic algae which lives inside the corals' tissue and provides the coral with food. Even in the water surrounding coral reefs, there is a microscopic soup of bacteria, archaea, and other types of microbes that respond to changes in the habitat and can indicate whether or not the coral reef is healthy.
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>news666624901</id>
            <title>Researchers find elevated levels of mercury in Colorado mountain wetlands</title>
            <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-05-elevated-mercury-colorado-mountain-wetlands.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">news666624901</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Fri, 16 May 2025 14:35:04 EDT</updated>
                
            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/colorado-moutains.jpg"/>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    Climate change is melting glaciers and permafrost in the mountains outside of Boulder, Colorado, exposing rocks and freeing up minerals containing sulfate, a form of sulfur, to flow downstream into local watersheds.
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>news666624378</id>
            <title>Ocean microbes offer clues to environmental resilience</title>
            <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-05-ocean-microbes-clues-environmental-resilience.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">news666624378</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Fri, 16 May 2025 14:26:22 EDT</updated>
                
            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/ocean-microbes-offer-c.jpg"/>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    Researchers at the University of Colorado Boulder and Oak Ridge National Laboratory have developed a new way to identify genetic changes that help tiny oxygen-producing microbes survive in extreme environments. The findings outline a new experimental approach for learning how microbes and other types of cells, including human cells, respond and adapt to environmental stress.
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>news666623582</id>
            <title>Theoretical model provides fresh route to more efficient cooling using light and heat</title>
            <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-05-theoretical-fresh-route-efficient-cooling.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">news666623582</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Fri, 16 May 2025 14:13:03 EDT</updated>
                
            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/fresh-route-to-more-ef.jpg"/>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    As climate change and growing energy demands strain global systems, scientists are increasingly turning to passive cooling technologies—ways to cool objects or spaces without using electricity. One promising method is radiative cooling, which works by reflecting sunlight and releasing heat in the form of infrared radiation into space. But despite its potential, this method is limited by natural laws that cap how much heat can be emitted. Now, a proposed theoretical model has the potential to boost the power of radiative cooling, potentially changing the way we manage heat in a warming world.
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>news666623401</id>
            <title>Optimizing rice mill lab analysis can improve yield, consumer qualities</title>
            <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-05-optimizing-rice-mill-lab-analysis.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">news666623401</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Fri, 16 May 2025 14:10:06 EDT</updated>
                
            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/optimizing-rice-mill-l.jpg"/>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    Before it gets to your table in a steaming dish, rice has to go through the mill. More specifically, the unprocessed rice kernels that are encased in an inedible hull must undergo milling to reveal the white rice grain.
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>news666623222</id>
            <title>Very different mammals follow the same rules of behavior: Research hints at an underlying architecture</title>
            <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-05-mammals-behavior-hints-underlying-architecture.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">news666623222</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Fri, 16 May 2025 14:07:04 EDT</updated>
                
            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/very-different-mammals.jpg"/>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    In the natural world—where predators pounce, prey flee, and group members feed and sleep in solidarity—animal behavior is glorious in its variety. Now, new research suggests there may be an underlying architecture that orders the movements of animals as they go about their very different lives. And it's more widespread than previously imagined.
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>news666612842</id>
            <title>Healing the ozone hole helps the Southern Ocean take up carbon, study reveals</title>
            <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-05-ozone-hole-southern-ocean-carbon.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">news666612842</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Fri, 16 May 2025 14:00:01 EDT</updated>
                
            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2023/ocean.jpg"/>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    New research suggests that the negative effects of the ozone hole on the carbon uptake of the Southern Ocean are reversible, but only if greenhouse gas emissions rapidly decrease.
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>news666622621</id>
            <title>Ancient ocean sediments link changes in currents to cooling of Northern Hemisphere 3.6 million years ago</title>
            <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-05-ancient-ocean-sediments-link-currents.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">news666622621</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Fri, 16 May 2025 13:57:04 EDT</updated>
                
            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/ancient-ocean-sediment-2.jpg"/>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    New research from an international group looking at ancient sediment cores in the North Atlantic has for the first time shown a strong correlation between sediment changes and a marked period of global cooling that occurred in the Northern Hemisphere some 3.6 million years ago. The changes in sediments imply that profound changes in the circulation of deep water currents occurred at this time.
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>news666622501</id>
            <title>Subtle ligand modifications in aluminum complexes unlock enhanced solid-state light emission</title>
            <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-05-subtle-ligand-modifications-aluminum-complexes.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">news666622501</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Fri, 16 May 2025 13:55:04 EDT</updated>
                
            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/scientists-tune-light.jpg"/>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    Artificial light, once a luxury, has become central to modern life, with its evolution spanning from fire to LEDs. Now, researchers have developed a new class of efficient light-emitting materials as promising candidates to be applied to lighten the darkness. They demonstrated easily accessible aluminum-based organometallic complexes that have the potential to be applied in optoelectronic devices.
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>news666620041</id>
            <title>GPS for proteins: Tracking the motions of cell receptors</title>
            <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-05-gps-proteins-tracking-motions-cell.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">news666620041</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Fri, 16 May 2025 13:14:03 EDT</updated>
                
            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/gps-for-proteins-track.jpg"/>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    Taste, pain, or response to stress—nearly all essential functions in the human body are regulated by molecular switches called G protein-coupled receptors (GPCRs). Researchers at the University of Basel have uncovered the fundamental mechanism for how such a GPCR works.
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>news666618501</id>
            <title>Structural mechanism reveals how antibiotic resistance to fusidic acid works</title>
            <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-05-mechanism-reveals-antibiotic-resistance-fusidic.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">news666618501</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Fri, 16 May 2025 12:48:24 EDT</updated>
                
            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/new-molecular-movie-re.jpg"/>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    In an article published in Nature Communications, researchers from Uppsala Antibiotic Center, Uppsala University and SciLifeLab describe a fundamental mechanism of antibiotic resistance. What happens in a bacterium that is resistant to the antibiotic fusidic acid?
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>