<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <channel>
        <title>The Information</title>
        <link>https://www.theinformation.com</link>
        
        <item>
            <id>tag:www.theinformation.com,2005:Briefing/15202</id>
            <title>Nvidia in Talks to Invest in Quantum Computing Startup</title>
            <link>https://www.theinformation.com/briefings/nvidia-talks-invest-quantum-computing-startup</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.theinformation.com,2005:Briefing/15202</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>2025-05-19T02:08:41Z</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>Nvidia is in advanced talks to invest in PsiQuantum, a quantum computing startup, The Information reported on Sunday. The talks come as PsiQuantum is in the process of raising at least $750 million in a funding round.</p> <p>The investment would be the latest signal that Nvidia has shifted its stance ...</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>tag:www.theinformation.com,2005:Article/15061</id>
            <title>Nvidia in Talks to Invest in Quantum Startup PsiQuantum</title>
            <link>https://www.theinformation.com/articles/nvidia-talks-invest-quantum-startup-psiquantum</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.theinformation.com,2005:Article/15061</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>2025-05-19T02:22:44Z</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>Nvidia is in advanced talks to invest in PsiQuantum, a quantum computing startup, according to a person involved in the discussions.&nbsp;The investment would be the latest signal that Nvidia has shifted its stance on quantum computing after CEO Jensen Huang earlier this year seemed to cast doubt on the field, saying it was likely two decades away from being useful technology.</p>

<p>The talks come as PsiQuantum is in the process of raising at least $750 million in a funding round, according to four people involved in the deal.</p>

<p>With most of Nvidia’s investments&mdash;such as CoreWeave or xAI&mdash;it pours money into startups that either buy or rent large amounts of its graphics procesing unit. The PsiQuantum deal would represent Nvidia trying to get ahead of the next wave of computing&mdash;which some people think could be bigger than the AI wave but is still years away.</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>tag:www.theinformation.com,2005:Briefing/15201</id>
            <title>Japanese Beer Chief Blames Social Media, Gaming for Falling Sales</title>
            <link>https://www.theinformation.com/briefings/japanese-beer-chief-blames-social-media-gaming-falling-sales</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.theinformation.com,2005:Briefing/15201</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>2025-05-19T00:06:18Z</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>Young people’s interest in social media and video games has cut into the leisure time previous generations spent drinking, says&nbsp;Atsushi Katsuki, the chief executive of Asahi, a Japanese beer company. The increasing amount of time spent on digital entertainment outweighs a growing trend for ...</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>tag:www.theinformation.com,2005:Briefing/15200</id>
            <title>U.S. Officials Scrutinize Apple Intelligence Partnership With Alibaba</title>
            <link>https://www.theinformation.com/briefings/u-s-officials-scrutinize-apple-intelligence-partnership-alibaba</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.theinformation.com,2005:Briefing/15200</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>2025-05-17T22:15:04Z</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>The U.S. government is scrutinizing Apple’s plan to work with Chinese tech giant Alibaba to release&nbsp;AI features in China, The New York Times reported.</p> <p>U.S. officials are worried the deal will help Alibaba improve its AI capabilities, broaden the reach of Chinese chatbots that censor ...</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>tag:www.theinformation.com,2005:Article/15060</id>
            <title>Behind Microsoft Layoffs, Automation Efforts Boom</title>
            <link>https://www.theinformation.com/articles/behind-microsoft-layoffs-automation-efforts-boom</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.theinformation.com,2005:Article/15060</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>2025-05-19T02:20:28Z</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>Jeff Hulse, a Microsoft vice president who oversees roughly 400 software engineers, told the team in recent months to use the company’s artificial intelligence chatbot, powered by OpenAI, to generate half the computer code they write, according to a person who heard the remarks. That would represent an increase from the 20% to 30% of code AI currently produces at the company, and shows how rapidly Microsoft is moving to incorporate such technology.</p>

<p>Then on Tuesday, Microsoft laid off more than a dozen engineers on Hulse’s team as part of a broader layoff of 6,000 people across the company that appeared to hit engineers harder than other types of roles, this person said.</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>tag:www.theinformation.com,2005:Article/15057</id>
            <title>Is Brian Chesky’s Big Bet Big Enough?</title>
            <link>https://www.theinformation.com/articles/brian-cheskys-big-bet-big-enough</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.theinformation.com,2005:Article/15057</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>2025-05-17T20:43:59Z</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p><b>Welcome, Weekenders</b>! In this newsletter:</p><p>• <i>The Big Read: </i>The AI <a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/bots-bust-servicenows-bill-mcdermott-makes-bet-ai">euphoria—and peril</a>—driving ServiceNow’s Bill McDermott</p><p>• <i>The Top 5: </i>Silicon Valley’s <a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/exotic-fitness-goals-tech-elite">most exotic fitness goals</a></p><p>• <i>Plus, our Recommendations:</i> A wager to save a dad; “Fargo” in Maine; and a band of brothers from Down Under</p><hr /><p><b>Lately, I’ve lived exactly</b> as Brian Chesky might want. Yet the experience has been deeply imperfect and a reflection of what could derail his megagrowth plans.</p><p>While visiting Mexico City last weekend, I filled a hole in a morning’s itinerary with a cooking class available on Airbnb’s Experiences feature. It was tremendous fun, with Vanessa, a chef in the megalopolis’ Roma neighborhood, dispensing age-old wisdom about tortillas (less masa is more), guacamole (add tomatillo) and dried-chile salsa (never spiced to the point of suffering, she insists).</p><p>I studied at Vanessa’s elbow just a couple days before Chesky unveiled a major revamp to Airbnb that hopes to turn it into a giant marketplace of bookings—a place to secure a massage, a photo shoot or a guided hike. The move greatly expands on Experiences, which since its 2016 launch has not lived up to Chesky’s expectations, and pushes Airbnb into micromarkets across the world. Thousands and thousands and thousands of Vanessas! And other small business owners like her who are eager to supplement their incomes.&nbsp;</p><p>But I have some doubts about the plan (as does <a href="https://stratechery.com/2025/airbnbs-new-app-experiences-and-services-cheskys-founder-mode/">Ben Thompson</a>), and the experience I’ve had with Airbnb since arriving in Los Angeles from Mexico City underscores a chief concern: I’m writing this from a West Hollywood apartment that sure looked nice from the pictures and cost nearly as much as a four-star hotel. Sitting here, though, I can only conclude those images benefited from some substantial amount of special effects magic. In reality, it is an aging, grimly appointed place; I picture some Raymond Chandler villain storming through the front door at any moment.</p><p>More than a decade into Airbnb’s existence, a booking on the app is still a total roll of the dice for the most part, and any frequent Airbnb user knows it. Sometimes it’s as advertised, but often it’s not. The inconsistency undoubtedly puts a limit on the customer base, a partial explanation as to why Airbnb hasn’t grown as much as Chesky has wanted recently.</p><p>If Airbnb hasn’t managed to solve the flaw in its core business, surely those new micromarkets will have the same problem—possibly in an exacerbated form since Airbnb wants to substantially broaden itself in unfamiliar settings and economies. How many people will pay for all these new services? I’m not saying the concept will be a total flop, but I can’t picture Airbnb making it work on a gigantic scale, which is what Chesky needs to goose the company’s stubbornly disappointing stock price.</p><p>And another thing—but, oh, my god, what is that stain on the wall, and why is it moving?&nbsp;</p><p><b>What WBD’s Retreat Really Means</b>&nbsp;</p><p>A couple days ago, David Zaslav, the Warner Bros. Discovery chief, had to do what no one surely likes to do: publicly admit a mistake. But he did, and the company will re-rebrand (or is it a re-re-rebrand?) its streaming service, <a href="https://www.theinformation.com/briefings/warner-bros-discovery-renames-streaming-service-hbo-max?rc=sslhyj">returning its name</a> to HBO Max.&nbsp;</p><p>The decision was mostly interpreted through a lens of what it reflects about WBD. That’s an amusingly narrow view, because if you pull back the camera, it also represents a pretty concrete final moment in the Streaming Wars. So yes, let’s just say it explicitly: Netflix has won. No other streamer—not Peacock, not HBO Max, not even Amazon—is going to come close to matching its enormous catalog. There’s Netflix, and then there’s everyone else, who I suspect would be best served by figuring out what makes them bespoke—or letting the end credits roll.&nbsp;</p><p><b>Apple’s New Partner, Musk’s Old Rival&nbsp;</b></p><p>The most interesting development at Apple isn’t a new iPhone or an update to its virtual reality headset: It’s the brain-computer interface Apple is <a href="https://www.wsj.com/tech/apple-brain-computer-interface-9ec69919">reportedly</a> developing with Synchron, a competitor to Elon Musk’s Neuralink. Our Akash Pasricha had <a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/a-better-brain-chip-than-elon-musks?rc=sslhyj">a Big Read</a> on Synchron a couple months ago, and the revelation about its partnership with Apple adds a substantial amount of legitimacy to Synchron’s efforts. At the same time, Apple’s decision to partner with Synchron rather than Neuralink puts another puncture in the perception of Musk as an unmatchable genius. Which, really, is happening more and more <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/04/02/business/tesla-sales-elon-musk.html">these days</a>!<i>—Abram Brown</i></p><hr /><h2><b>Weekend’s Latest Stories</b></h2><h1 class="weekend-header">
<a href="https://www.theinformation.com/features/the-big-read">The Big Read</a> </h1><a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/bots-bust-servicenows-bill-mcdermott-makes-bet-ai"><figure><img src="https://tii.imgix.net/article/pictures/newsletters-production/d6905527-37e1-450e-a2e7-5033bd83b952-1IDWOC.jpg?auto=compress" /></figure></a><h2><a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/bots-bust-servicenows-bill-mcdermott-makes-bet-ai">Bots or Bust: ServiceNow’s Bill McDermott Makes an All-In Bet on AI</a></h2><p>Bill McDermott, ServiceNow’s CEO, is someone who drafts off mile-high dreams, ones that at times seem to defy reality. Or as the company’s vice chair, Nick Tzitzon, put it: “Bill will never be constrained by what other people’s version of a situation is.”</p><p>His vision has come to rest solely on artificial intelligence, as our Akash Pasricha reports <a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/bots-bust-servicenows-bill-mcdermott-makes-bet-ai">in Weekend’s latest Big Read</a>. But McDermott faces something of an uphill climb. His salespeople have to convince customers they need ServiceNow’s AI—while every other company is trying to do the same with their AI—and then teach them how to use its unfamiliar features. McDermott sees the reinvention of the company as a total necessity. As he told Akash: “If you always do what you always did, you’ll always get what you always got.”</p><h1 class="weekend-header"><a href="https://www.theinformation.com/features/the-top-5?rc=sslhyj">The Top Five</a></h1><figure><img src="https://tii.imgix.net/article/pictures/newsletters-production/d6905527-37e1-450e-a2e7-5033bd83b952-Ni82tG.jpg?auto=compress" /></figure><h2><a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/exotic-fitness-goals-tech-elite">The Exotic Fitness Goals of the Tech Elite</a></h2><p>When I was traveling over the past week, I felt proud of myself for sticking to my workout routine: a bunch of runs and even some early morning weightlifting at a gym near my dreary Airbnb. And then…I edited <a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/exotic-fitness-goals-tech-elite">this humbling piece</a> by our Nick Wingfield.</p><p>Nick tracked down a group of techies who’ve taken the same crazy drive that propels them at work and channeled it into some outlandish feats of fitness. They’re people who aren’t just satisfied they made it out for a couple miles: They measure their regimens in dozens of miles, which is exactly what Josh Ip, founder of Ranger, an AI startup, did to prepare for a self-organized 100-mile run around San Francisco last summer.</p><p>The run took Ip 29 hours to complete, and at different points, some of the investors in his startup ran alongside him. “Investors want you to be maniacal and tolerate any amount of pain. They also want to know you can run through walls,” Ip said. “If anything, me being able to do this was my way of showing, ‘Oh shit, this guy can do what he says he can do. If he can do that, I’m assuming he can build a startup.’”&nbsp;</p><p><i>Abram Brown, editor of The Information’s Weekend section, has an unblemished Airbnb rating—in case you were wondering. Reach him at </i><a href="mailto:abe@theinformation.com">abe@theinformation.com</a>.</p><hr /><figure><img src="https://tii.imgix.net/article/pictures/newsletters-production/0a0c76abb8-AVVbiS.jpg?auto=compress" /></figure><p><b>Listening: “Embedded: Alternate Realities” (NPR)&nbsp;</b></p><p>Generally,<b> </b>bets between family members are gentle affairs—wagers over bragging rights. Or a steak dinner at most. But the one NPR reporter Zach Mack made with his father in “<a href="https://www.npr.org/2026/01/01/1256998295/embedded-alternate-realities-bonus">Embedded: Alternate Realities</a>” was different: Nominally, it carried a $10,000 prize. In reality, the stakes were even higher: They gambled over nothing less than the family’s ability to stay together.&nbsp;</p><p>I’m not really reaching for hyperbole. Last year, Mack bet his father that 10 online conspiracy theories wouldn’t come true within a year—with Mack believing the strict timeline would be the only way to definitively prove them false to his father and prevent the family from breaking apart over his dad’s unshakable belief in them. Alas, the tale of a child trying to sober up a parent radicalized by the internet is an increasingly familiar one. Few are documented with such intimacy.<i>—A.B.</i></p><p><b>Reading: “The Savage, Noble Death of Babs Dionne” by Ron Currie&nbsp;</b></p><p>Imagine Maine, the state with “Vacationland” printed on license plates, and I promise whatever comes to mind is decidedly not the part of Maine ruthlessly controlled by Babs Dionne, a mother, grandmother and nightstick-wielding mobster. But Babs is losing her grip on her small-town turf, and over the course of the 24 hours presented in “<a href="https://www.amazon.com/Savage-Noble-Death-Babs-Dionne/dp/0593851668">The Savage, Noble Death of Babs Dionne</a>,” it slips fully through her fingers.&nbsp;</p><p>Mama Dionne has stretched her ambitions too far, enraging a rival outfit. In retaliation, her competitors dispatch a hitman known only as The Man, an Anton Chigurh of the north, who drives a spotless Impala rather than a pickup. To stave off The Man, Babs might hope to count on her military vet daughter, Lorie. But Lorie finds herself preoccupied by the ghostly apparitions of fallen comrades, possibly hallucinations from her spiraling opioid withdrawal. Like everyone around her, she is dogged by death and the deaths she’s caused.<i>—A.B.</i></p><p><b>Watching: “The Narrow Road to the Deep North” (Amazon Prime)</b></p><p>Often, the hell of war is shown through gruesome scenes from the battlefield. That’s not really the case in “<a href="https://www.amazon.com/Narrow-Road-Deep-North-Season/dp/B0DV5PZB9P">The Narrow Road to the Deep North</a>,” which nonetheless makes war’s dire realities abundantly clear. The five-episode show is a domestic drama and a prisoner-of-war series, skipping between three timelines in the life of a young British doctor, Dorrigo Evans, who joins family in Australia before fighting against Japan in World War II, an experience that curdles him. Jacob Elordi, the tall hunk from “Euphoria” and “Saltburn,” plays Dorrigo in the two earlier periods; a weathered and excellent Ciarán Hinds follows behind him, portraying Dorrigo in the 1980s. Together, they present halves of the same broken person, fitting together remarkably well.—<i>A.B.</i></p><hr /><h2><b>Final Thought</b></h2><p>You know—whatever works, folks!</p><a href="https://x.com/jackkuveke/status/1923051872400572531"><figure><img src="https://tii.imgix.net/article/pictures/newsletters-production/d6905527-37e1-450e-a2e7-5033bd83b952-277EeU.png?auto=compress" /></figure></a>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>tag:www.theinformation.com,2005:Article/15058</id>
            <title>The Exotic Fitness Goals of the Tech Elite</title>
            <link>https://www.theinformation.com/articles/exotic-fitness-goals-tech-elite</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.theinformation.com,2005:Article/15058</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>2025-05-18T17:19:19Z</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>When normies want to set lofty fitness goals for themselves, they train for half- or full-marathons. If they’re feeling ambitious, perhaps they shoot for a triathlon or a Tough Mudder. For the type A personalities of tech, though, those events are sometimes warmups, literally, for even more extravagant athletic feats.</p>

<p>Last Friday night, for example, Randi Zuckerberg&mdash;an early Facebook employee and the host of a tech-themed radio show on SiriusXM&mdash;crossed the finish line in Flagstaff, Ariz., at the end of a 257-mile ultramarathon called the Cocodona 250. Zuckerberg said that 10 of the 16 marathons (26.2 miles) and 3 of the 10 ultramarathons (31 or more miles) she had run over the prior few years were part of her training regimen for the grueling Arizona race, which took her 113 hours to complete.</p>

<p>“The Boston Marathon I did as my final long run,” said Zuckerberg, who is the sister of Meta Platforms CEO Mark Zuckerberg.</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>tag:www.theinformation.com,2005:Briefing/15199</id>
            <title>Google ‘Super Intensely’ Debated Buying Netflix, Google CEO Says</title>
            <link>https://www.theinformation.com/briefings/google-super-intensely-debated-buying-netflix-google-ceo-says</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.theinformation.com,2005:Briefing/15199</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>2025-05-17T22:15:06Z</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>Google at some point considered acquiring Netflix, Google CEO Sundar Pichai said in a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ReGC2GtWFp4">podcast interview</a> that aired Friday. “We debated Netflix at some point super intensely inside,” Pichai said, adding: “I wouldn’t call it regrets, but you always look back.”</p> <p>Pichai didn’t specify when ...</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>tag:www.theinformation.com,2005:Article/15030</id>
            <title>Why the Charter-Cox $34.5 Billion Cable Deal Matters</title>
            <link>https://www.theinformation.com/articles/charter-cox-34-5-billion-cable-deal-matters</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.theinformation.com,2005:Article/15030</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>2025-05-16T21:39:11Z</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>Misery loves company, as they say. <a href="https://www.theinformation.com/briefings/charter-acquire-cox-34-5-billion-create-new-cable-broadband-leader?rc=9byxri">Friday’s announcement</a> that two of the three biggest cable-broadband firms, Charter Communications and Cox Communications, are combining is a logical next step in the consolidation of a stagnant but still significant industry. Charter, whose biggest shareholder is controlled by aging cable magnate John Malone, is buying Cox Communications for $34.5 billion in cash, stock and assumption of debt. The resulting company, which will take the Cox name, will be by far the biggest cable-broadband company in the U.S., ahead of Comcast, which is now roughly equal to Charter in subscriber numbers.</p><p>Why should you care? Sure, if your focus is growth, then Charter, Cox and Comcast are yesterday’s companies. Malone, a star media dealmaker of the 1990s and early 2000s, is all but retired (the man once called the “Darth Vader” of cable last year gave up his nonvoting director emeritus position on Charter’s board). But the big cable companies are still the primary source of internet access for many, if not most, Americans, which makes them a little like the water company—a service people only think about when it doesn’t work. That makes their financial health important, given that they need to maintain the pipes that carry the internet to people’s homes and businesses.</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>tag:www.theinformation.com,2005:Briefing/15198</id>
            <title>Qualcomm to Launch Data Center Chip in Challenge to Nvidia</title>
            <link>https://www.theinformation.com/briefings/qualcomm-launch-data-center-chip-challenge-nvidia</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.theinformation.com,2005:Briefing/15198</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>2025-05-17T22:15:04Z</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>Qualcomm, known for designing and licensing smartphone processors, said earlier this week it would develop data center chips for artificial intelligence, starting in Saudi Arabia. The move adds Qualcomm to the long list of challengers to Nvidia, whose chips dominate the AI data center market.</p> <p> ...</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>tag:www.theinformation.com,2005:Briefing/15197</id>
            <title>Chobani Acquires Healthy Food Startup Daily Harvest</title>
            <link>https://www.theinformation.com/briefings/chobani-acquires-healthy-food-startup-daily-harvest</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.theinformation.com,2005:Briefing/15197</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>2025-05-17T22:15:05Z</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>Chobani said Friday it had acquired smoothie and frozen meal startup Daily Harvest, marking the latest dealmaking activity among healthy food startups. Terms of the acquisition weren’t disclosed.</p> <p>Daily Harvest was founded in 2015 and raised nearly $190 million total from investors at a peak ...</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>tag:www.theinformation.com,2005:Briefing/15196</id>
            <title>OpenAI Releases Coding Agent That Automates Work for Software Engineers</title>
            <link>https://www.theinformation.com/briefings/openai-releases-coding-agent-automates-work-software-engineers</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.theinformation.com,2005:Briefing/15196</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>2025-05-17T22:15:05Z</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>OpenAI said Friday it released an artificial intelligence coding “agent” that can automate software engineering tasks such as fixing bugs and answering questions about a codebase. It’s following startups including Anthropic and Cognition that have released similar coding assistants.</p> <p>The coding ...</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>tag:www.theinformation.com,2005:Article/15055</id>
            <title>Bots or Bust: ServiceNow’s Bill McDermott Makes an All-In Bet on AI</title>
            <link>https://www.theinformation.com/articles/bots-bust-servicenows-bill-mcdermott-makes-bet-ai</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.theinformation.com,2005:Article/15055</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>2025-05-18T17:02:33Z</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>Late on a Friday night in March, Bill McDermott, ServiceNow’s CEO and chairman, walked off a flight in San Jose, Calif., and then immediately asked his chief of staff to get his top sales and engineering execs on the phone. He had a task for them.</p>

<p>McDermott had just spent a week in New York meeting with customers, including the heads of banks and a sports league.&nbsp;They’d told him they had no idea where to start with AI, which has become a matter of foremost importance to <a href="https://www.theinformation.com/org-charts/servicenow?selected_employee=bill-mcdermott">ServiceNow</a>, a giant in the deeply unsexy business of making software for resolving issues in back-office departments such as IT, finance and HR.&nbsp;Many of the company’s latest programs involve AI, and McDermott has pinned a substantial portion of its growth to the technology&mdash;and to customers understanding its value.</p>

<p>In a 15-minute phone conversation with his lieutenants, McDermott outlined the details of a new AI consulting service for marquee clients&nbsp;that would arguably offer more hand-holding&nbsp;than any other such program offered by ServiceNow and gave them a tight deadline: He wanted it finalized in a couple weeks, so he could talk it up at ServiceNow’s 25,000-person customer conference at the Venetian Resort in Las Vegas.</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>tag:www.theinformation.com,2005:Briefing/15195</id>
            <title>TikTok Parent ByteDance Eyes 20% Revenue Growth in 2025</title>
            <link>https://www.theinformation.com/briefings/tiktok-parent-bytedance-eyes-20-revenue-growth-2025</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.theinformation.com,2005:Briefing/15195</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>2025-05-17T22:15:05Z</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>ByteDance is targeting revenue growth of about 20% this year, which could help it catch up to rival Meta Platforms, according to Bloomberg.</p> <p>The TikTok parent company expects revenue to rise to about $186 billion in 2025, up from $155 billion last year, Bloomberg reported. Analysts expect Meta to ...</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>tag:www.theinformation.com,2005:Briefing/15194</id>
            <title>Logistics Startup Stord Raises $200 Million, Eyes More M&amp;A</title>
            <link>https://www.theinformation.com/briefings/logistics-startup-stord-raises-200-million-eyes-m</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.theinformation.com,2005:Briefing/15194</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>2025-05-17T22:15:04Z</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>Logistics startup Stord said Friday it raised $80 million in equity funding at a $1.5 billion valuation, as well as $120 million in debt financing, likely setting up the company to acquire more U.S. warehousing operations.</p> <p>Stord provides fulfillment and warehousing services to help merchants ...</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>tag:www.theinformation.com,2005:Briefing/15193</id>
            <title>Charter to Acquire Cox for $34.5 Billion to Create New Cable-Broadband Leader</title>
            <link>https://www.theinformation.com/briefings/charter-acquire-cox-34-5-billion-create-new-cable-broadband-leader</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.theinformation.com,2005:Briefing/15193</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>2025-05-17T22:15:04Z</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>Two of the biggest cable TV and broadband operators, Charter Communications and Cox Communications,&nbsp;are combining, in a sign of how the decline of cable TV and competition in broadband is forcing another stage of consolidation.</p> <p>Charter is buying Cox in a deal that values Cox at $34.5 ...</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>tag:www.theinformation.com,2005:Article/15052</id>
            <title>Chime’s Approach to Payday Lending Is Costly—for Chime</title>
            <link>https://www.theinformation.com/articles/chimes-payday-lending-costly-chime</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.theinformation.com,2005:Article/15052</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>2025-05-16T18:21:08Z</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>Last summer, banking app Chime introduced a lending product that let customers borrow small amounts to get them through to their next paycheck. Typical payday lenders charge exorbitant fees, but Chime was making the loans largely for free.</p>

<p>The fintech’s big bet is that fronting cash to customers&mdash;and only charging people that want extra-fast advances&mdash;will boost customer loyalty while also providing some fresh revenue. But Chime is now learning the cost of the loans, just as it tries to convince Wall Street it can generate healthy growth and profits from its business of providing banking services for everyday Americans.</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>tag:www.theinformation.com,2005:Briefing/15192</id>
            <title>Nvidia Plans New China R&amp;D Hub Amid Tightening U.S. Export Curbs</title>
            <link>https://www.theinformation.com/briefings/nvidia-plans-new-china-r-d-hub-amid-tightening-u-s-export-curbs</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.theinformation.com,2005:Briefing/15192</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>2025-05-17T22:15:06Z</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>Nvidia is planning to build a new research and development center in Shanghai as part of efforts to maintain its competitive edge in China amid declining sales due to stricter U.S. export controls, the Financial Times reported, citing two people with knowledge of the matter.</p> <p>During a visit to ...</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>tag:www.theinformation.com,2005:Article/15029</id>
            <title>Why YouTube Should Say How Much Money It Makes</title>
            <link>https://www.theinformation.com/articles/youtube-say-money-makes</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.theinformation.com,2005:Article/15029</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>2025-05-16T00:09:35Z</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>Video-streaming and TV executives were out in force in New York this week, as outlets pitched their program schedules to marketers at lavish star-studded presentations. None other than Lady Gaga performed at YouTube’s party in Lincoln Center, for instance. There’s no doubt YouTube has come a long way since its founding 20 years ago. It now has a bigger share of the audience than any TV service of any kind, <a href="https://www.nielsen.com/data-center/the-gauge/#viewing-by-distributor">according to Nielsen</a>. And it passed $50 billion in annual revenue last fall, according to executives from its parent, Google, including both ads and <a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/youtube-tries-again-to-compete-with-amazon-to-become-all-video-hub?rc=9byxri">subscriptions</a>.</p><p>Yet we still don’t know how much profit YouTube makes, if any! While the company has begun giving us an occasional glimpse of its top line—including regular quarterly updates on its ad business—the bottom line remains a big secret. And it’s not just the public that is in the dark on this issue. When my colleagues Sahil Patel and Kaya Yurieff <a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/youtube-leaders-bring-a-new-focus-on-financial-discipline?rc=9byxri">wrote about YouTube’s new and more financially driven culture a year ago</a>, they heard from numerous current and former YouTube staffers that they didn’t know for sure whether it made money.</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>tag:www.theinformation.com,2005:Briefing/15191</id>
            <title>Cohere Revenue Falls 85% Short of Target</title>
            <link>https://www.theinformation.com/briefings/cohere-revenue-falls-85-short-target</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.theinformation.com,2005:Briefing/15191</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>2025-05-17T22:15:06Z</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>Artificial intelligence model developer Cohere fell well short of revenue projections the company prepared in early 2023, missing its target for last year by 85%.</p> <p>In a pitch to investors two years ago, the company forecast making around $450 million in annualized revenue by the end of last year. ...</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>