<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <channel>
        <title>The Verge</title>
        <link>https://www.theverge.com</link>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.theverge.com/?p=669238</id>
            <title>Apple is trying to get ‘LLM Siri’ back on track</title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/669238/apple-siri-llm-ai-revamp</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theverge.com/?p=669238</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>2025-05-18T19:06:37-04:00</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    Apple Intelligence has been a wreck since its first features rolled out last year, and a big new report from Bloomberg’s Mark Gurman details why — and how Apple is trying to piece things back together. And much of its effort hinges on rebuilding Siri from the ground up. Gurman has reported in the past [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.theverge.com/21280354/best-ipad-deals-apple</id>
            <title>Here are the best iPad deals you can get right now</title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/21280354/best-ipad-deals-apple</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theverge.com/21280354/best-ipad-deals-apple</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>2025-05-18T13:05:20-04:00</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    While the best iPad deals usually land during major sale events like Black Friday and Prime Day,&#160;many great iPad deals are attainable outside of those times. The day-to-day discounts may come and go like changing winds, but there’s often some amount to be saved, particularly on Apple’s more affordable iPads. The most recent&#160;iPad Pro and [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.theverge.com/?p=669157</id>
            <title>China begins assembling its supercomputer in space</title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/669157/china-begins-assembling-its-supercomputer-in-space</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theverge.com/?p=669157</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>2025-05-18T12:35:23-04:00</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    China has launched the first 12 satellites of a planned 2,800-strong orbital supercomputer satellite network, reports Space News. The satellites, created by the company ADA Space, Zhijiang Laboratory, and Neijang High-Tech Zone, will be able to process the data they collect themselves, rather than relying on terrestrial stations to do it for them, according to [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.theverge.com/?p=668845</id>
            <title>I used two GPS hiking apps for backpacking and I’ll do it again</title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/hands-on/668845/all-trails-gaia-gps-cal-topo-backpacking-review</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theverge.com/?p=668845</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>2025-05-17T13:34:31-04:00</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    For most of my life, I've relied on a paper map when I go outdoors. Then, in March, I joined my friend Rusty on the Appalachian Trail for two weeks. He told me to download FarOut. FarOut was my introduction to the world of app-based navigation. It's focused on thru-hikers, and has useful details, including [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.theverge.com/?p=667948</id>
            <title>In a year full of giant games, some little mice stand out</title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/games/667948/maze-mice-pc-early-access-small-game</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theverge.com/?p=667948</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>2025-05-18T14:47:43-04:00</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    There have been a lot of big games this year that have felt all-consuming, like Monster Hunter Wilds or Clair Obscur: Expedition 33. Maze Mice offers something different: a small, pick-up-and-play experience that takes a bunch of ideas from some classics and adds a clever twist. The game, from Luck Be a Landlord developer TrampolineTales, [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.theverge.com/?p=668638</id>
            <title>The best wireless headphones get even better</title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/installer-newsletter/668638/best-wireless-headphones-doom-murderbot-installer</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theverge.com/?p=668638</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>2025-05-16T14:20:38-04:00</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    Hi, friends! Welcome to Installer No. 83, your guide to the best and Verge-iest stuff in the world. (If you're new here, welcome, please don't spoil Andor for me, and also you can read all the old editions at the Installer homepage.) This week, I've been reading about Mission: Impossible and Sam Altman's kitchen and [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.theverge.com/?p=669158</id>
            <title>Amazon claims it’s ‘constantly inviting’ new customers to Alexa Plus</title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/669158/amazon-claims-its-constantly-inviting-new-customers-to-alexa-plus</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theverge.com/?p=669158</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>2025-05-17T20:44:28-04:00</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    Yesterday, Reuters ran a story with the headline “Weeks after Amazon&#8217;s Alexa+ AI launch, a mystery: where are the users?,” in which it detailed its difficulty locating first-hand accounts of the AI-upgraded assistants’ use online. The Verge asked Amazon about the story, and the company has responded to say that the idea that Alexa Plus [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.theverge.com/?p=669140</id>
            <title>How a DoorDash driver scammed the company out $2.5 million</title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/669140/doordash-driver-convicted-delivery-scam</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theverge.com/?p=669140</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>2025-05-18T08:14:18-04:00</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    A former DoorDash delivery driver pleaded guilty this week to a wire fraud conspiracy that scammed the company out of over $2.5 million, the US Attorney’s Office in California’s Northern District announced on Tuesday. He and others made it happen over a period of months using fake customer accounts, deliveries that never happened, driver accounts, [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.theverge.com/?p=668088</id>
            <title>REI’s anniversary sale is dropping prices on Garmins and other great outdoor gear</title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/tech/668088/rei-anniversary-sale-2025-garmin-watch-inreach-stoves-water-filters-deal-sale</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theverge.com/?p=668088</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>2025-05-17T11:45:36-04:00</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    Just in time to make the most of the warmer weather, REI is slashing prices on a bunch of our favorite outdoor gadgets and goods as a part of its annual anniversary sale. Now through May 26th, the outdoor retailer is taking up to 30 percent off a large number of items, from Garmin watches [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.theverge.com/?p=669047</id>
            <title>Epic asks judge to make Apple let Fortnite back on the US App Store</title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/669047/epic-fortnite-filing-apple-app-store-review-order</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theverge.com/?p=669047</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>2025-05-17T11:11:05-04:00</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    Epic is asking District Judge Yvonne Gonzalez Rogers to order Apple to review — and approve if compliant with Apple’s guidelines — Epic’s submission of Fortnite to the US App Store in a new court filing. The company argues in the document that Apple is once again in contempt of the judge’s April order restricting it from [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>