<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <channel>
        <title></title>
        <link>https://www.fool.com</link>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/19/warren-buffett-is-buying-secret-stock-again-clues/</id>
            <title>Warren Buffett Is Buying a Secret Stock Again -- and Based on Clues, This Is the Company I Believe He's Building a Position In</title>
            <link>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/19/warren-buffett-is-buying-secret-stock-again-clues/?source=iedfolrf0000001</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/19/warren-buffett-is-buying-secret-stock-again-clues/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Mon, 19 May 2025 03:06:00 -0400</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    For the first time since 2023, the Oracle of Omaha is using the confidential tag to build a stake in a company without investors knowing which stock it is.
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/3-artificial-intelligence-ai-stocks-that-may-soar/</id>
            <title>3 Artificial Intelligence (AI) Stocks That Could Soar in the Second Half of 2025</title>
            <link>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/3-artificial-intelligence-ai-stocks-that-may-soar/?source=iedfolrf0000001</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/3-artificial-intelligence-ai-stocks-that-may-soar/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 19:30:00 -0400</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    One small media and entertainment stock has been soaring thanks to AI licensing.
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/down-12-this-year-should-you-buy-alphabet-stock/</id>
            <title>Down 12% This Year, Should You Buy Alphabet Stock?</title>
            <link>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/down-12-this-year-should-you-buy-alphabet-stock/?source=iedfolrf0000001</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/down-12-this-year-should-you-buy-alphabet-stock/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 18:30:00 -0400</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>Shares of <strong>Alphabet</strong> <span class="ticker">(NASDAQ: GOOG)</span> <span class="ticker">(NASDAQ: GOOGL)</span> are down 12% so far in 2025. The Google owner is underperforming the <strong>Nasdaq Composite</strong>, which has rallied in recent weeks and is only down about 1% year to date at the time of writing.</p><p>At first glance, the stock appears to be a no-brainer buy. This is one of the largest and most profitable companies in the world, with a very strong brand in Google. But some investors are questioning Google's competitive position, especially in search. More people seem to be using OpenAI's ChatGPT and other leading <a href="https://www.fool.com/terms/a/artificial-intelligence/">artificial intelligence (AI)</a> models as a substitute for Google Search.</p><p>We'll explore what this means for Google. But I believe investors could be greatly underestimating the company's AI capabilities.</p><p><a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/down-12-this-year-should-you-buy-alphabet-stock/?source=iedfolrf0000001">Continue reading</a></p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/the-2-best-stocks-to-invest-1000-in-right-now/</id>
            <title>The 2 Best Stocks to Invest $1,000 in Right Now</title>
            <link>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/the-2-best-stocks-to-invest-1000-in-right-now/?source=iedfolrf0000001</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/the-2-best-stocks-to-invest-1000-in-right-now/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 18:17:00 -0400</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>The U.S. equity market has been challenging for investors in 2025, weighed down by inflation, geopolitical tensions, and rising interest rates. Investors have also been concerned about the escalation of trade wars in an already uncertain macroeconomic environment.</p><p>However, such periods of high turbulence also offer astute investors a rare opportunity to pick up shares in attractive stocks that are trading at reasonable valuation levels.</p><p class="caption">Image source: Getty Images.</p><p><a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/the-2-best-stocks-to-invest-1000-in-right-now/?source=iedfolrf0000001">Continue reading</a></p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/where-will-d-wave-quantum-stock-be-in-1-year/</id>
            <title>Where Will D-Wave Quantum Stock Be in 1 Year?</title>
            <link>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/where-will-d-wave-quantum-stock-be-in-1-year/?source=iedfolrf0000001</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/where-will-d-wave-quantum-stock-be-in-1-year/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 18:15:00 -0400</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>Amid the wild swings on Wall Street this year, quantum computing remains one of the hottest stock market investing themes. <strong>D-Wave Quantum</strong> <span class="ticker">(NYSE: QBTS)</span> has emerged as an industry leader, capturing strong demand for its cutting-edge technology with a growing number of commercial use cases. Accelerating sales have powered the stock to a staggering 705% return over the past year as of this writing, with optimism building among investors toward the company's outlook.</p><p>Can the rally keep going? Let's discuss where D-Wave Quantum stock might be in one year from now.</p><p class="caption">Image source: Getty Images.</p><p><a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/where-will-d-wave-quantum-stock-be-in-1-year/?source=iedfolrf0000001">Continue reading</a></p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/ives-says-bull-case-back-on-table-apple-palantir/</id>
            <title>Bull Case "Back on the Table" for Apple, Microsoft, and Palantir Following Trade Truce, Says Dan Ives</title>
            <link>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/ives-says-bull-case-back-on-table-apple-palantir/?source=iedfolrf0000001</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/ives-says-bull-case-back-on-table-apple-palantir/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 18:10:00 -0400</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>Things were looking extremely difficult for technology companies just a few weeks ago. President Donald Trump announced tariffs on imports from countries around the world -- and an especially high tariff of 145% on imports from China. The move could have been disastrous for tech stocks in two ways: Higher prices in general would reduce demand for their products and services, and the higher prices on their imported parts and finished goods would increase their costs.</p><p>Wedbush analyst Dan Ives even <a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/04/07/ives-calls-tariffs-armageddon-should-you-invest/">called the scenario "Armageddon"</a> for technology companies. But, luckily for these players and for investors, the situation has greatly improved. Since Trump's first announcement, he followed up by temporarily exempting electronics from tariffs. That was a first win for the industry. Then, just last week, the U.S. and China reached an initial trade agreement, dropping the level on imports from China to 30%.</p><p>Now, Ives says the bull case is "back on the table" for tech stocks such as <strong>Apple</strong> <span class="ticker">(NASDAQ: AAPL)</span>, <strong>Microsoft</strong>, and <strong>Palantir Technologies</strong>. Let's take a closer look at the situation and consider whether now is a good time to get in on these growth players.</p><p><a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/ives-says-bull-case-back-on-table-apple-palantir/?source=iedfolrf0000001">Continue reading</a></p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.fool.com/retirement/2025/05/18/its-true-these-13-states-dont-tax-retirement-incom/</id>
            <title>It's True: These 13 States Don't Tax Retirement Income</title>
            <link>https://www.fool.com/retirement/2025/05/18/its-true-these-13-states-dont-tax-retirement-incom/?source=iedfolrf0000001</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fool.com/retirement/2025/05/18/its-true-these-13-states-dont-tax-retirement-incom/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 15:30:00 -0400</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    Something as simple as changing states could lower your yearly tax liability by quite a bit.
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/artificial-intelligence-ai-infrastructure-spend-co/</id>
            <title>Artificial Intelligence (AI) Infrastructure Spend Could Hit $6.7 Trillion by 2030, According to McKinsey. 4 Data Center Stocks to Load Up on Right Now Like There's No Tomorrow.</title>
            <link>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/artificial-intelligence-ai-infrastructure-spend-co/?source=iedfolrf0000001</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/artificial-intelligence-ai-infrastructure-spend-co/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 15:22:00 -0400</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>Global management consulting firm McKinsey &amp; Company recently published a report detailing compelling trends in research and development (R&amp;D) and capital expenditure (<a href="https://www.fool.com/terms/c/capital-expenditure/">capex</a>) related to artificial intelligence (AI) investments over the next five years.</p><p>Per McKinsey's analysis, spending on AI infrastructure could reach $6.7 trillion by 2030. Among these different infrastructure opportunities, McKinsey estimates that nearly $3.1 trillion will be allocated toward chip designers for AI-equipped data centers.</p><p>Let's analyze which companies are making major investments in AI infrastructure right now and explore what they're investing in. From there, I'll reveal my top four data center stocks to load up on right now and explain why.</p><p><a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/artificial-intelligence-ai-infrastructure-spend-co/?source=iedfolrf0000001">Continue reading</a></p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/this-top-warren-buffett-stock-is-a-super-dividend/</id>
            <title>This Top Warren Buffett Stock Is a Super Dividend Stock to Buy for Passive Income</title>
            <link>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/this-top-warren-buffett-stock-is-a-super-dividend/?source=iedfolrf0000001</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/this-top-warren-buffett-stock-is-a-super-dividend/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 15:17:00 -0400</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p><strong><span>Chevron</span></strong><span> <span class="ticker">(NYSE: CVX)</span> is one of the top holdings of Warren Buffett's </span><strong><span>Berkshire Hathaway</span></strong><span> <span class="ticker">(NYSE: BRK.A)</span><span class="ticker">(NYSE: BRK.B)</span>. Buffett's company owns 6.8% of the oil giant's outstanding shares (118.6 million shares worth $16.7 billion). It's Berkshire's fifth-largest holding at 5.8% of its investment portfolio. </span></p><p><span>One of </span><a class="editor-rtfLink" href="https://www.fool.com/investing/how-to-invest/stocks/how-to-invest-in-chevron-stock/"><span>Chevron</span></a><span>'s top investment features is its high-yielding dividend. Buffett's company </span><span>stands to</span> <a class="editor-rtfLink" href="https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/04/21/warren-buffett-secret-nasdaq-bear-market-dividend/"><span>collect more than $800 million in dividend income from Chevron</span></a><span> this year. </span></p><p><span>Here's why investors </span><span>who want</span><span> to generate passive income should </span><span>take a closer</span><span> look at this top Buffett stock.</span></p><p><a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/this-top-warren-buffett-stock-is-a-super-dividend/?source=iedfolrf0000001">Continue reading</a></p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/through-all-of-the-tariff-drama-wall-streets-most/</id>
            <title>Through All of the Tariff Drama, Wall Street's Most Bullish Strategist Hasn't Flinched. He Still Thinks the S&amp;P 500 Index Can Hit 7,000 This Year.</title>
            <link>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/through-all-of-the-tariff-drama-wall-streets-most/?source=iedfolrf0000001</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/through-all-of-the-tariff-drama-wall-streets-most/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 15:10:00 -0400</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>After the tariff drama began to unfold in late March and early April, most Wall Street strategists did not hesitate to lower their price targets for the benchmark <strong>S&amp;P 500 </strong><span class="ticker">(SNPINDEX: ^GSPC)</span>. After all, elevated tariff rates could increase inflation and slow the economy, potentially leading to a recession or some kind of stagflation scenario that would make the monetary tools at the Federal Reserve's disposal less effective.</p><p>But through the last month and a half, one of Wall Street's most bullish strategists coming into the year, <strong>Wells Fargo</strong>'s Christopher Harvey, hasn't flinched. He hasn't once changed his roughly 7,000 price target for the S&amp;P 500, which is now the highest among his peers. And he still thinks that price target is achievable this year. Here's why.</p><p></p><p><a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/through-all-of-the-tariff-drama-wall-streets-most/?source=iedfolrf0000001">Continue reading</a></p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/warren-buffetts-347-billion-warning-to-wall-street/</id>
            <title>Warren Buffett's $347 Billion Warning to Wall Street Is Ringing Out Loud and Clear. History Says This Happens Next.</title>
            <link>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/warren-buffetts-347-billion-warning-to-wall-street/?source=iedfolrf0000001</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/warren-buffetts-347-billion-warning-to-wall-street/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 15:10:00 -0400</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>The bull market roared on last year, and investors favored high growth stocks in particular -- with the idea that these sorts of players would excel in a potentially lower interest rate environment. And many of these investor favorites are involved in artificial intelligence (AI), a booming field that could drive growth well into the future.</p><p>But, amid all of this optimism, Warren Buffett began to construct a significant warning to Wall Street. The billionaire investor didn't join the crowd and buy stocks hand over fist. He selectively made some purchases -- for example, adding <strong>Constellation Brands</strong> to the <strong>Berkshire Hathaway</strong> portfolio in the fourth quarter. But overall, he was a net seller of stocks, even reducing positions in top holdings <strong>Apple</strong> and <strong>Bank of America</strong> last year. And at the same time, Buffett built up a record level of cash -- and that level has marched higher into the new year, totaling more than $347 billion as of the end of the first quarter.</p><p>In that period, Buffett was a net seller of stocks for the 10th consecutive quarter, extending the billion-dollar warning into this year. Now let's take a look at history to see what stocks may do next.</p><p><a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/warren-buffetts-347-billion-warning-to-wall-street/?source=iedfolrf0000001">Continue reading</a></p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/the-smartest-high-yielding-dividend-stocks-in-the/</id>
            <title>The Smartest High-Yielding Dividend Stocks in the S&amp;P 500 Index to Buy With $3,000 Right Now</title>
            <link>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/the-smartest-high-yielding-dividend-stocks-in-the/?source=iedfolrf0000001</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/the-smartest-high-yielding-dividend-stocks-in-the/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 15:00:00 -0400</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>The stock market has been incredibly volatile this year, registering a nearly 20% fall from February highs before bouncing back with a roughly 20% gain since President Donald Trump's sweeping tariff announcement in April. Two of the three major indexes entered bear market territory at one point.</p><p>Not everyone has the stomach for this kind of volatility as it can be incredibly stressful to see so much movement in such a short time period. Many investors prefer to focus on passive income by purchasing stocks with healthy, growing dividends. For those intrigued by this approach, here are the smartest dividend stocks in the broader benchmark <strong>S&amp;P 500 </strong>index to buy with $3,000 right now.</p><p>Tobacco company <strong>Philip Morris International</strong> <span class="ticker">(NYSE: PM)</span> was <a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/04/28/best-stock-buy-altria-vs-philip-morris/">spun off from its parent company</a>, <strong>Altria Group</strong> (formerly Philip Morris Companies Inc.), and taken public in 2008. It was also around this time that the company made the decision to shift its focus from cigarettes to smoke-free products such as ZYN and iQOS.</p><p><a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/the-smartest-high-yielding-dividend-stocks-in-the/?source=iedfolrf0000001">Continue reading</a></p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.fool.com/retirement/2025/05/18/thinking-about-delaying-your-retirement-3-things/</id>
            <title>Thinking About Delaying Your Retirement? 3 Things to Do Now</title>
            <link>https://www.fool.com/retirement/2025/05/18/thinking-about-delaying-your-retirement-3-things/?source=iedfolrf0000001</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fool.com/retirement/2025/05/18/thinking-about-delaying-your-retirement-3-things/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 15:00:00 -0400</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>You decided long ago that 2025 was going to be the year you retired. Now it's here, and you're wondering whether that's still the best plan. Perhaps you weren't able to save as much as you'd hoped for retirement. There's a lot of uncertainty right now about tariffs and how they could increase inflation. And Social Security's future still has a lot of question marks, too.</p><p>So you might decide that postponing your retirement for a few months or years is the best move for you right now. That's OK. But if you're thinking of going this route, make sure you also take the following three steps.</p><p class="caption">Image source: Getty Images.</p><p><a href="https://www.fool.com/retirement/2025/05/18/thinking-about-delaying-your-retirement-3-things/?source=iedfolrf0000001">Continue reading</a></p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/dollar-general-is-rallying-but-are-investors-overl/</id>
            <title>Dollar General Is Rallying, but Are Investors Overlooking This Vital Growth Story?</title>
            <link>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/dollar-general-is-rallying-but-are-investors-overl/?source=iedfolrf0000001</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/dollar-general-is-rallying-but-are-investors-overl/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 14:15:00 -0400</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>The <strong>S&amp;P 500 </strong><span class="ticker">(SNPINDEX: ^GSPC)</span> has basically gone nowhere so far in 2025, but it has done it in an exciting way. The market's correction, however, didn't seem to have an impact on <strong>Dollar General</strong> <span class="ticker">(NYSE: DG)</span> shares, which rose while the S&amp;P 500 index was falling. At the time of this writing, Dollar General is up around 15% while the market is flat.</p><p>Before you rush out and buy outperforming Dollar General stock, you need to understand this one overlooked "growth" story.</p><p>Dollar General is, from a big-picture perspective, <a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/stock-market/market-sectors/consumer-discretionary/retail-stocks/">a retailer</a>. But it is focused on selling products at low price points. Further, it targets less affluent markets that are underserved by larger retailers, notably big-box stores like <strong>Walmart</strong> and <strong>Target</strong>. The goal is to provide a mix of convenience and low price points for consumers.</p><p><a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/dollar-general-is-rallying-but-are-investors-overl/?source=iedfolrf0000001">Continue reading</a></p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/should-you-buy-ionq-stock-to-ride-the-quantum-comp/</id>
            <title>Should You Buy IonQ Stock to Ride the Quantum Computing Revolution? The Answer May Surprise You</title>
            <link>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/should-you-buy-ionq-stock-to-ride-the-quantum-comp/?source=iedfolrf0000001</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/should-you-buy-ionq-stock-to-ride-the-quantum-comp/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 14:00:00 -0400</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>Science fiction is slowly turning into science fact. At least, that's what it looks like when we have self-driving cars, humanoid robots, and now quantum computers emerging into the limelight. Researchers predict that quantum computing will create $850 billion in economic value by 2040, and investors are scooping up shares of quantum computing stocks like they're going out of style. <strong>IonQ</strong> <span class="ticker">(NYSE: IONQ)</span> is up over 300% in the last 12 months as of this writing, making huge gains for shareholders.</p><p>Is now the time to hop on the IonQ train and ride the quantum computing revolution? The answer is more complicated than you think.</p><p>We can easily understand why society would value self-driving cars or humanoid robots. They take work previously done by humans and offload it to machines, allowing people to have more leisure time. But why would we want quantum computers?</p><p><a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/should-you-buy-ionq-stock-to-ride-the-quantum-comp/?source=iedfolrf0000001">Continue reading</a></p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/prediction-this-artificial-intelligence-ai-stock-w/</id>
            <title>Prediction: This Artificial Intelligence (AI) Stock Will Go Parabolic in June (Hint: It's Not Nvidia)</title>
            <link>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/prediction-this-artificial-intelligence-ai-stock-w/?source=iedfolrf0000001</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/prediction-this-artificial-intelligence-ai-stock-w/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 12:15:00 -0400</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    Next month could be a make-or-break moment for Tesla.
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/dont-fall-for-these-3-dividend-stocks-they-may-hav/</id>
            <title>Don't Fall for These 3 Dividend Stocks: They May Have to Make a Cut.</title>
            <link>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/dont-fall-for-these-3-dividend-stocks-they-may-hav/?source=iedfolrf0000001</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/dont-fall-for-these-3-dividend-stocks-they-may-hav/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 12:05:00 -0400</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    Here are three dividend-paying stocks that warrant closer examination.
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/warren-buffett-nearly-made-his-biggest-investment/</id>
            <title>Warren Buffett Nearly Made His Biggest Investment Since 2022. Here's What's Holding Him Back.</title>
            <link>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/warren-buffett-nearly-made-his-biggest-investment/?source=iedfolrf0000001</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/warren-buffett-nearly-made-his-biggest-investment/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 12:00:00 -0400</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    Buffett said Berkshire came close to spending $10 billion, and he'd happily spend $100 billion.
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/2-no-brainer-warren-buffett-stocks-to-buy-now/</id>
            <title>2 No-Brainer Warren Buffett Stocks to Buy Right Now</title>
            <link>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/2-no-brainer-warren-buffett-stocks-to-buy-now/?source=iedfolrf0000001</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/2-no-brainer-warren-buffett-stocks-to-buy-now/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 11:37:00 -0400</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>With Warren Buffett's recent announcement that he's stepping down as the CEO of<strong> Berkshire Hathaway,</strong> it's worth taking a look at a couple of stocks in his company's $286 billion portfolio that look like good buys right now.</p><p>Two standouts among the many great options are <strong>Amazon</strong> <span class="ticker">(NASDAQ: AMZN)</span> and <strong>American Express </strong><span class="ticker">(NYSE: AXP)</span>. Here's why you should consider picking up their shares now.</p><p class="caption">Image source: Getty Images.</p><p><a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/2-no-brainer-warren-buffett-stocks-to-buy-now/?source=iedfolrf0000001">Continue reading</a></p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/the-nasdaq-just-soared-30-from-its-2025-low-3-vang/</id>
            <title>The Nasdaq Just Soared 30% From Its 2025 Low: 3 Vanguard ETFs to Buy Now</title>
            <link>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/the-nasdaq-just-soared-30-from-its-2025-low-3-vang/?source=iedfolrf0000001</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/the-nasdaq-just-soared-30-from-its-2025-low-3-vang/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 10:33:00 -0400</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>The <strong>Nasdaq Composite</strong> <span class="ticker">(NASDAQINDEX: ^IXIC)</span> closed Wednesday at 19,146.81 -- a staggering 29.5% rally from its 52-week intraday low of 14,784.03 on April 7.</p><p>Trade tensions are easing. Reciprocal tariffs are being paused or cut. The economy is showing resiliency. Big banks such as <strong>Goldman Sachs</strong> and <strong>JPMorgan Chase</strong> just reduced their recession odds forecasts. In sum, a renewed wave of investor optimism is rippling through the market.</p><p>Of course, there's always the "stroke of the pen risk" that policies change and tensions flare once more. However, with a prolonged trade war now likely avoided, investors can shift their focus back to building their portfolios around quality companies.</p><p><a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/the-nasdaq-just-soared-30-from-its-2025-low-3-vang/?source=iedfolrf0000001">Continue reading</a></p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/sweetgreen-is-betting-it-all-on-store-growth/</id>
            <title>Sweetgreen Is Betting It All on Store Growth</title>
            <link>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/sweetgreen-is-betting-it-all-on-store-growth/?source=iedfolrf0000001</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/sweetgreen-is-betting-it-all-on-store-growth/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 10:17:00 -0400</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p><strong>Sweetgreen</strong> <span class="ticker">(NYSE: SG)</span> is a young restaurant chain that aims to grow in the years ahead, but it's important to know that financial results for this type of business need to be assessed in a particular way. For example, the company's first quarter appears to have been reasonably strong, with the top line expanding by 5.4%.</p><p>But there's an underlying weakness here that you have to understand before you buy into this salad-focused fast-food concept. Let's take a closer look.</p><p>Sweetgreen is basically <a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/stock-market/market-sectors/consumer-discretionary/restaurant-stocks/fast-food-stocks/">a fast-food restaurant</a> chain. The food it sells which, as noted, is salads isn't actually all that important when you step back and look at how the business operates from a big-picture perspective. Like all fast-food restaurants, there are two key numbers that are important to monitor.</p><p><a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/sweetgreen-is-betting-it-all-on-store-growth/?source=iedfolrf0000001">Continue reading</a></p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/is-united-parcel-service-stock-a-buy-despite-tarif/</id>
            <title>Is United Parcel Service Stock a Buy Despite Tariff Worries?</title>
            <link>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/is-united-parcel-service-stock-a-buy-despite-tarif/?source=iedfolrf0000001</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/is-united-parcel-service-stock-a-buy-despite-tarif/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 10:05:00 -0400</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>At its current share price, <strong>United Parcel Service</strong>'s <span class="ticker">(NYSE: UPS)</span> dividend offers investors a huge 6.4% yield. That payout is backed by 16 straight annual dividend increases, so given that the <strong>S&amp;P 500</strong> <span class="ticker">(SNPINDEX: ^GSPC)</span> index is only offering a measly 1.3% yield, income-seeking investors should be doing a deep dive on UPS today. But is the logistics giant's stock worth buying as international trade faces the threat of tariff-driven upheavals?</p><p>Business situations, and emotions, change quickly on Wall Street. Beginning in 2020, the coronavirus pandemic led investors to drive UPS stock sharply higher. The thesis seemed to be that COVID would keep people stuck in their homes forever and, thus, they would have to buy more things over <a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/stock-market/market-sectors/consumer-discretionary/internet-direct-marketing-retail-stocks/">the internet</a>. That, in turn, would result in massive growth for package delivery companies like UPS.</p><p class="caption"><a href="https://ycharts.com/companies/UPS/chart/"><img alt="UPS Chart" src="https://media.ycharts.com/charts/01c0d18fdcc0753e1da342b9e0385a21.png" /></a><br /><a href="https://ycharts.com/companies/UPS">UPS</a> data by <a href="https://ycharts.com">YCharts</a>.</p><p><a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/is-united-parcel-service-stock-a-buy-despite-tarif/?source=iedfolrf0000001">Continue reading</a></p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/archer-aviation-stock-soars-is-it-still-a-buy/</id>
            <title>Archer Aviation Stock Soars: Is It Still a Buy Below $13?</title>
            <link>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/archer-aviation-stock-soars-is-it-still-a-buy/?source=iedfolrf0000001</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/archer-aviation-stock-soars-is-it-still-a-buy/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 09:45:00 -0400</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>The bull market may be returning. Investors in <strong>Archer Aviation</strong> <span class="ticker">(NYSE: ACHR)</span> certainly think so, with the stock shooting up close to 70% in the past month on the back of an optimistic earnings report. The upstart builder of electric air taxis is trying to disrupt the transportation market with its new Midnight aircraft and has orders from governments and corporations around the world.</p><p>However, the company is still in the certification stage and is not generating any revenue at the moment. With the stock soaring, should investors buy Archer Aviation stock below $13? Let's run the numbers and investigate further.</p><p>Electric air taxis -- sometimes called eVTOLs -- are aiming to disrupt the transportation market and alleviate traffic in large cities. There are plenty of start-ups trying to build these aircraft, with Archer Aviation being one of the leaders. With advancements in materials and electric propulsion, Archer Aviation's Midnight aircraft can theoretically safely and quietly fly a group of four people above a city, skipping the vehicle traffic below. </p><p><a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/archer-aviation-stock-soars-is-it-still-a-buy/?source=iedfolrf0000001">Continue reading</a></p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/prediction-this-beaten-down-stock-could-double-in/</id>
            <title>Prediction: This Beaten-Down Stock Could Double in The Next 5 Years</title>
            <link>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/prediction-this-beaten-down-stock-could-double-in/?source=iedfolrf0000001</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/prediction-this-beaten-down-stock-could-double-in/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 09:30:00 -0400</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>Despite making significant clinical progress,<strong> CRISPR Therapeutics</strong> <span class="ticker">(NASDAQ: CRSP)</span> has been struggling financially in the past three years. The company's shares are down by 24% over this period, while the <strong>S&amp;P 500</strong> has gained 41%. The gene-editing specialist has, no doubt, faced some headwinds.</p><p>However, important catalysts could double its stock price by 2030. For those keeping score at home, that would amount to a compound annual growth rate of about 14.9%, well above the market's historical average returns. </p><p>CRISPR Therapeutics' focus on gene editing has some advantages and disadvantages. On the one hand, its revolutionary techniques can allow researchers to create therapies for otherwise untreatable (or difficult-to-treat) conditions. CRISPR proved as much when it created and developed Casgevy, a one-time treatment that provides a functional cure for two genetic blood disorders: sickle cell disease and transfusion-dependent beta-thalassemia. CRISPR shares the rights to Casgevy together with <strong>Vertex Pharmaceuticals</strong>.</p><p><a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/prediction-this-beaten-down-stock-could-double-in/?source=iedfolrf0000001">Continue reading</a></p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/1-beaten-down-trillion-dollar-ai-stock-to-buy-on/</id>
            <title>1 Beaten-Down, Trillion-Dollar Artificial Intelligence (AI) Stock to Buy on the Dip</title>
            <link>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/1-beaten-down-trillion-dollar-ai-stock-to-buy-on/?source=iedfolrf0000001</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/1-beaten-down-trillion-dollar-ai-stock-to-buy-on/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 09:00:00 -0400</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p><strong>Alphabet</strong>'s <span class="ticker">(NASDAQ: GOOG)</span> <span class="ticker">(NASDAQ: GOOGL)</span> shares are down by 12% this year, partly due to being swept up in broader market volatility. However, the company has faced issues of its own. The stock could remain volatile in the short run, and developments could disrupt the company's dominance in the search engine niche.</p><p>Despite these challenges, Alphabet remains an excellent stock to buy while its shares are down -- and to hold on to for a while, even with a market capitalization of about $2 trillion. Let me explain.</p><p class="caption">Image source: Getty Images.</p><p><a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/1-beaten-down-trillion-dollar-ai-stock-to-buy-on/?source=iedfolrf0000001">Continue reading</a></p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/walmarts-q1-report-was-better-than-it-seems/</id>
            <title>Actually, Walmart's Q1 Report Was Better Than It Seems</title>
            <link>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/walmarts-q1-report-was-better-than-it-seems/?source=iedfolrf0000001</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/walmarts-q1-report-was-better-than-it-seems/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 08:47:00 -0400</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    The market seems to be focusing on the wrong things, causing it to look right past some important details.
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/its-time-to-invest-in-americas-copper-champion/</id>
            <title>It's Time to Invest in "America's Copper Champion"</title>
            <link>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/its-time-to-invest-in-americas-copper-champion/?source=iedfolrf0000001</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/its-time-to-invest-in-americas-copper-champion/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 08:30:00 -0400</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>While the tariff situation remains dynamic, one thing is crystal clear: The current administration wants to support domestic provision of key metals and minerals, including copper. That's excellent news for <strong>Freeport-McMoRan</strong> <span class="ticker">(NYSE: FCX)</span>, which calls itself "America's Copper Champion." Here's why the stock is a great buy right now.</p><p>Copper is critical to the modern economy. It's a crucial element in the electrification-of-everything trend, which encompasses electric vehicles, the Internet of Everything, renewable energy, data centers, and the electrical transmission and distribution networks needed to support the growing electrification of the economy.</p><p>Whatever the tariff landscape ends up looking like, the Trump administration is likely to support the domestic production of copper, and Freeport-McMoran will play a key role.</p><p><a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/its-time-to-invest-in-americas-copper-champion/?source=iedfolrf0000001">Continue reading</a></p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/is-chargepoint-stock-a-buy-now/</id>
            <title>Is ChargePoint Stock a Buy Now?</title>
            <link>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/is-chargepoint-stock-a-buy-now/?source=iedfolrf0000001</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/is-chargepoint-stock-a-buy-now/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 08:15:00 -0400</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>The <a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/stock-market/market-sectors/consumer-discretionary/automotive-stocks/electric-car-stocks/">electric vehicle</a> (EV) market is still in its infancy in the U.S., with plenty of room for small companies to stake a claim and establish themselves as key players. <strong>ChargePoint Holdings</strong> <span class="ticker">(NYSE: CHPT)</span> is trying to do just that with its EV chargers, but it's been an uphill battle for the company amid lackluster sales and a precarious EV market.</p><p>Here are three reasons why ChargePoint stock isn't a buy right now.</p><p class="caption">Image source: Getty Images.</p><p><a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/is-chargepoint-stock-a-buy-now/?source=iedfolrf0000001">Continue reading</a></p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/7-no-brainer-dividend-growth-stocks-to-buy-right-n/</id>
            <title>7 No-Brainer Dividend Growth Stocks to Buy Right Now</title>
            <link>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/7-no-brainer-dividend-growth-stocks-to-buy-right-n/?source=iedfolrf0000001</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/7-no-brainer-dividend-growth-stocks-to-buy-right-n/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 08:15:00 -0400</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>While many investors chase fleeting market trends, dividend growth investing offers something far more valuable. Namely, compounding wealth through businesses that pay you to own them. Moreover, elite dividend growth stocks, defined as those with five-year dividend growth rates above 6% and <a href="https://www.fool.com/terms/d/dividend-payout-ratio/">payout ratios</a> under 75%, have a stellar record of delivering superior returns to the benchmark <strong>S&amp;P 500</strong>.</p><p>This outperformance reveals a deeper truth about exceptional businesses. Companies that consistently grow dividends faster than 6% annually while maintaining conservative payout ratios possess <a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/2024/09/12/get-rich-slowly-the-magic-of-dividend-growth-stock/">two critical advantages</a>: accelerating earnings power and disciplined capital allocation. Equally as important, these traits typically signal businesses protected by wide economic moats, pricing power, network effects, and/or regulatory barriers that competitors can't easily overcome.</p><p class="caption">Image source: Getty Images.</p><p><a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/7-no-brainer-dividend-growth-stocks-to-buy-right-n/?source=iedfolrf0000001">Continue reading</a></p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/best-space-stock-enjoys-big-change-35-1-day-pop/</id>
            <title>One of the Best Space Stocks Just Reported a Big Change, and Its Stock Popped 35% in 1 Day</title>
            <link>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/best-space-stock-enjoys-big-change-35-1-day-pop/?source=iedfolrf0000001</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/best-space-stock-enjoys-big-change-35-1-day-pop/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 08:08:00 -0400</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    Investors are buying Intuitive Machines stock after earnings. They should have bought it before.
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/3-tech-stocks-drive-wealth-now-years-to-come/</id>
            <title>3 Tech Stocks Destined to Drive Wealth Now and for Years to Come</title>
            <link>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/3-tech-stocks-drive-wealth-now-years-to-come/?source=iedfolrf0000001</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/3-tech-stocks-drive-wealth-now-years-to-come/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 08:00:00 -0400</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>Investors can often simplify their investment choices by buying stock in established, wealth-building companies. Such stocks tend to offer investors more safety, and this approach is especially beneficial when a stock has not approached the end of its high-growth years.</p><p>Fortunately, the market offers numerous stocks that fit this description, and many of them have achieved their growth through success in <a href="https://www.fool.com/terms/a/artificial-intelligence/">artificial intelligence (AI)</a>.</p><p>With that, three analysts from The Motley Fool have recommended stocks that fit such a description. These large-cap stocks have not only stayed at the top of industries they helped transform but have also focused on plans that can keep them on a growth trajectory for years to come.</p><p><a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/3-tech-stocks-drive-wealth-now-years-to-come/?source=iedfolrf0000001">Continue reading</a></p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/my-prediction-for-ionq-stock-up-294-in-52-weeks/</id>
            <title>IonQ Stock Is Up 294% in the Past Year. Here's My Prediction For What Comes Next</title>
            <link>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/my-prediction-for-ionq-stock-up-294-in-52-weeks/?source=iedfolrf0000001</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/my-prediction-for-ionq-stock-up-294-in-52-weeks/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 07:41:00 -0400</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>Investors are keen on quantum computing stocks like <strong>IonQ</strong> <span class="ticker">(NYSE: IONQ)</span> right now. The stock is up a whopping 294% in the past year, likely due to industry breakthroughs in quantum computer chips that are helping improve error correction and computational speeds. With a market cap of $8.6 billion as of this writing, IonQ is the largest pure play quantum computing stock on the market and has been a favorite of investors in the last few quarters.</p><p>It can't be because of the company's underlying financial performance, which remains ugly. IonQ is generating minimal sales and racking up huge losses quarter after quarter. Here's my prediction for what comes next for IonQ shareholders.</p><p>IonQ aims to build quantum computers to sell to third parties. The promise of quantum computers is large. Using quantum mechanics, researchers have been able to build quantum bits -- Qubits -- that can compute difficult problems exponentially faster than traditional computers. If quantum computers can be widely commercialized, it promises a revolution in computing similar to that of traditional computers. IonQ has an early stage quantum computer that it sells to research institutions and through the cloud computing platforms.</p><p><a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/my-prediction-for-ionq-stock-up-294-in-52-weeks/?source=iedfolrf0000001">Continue reading</a></p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/heres-why-amazon-is-a-brilliant-buy-now-hint-its-n/</id>
            <title>Here's Why Amazon Is a Brilliant Buy Now (Hint: It's Not E-Commerce)</title>
            <link>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/heres-why-amazon-is-a-brilliant-buy-now-hint-its-n/?source=iedfolrf0000001</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/heres-why-amazon-is-a-brilliant-buy-now-hint-its-n/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 07:15:00 -0400</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p><strong>Amazon </strong><span class="ticker">(NASDAQ: AMZN)</span> was one of the biggest winners of the e-commerce revolution, and its platform is by far the most used option in this realm. On the investment side, it's what most users might think about Amazon. However, there are far better reasons to own the stock than that, as there isn't much growth in its e-commerce business anymore.</p><p>Furthermore, my primary reason to invest in Amazon isn't affected by tariffs, which just adds to an ever-growing list of reasons why Amazon should be viewed as a cloud computing company, not an e-commerce company. Amazon Web Services (AWS) is my primary reason for investing in Amazon. When you dig down a bit deeper, it's clear why this division is so exciting.</p><p class="caption">Image source: Getty Images.</p><p><a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/heres-why-amazon-is-a-brilliant-buy-now-hint-its-n/?source=iedfolrf0000001">Continue reading</a></p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/massive-news-for-unitedhealth-stock-investors/</id>
            <title>Massive News for UnitedHealth Stock Investors!</title>
            <link>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/massive-news-for-unitedhealth-stock-investors/?source=iedfolrf0000001</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/massive-news-for-unitedhealth-stock-investors/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 07:04:00 -0400</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p><strong>UnitedHealth</strong> <span class="ticker">(NYSE: UNH)</span> is reportedly under criminal investigation, and in this video, I will discuss what that could mean for investors.</p><p><em>*Stock prices used were the afternoon prices of May 14, 2025. The video was published on May 16, 2025.</em></p><p></p><p><a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/massive-news-for-unitedhealth-stock-investors/?source=iedfolrf0000001">Continue reading</a></p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/these-2-dividend-stocks-also-happen-to-be-american/</id>
            <title>These 2 Dividend Stocks Also Happen to Be American Companies (Somewhat) Insulated From Trade War Troubles</title>
            <link>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/these-2-dividend-stocks-also-happen-to-be-american/?source=iedfolrf0000001</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/these-2-dividend-stocks-also-happen-to-be-american/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 07:00:00 -0400</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>Despite the U.S. and China announcing a 90-day pause on elevated tariff rates against one another, there is still a 10% blanket tariff rate on imports from most of the country's major trading partners, as well as 25% tariffs on steel, aluminum, and some auto parts. Additionally, negotiations are ongoing and while the worst of the trade war looks to be in the past, investors are still unclear about exactly how things will shake out.</p><p>After so much market volatility, some investors may prefer to hunt for stocks that generate solid passive income. If they happen to be at least somewhat insulated from the ongoing trade war, that's even better. Here are two stocks that fit into this theme.</p><p>The massive telecommunications company <strong>Verizon</strong> <span class="ticker">(NYSE: VZ)</span> is headquartered in New York City, and made it abundantly clear in April that consumers would be on the hook for higher prices resulting from tariffs, if they were to stay at elevated rates. Long term, this may not be such a popular decision with customers, but financially it does offer some insulation from tariffs. Verizon also should have pricing power, given its well-known brand and the necessity of its offerings including internet and phone service.</p><p><a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/these-2-dividend-stocks-also-happen-to-be-american/?source=iedfolrf0000001">Continue reading</a></p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/should-you-buy-disney-stock-hold-5-years/</id>
            <title>Should You Buy Disney Stock in May and Hold for 5 Years?</title>
            <link>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/should-you-buy-disney-stock-hold-5-years/?source=iedfolrf0000001</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/should-you-buy-disney-stock-hold-5-years/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 06:50:00 -0400</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p><span>Since </span><strong><span>Walt Disney</span></strong><span> <span class="ticker">(NYSE: DIS)</span> reported financial results for its fiscal 2025 second quarter (ended March 29), shares are up a noteworthy 9% (as of May 14). Revenue increased 7% year over year to $23.6 billion, while adjusted earnings per share (EPS) jumped 20%. Both of these headline figures came in ahead of Wall Street's expectations. </span></p><p><span>Despite the momentum, shares trade at a gut-wrenching 45% below their all-time high. Owning the business hasn't worked out well for investors in recent years. But there are reasons to be bullish on Disney.</span></p><p><span>Should you buy this </span><a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/stock-market/market-sectors/consumer-discretionary/"><span>consumer discretionary stock</span></a><span> in May and hold it for five years?</span></p><p><a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/should-you-buy-disney-stock-hold-5-years/?source=iedfolrf0000001">Continue reading</a></p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/massive-news-for-apple-stock-investors/</id>
            <title>Massive News for Apple Stock Investors!</title>
            <link>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/massive-news-for-apple-stock-investors/?source=iedfolrf0000001</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/massive-news-for-apple-stock-investors/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 06:37:00 -0400</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>The company has done a great job of communicating its prospects amid rising geopolitical tensions.</p><p><em>*Stock prices used were the afternoon prices of May 15, 2025. The video was published on May 17, 2025.</em></p><p></p><p><a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/massive-news-for-apple-stock-investors/?source=iedfolrf0000001">Continue reading</a></p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/dan-ives-says-us-china-tariff-pause-is-a-dream-sce/</id>
            <title>Dan Ives Says U.S.-China Tariff Pause Is a "Dream Scenario" for Apple. Is This the Buy Signal Investors Were Waiting For?</title>
            <link>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/dan-ives-says-us-china-tariff-pause-is-a-dream-sce/?source=iedfolrf0000001</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/dan-ives-says-us-china-tariff-pause-is-a-dream-sce/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 06:30:00 -0400</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>The announcement of the 90-day tariff pause with China turned into a boon for tech stocks, as the indexes spiked higher. One of the more notable cheerleaders is Dan Ives, senior equity research analyst at Wedbush Securities. Ives went so far as to call this a "dream scenario" for <strong>Apple </strong><span class="ticker">(NASDAQ: AAPL)</span>.</p><p>But is that truly the case? Nobody questions the market leadership of the iPhone and the iOS ecosystem, and a trade deal with China should bring more certainty to its supply chain.</p><p>Still, Apple recently lost its <a href="https://www.fool.com/terms/m/market-cap/">market cap</a> lead to <strong>Nvidia</strong>, which is now just behind <strong>Microsoft</strong>'s $3.35 trillion capitalization. A deeper dive into Apple may call into question its value proposition. Thus, investors need to take a closer look at the stock to know whether it could still be a buy.</p><p><a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/dan-ives-says-us-china-tariff-pause-is-a-dream-sce/?source=iedfolrf0000001">Continue reading</a></p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/prediction-rocket-lab-usa-is-going-global/</id>
            <title>Prediction: Rocket Lab USA Is Going Global</title>
            <link>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/prediction-rocket-lab-usa-is-going-global/?source=iedfolrf0000001</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/prediction-rocket-lab-usa-is-going-global/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 06:17:00 -0400</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    Rocket Lab is still not profitable, but at least it is growing -- hopefully in Europe.
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/meet-the-warren-buffett-stock-thats-gained-5502284/</id>
            <title>Meet the Warren Buffett Investment That's Gained 5,502,284% and Looks Set to Soar Even Higher</title>
            <link>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/meet-the-warren-buffett-stock-thats-gained-5502284/?source=iedfolrf0000001</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/meet-the-warren-buffett-stock-thats-gained-5502284/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 06:15:00 -0400</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    Warren Buffett has had a lot of successful investments, but one in particular has crushed the stock market time and again.
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.fool.com/retirement/2025/05/18/dont-need-your-required-minimum-distribution-rmd/</id>
            <title>Don't Need Your Required Minimum Distribution (RMD) Just Yet? Here's What You Can Do With the Cash Influx.</title>
            <link>https://www.fool.com/retirement/2025/05/18/dont-need-your-required-minimum-distribution-rmd/?source=iedfolrf0000001</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fool.com/retirement/2025/05/18/dont-need-your-required-minimum-distribution-rmd/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 06:05:00 -0400</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>For many retirees, 73 is the magic age -- the time they must begin withdrawing <a href="https://www.fool.com/retirement/required-minimum-distributions/">required minimum distributions</a> (RMDs) from their retirement accounts. Retirees born in 1960 or later have until 75 to start taking RMDs. However, what do you do if you don't <em>need</em> the money just yet? Here are five ideas.</p><p>There's no rule saying you can't withdraw funds from your retirement accounts and immediately reinvest them elsewhere. Here are some popular options:</p><p class="caption">Image source: Getty Images.</p><p><a href="https://www.fool.com/retirement/2025/05/18/dont-need-your-required-minimum-distribution-rmd/?source=iedfolrf0000001">Continue reading</a></p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/heres-what-you-need-to-know-before-buying-or-selli/</id>
            <title>Here's What You Need to Know Before Buying or Selling Uber Stock</title>
            <link>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/heres-what-you-need-to-know-before-buying-or-selli/?source=iedfolrf0000001</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/heres-what-you-need-to-know-before-buying-or-selli/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 06:04:00 -0400</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p><strong>Uber</strong>'s <span class="ticker">(NYSE: UBER)</span> stock price is already up over 50% in 2025.</p><p><em>*Stock prices used were the afternoon prices of May 15, 2025. The video was published on May 17, 2025.</em></p><p></p><p><a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/heres-what-you-need-to-know-before-buying-or-selli/?source=iedfolrf0000001">Continue reading</a></p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/this-1-catalyst-could-send-bitcoin-skyrocketing-hi/</id>
            <title>This 1 Catalyst Could Send Bitcoin Skyrocketing Higher, According to Silicon Valley Billionaire Tim Draper</title>
            <link>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/this-1-catalyst-could-send-bitcoin-skyrocketing-hi/?source=iedfolrf0000001</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/this-1-catalyst-could-send-bitcoin-skyrocketing-hi/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 06:00:00 -0400</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>These days, it seems like everybody is trying to buy Bitcoin <span class="ticker">(CRYPTO: BTC)</span> -- individuals, Wall Street banks, institutional investors, and even the U.S. government. But until recently, corporations were not getting into the act. Only a relatively small number of publicly traded companies currently hold <a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/how-to-invest/stocks/how-to-invest-in-bitcoin/">Bitcoin</a> on their balance sheets.</p><p>But that could be changing. According to billionaire Silicon Valley venture capitalist Tim Draper, corporations need to start buying Bitcoin.If America's publicly traded corporations decide to go on a Bitcoin buying spree, that could send the world's most popular cryptocurrency soaring to new all-time highs.</p><p>Corporations are starting to follow the playbook created by <strong>MicroStrategy</strong> <span class="ticker">(NASDAQ: MSTR)</span>, the company now doing business as Strategy. That playbook primarily consists of one play: buying Bitcoin. Strategy now owns a staggering amount of Bitcoin -- 568,840 coins and counting. It seems that nearly every week, Strategy reports a major buy of more Bitcoin. Its current Bitcoin stockpile is valued at nearly $60 billion.</p><p><a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/this-1-catalyst-could-send-bitcoin-skyrocketing-hi/?source=iedfolrf0000001">Continue reading</a></p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/got-100-3-top-growth-stocks-to-buy-that-could-doub/</id>
            <title>Got $100? 3 Top Growth Stocks to Buy That Could Double Your Money</title>
            <link>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/got-100-3-top-growth-stocks-to-buy-that-could-doub/?source=iedfolrf0000001</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/got-100-3-top-growth-stocks-to-buy-that-could-doub/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 05:47:00 -0400</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>Everyone knows that it takes money to make money. However, you don't need much money to begin making money.</p><p>Many stocks with exceptional growth prospects have relatively low share prices. Got $100? Here are three top growth stocks to buy that could double your money.</p><p class="caption">Image source: Getty Images.</p><p><a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/got-100-3-top-growth-stocks-to-buy-that-could-doub/?source=iedfolrf0000001">Continue reading</a></p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/1-monster-stock-up-25-this-year-to-buy-with-1000-r/</id>
            <title>1 Monster Stock Up 30% This Year to Buy With $1,000 Right Now</title>
            <link>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/1-monster-stock-up-25-this-year-to-buy-with-1000-r/?source=iedfolrf0000001</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/1-monster-stock-up-25-this-year-to-buy-with-1000-r/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 05:45:00 -0400</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p><strong>Nu Holdings</strong> <span class="ticker">(NYSE: NU)</span> continues to crush the market, up almost 30% this year while the <strong>S&amp;P 500</strong> is little changed. It reported inspiring results for the 2025 first quarter, and because it's not a U.S. company, investors may see it as a safer stock while <a href="https://www.fool.com/terms/t/tariffs/">tariff discussions</a> are still in the works. That's a turnaround from previous market sentiment, which viewed its international status as a risk factor.</p><p>There are a lot of exciting things going on at this Brazil-based online bank, and if you have $1,000 available to invest after paying off debt and saving for an emergency fund, Nu stock is an excellent candidate.</p><p>Nu was created as a reaction to the stringent barriers to entry in the Brazilian banking market, which is dominated by a handful of large, legacy banks. It offers all-digital financial services, and now that it has created a strong brand presence, it has launched new products to target other strata of society, and it's rolling out in new markets.</p><p><a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/1-monster-stock-up-25-this-year-to-buy-with-1000-r/?source=iedfolrf0000001">Continue reading</a></p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/3-top-oil-stocks-that-can-still-thrive-even-though/</id>
            <title>3 Top Oil Stocks That Can Still Thrive Even Though Oil Prices Have Dropped Into the $60s</title>
            <link>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/3-top-oil-stocks-that-can-still-thrive-even-though/?source=iedfolrf0000001</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/3-top-oil-stocks-that-can-still-thrive-even-though/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 05:40:00 -0400</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>Crude oil prices have slumped this year. Brent, the global oil price benchmark, has fallen more than 10% on the year, pushing it into the low $60s. That slump will impact the cash flows that oil companies produce. </p><p>However, some <a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/stock-market/market-sectors/energy/are-oil-gas-good-investment/">oil stocks</a> are in a better position to handle lower oil prices than others. <strong>TotalEnergies</strong> <span class="ticker">(NYSE: TTE)</span>, <strong>ExxonMobil</strong> <span class="ticker">(NYSE: XOM)</span>, and <strong>Chevron</strong> <span class="ticker">(NYSE: CVX)</span> stand out to a few Fool.com contributors for their ability to continue thriving at lower crude prices. Here's a closer look at these top-tier oil stocks.</p><p class="caption">Image source: Getty Images.</p><p><a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/3-top-oil-stocks-that-can-still-thrive-even-though/?source=iedfolrf0000001">Continue reading</a></p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/huge-news-for-eli-lilly-stock-investors/</id>
            <title>Huge News for Eli Lilly Stock Investors!</title>
            <link>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/huge-news-for-eli-lilly-stock-investors/?source=iedfolrf0000001</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/huge-news-for-eli-lilly-stock-investors/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 05:40:00 -0400</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p><strong>Eli Lilly</strong> <span class="ticker">(NYSE: LLY)</span> has a strong pipeline of new medicines that could increase the stock price.</p><p><em>*Stock prices used were the afternoon prices of May 15, 2025. The video was published on May 17, 2025.</em></p><p></p><p><a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/huge-news-for-eli-lilly-stock-investors/?source=iedfolrf0000001">Continue reading</a></p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/smartest-fintech-stocks-to-buy-with-1000-right-now/</id>
            <title>The Smartest Fintech Stocks to Buy With $1,000 Right Now</title>
            <link>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/smartest-fintech-stocks-to-buy-with-1000-right-now/?source=iedfolrf0000001</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/smartest-fintech-stocks-to-buy-with-1000-right-now/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 05:30:00 -0400</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p><span>There are many trends shaping our economy. And while everyone seems to remain fixated on artificial intelligence (AI), it's important not to forgot about a trend that has been ongoing for several years.</span></p><p><span>I'm talking about the intersection of financial services and technology, otherwise known as fintech. This category includes both younger and faster-growing enterprises, as well as those that are a bit more mature. Nonetheless, given the rising importance of these businesses, investors should consider allocating capital to the industry.</span></p><p><span>Here are two of the smartest </span><a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/stock-market/market-sectors/financials/fintech-stocks/"><span>fintech stocks</span></a><span> that investors can buy with $1,000 right now.</span></p><p><a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/smartest-fintech-stocks-to-buy-with-1000-right-now/?source=iedfolrf0000001">Continue reading</a></p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/should-you-buy-these-beaten-down-nasdaq-100-stocks/</id>
            <title>Should You Buy These Beaten-Down Nasdaq-100 Stocks?</title>
            <link>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/should-you-buy-these-beaten-down-nasdaq-100-stocks/?source=iedfolrf0000001</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/should-you-buy-these-beaten-down-nasdaq-100-stocks/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 05:25:00 -0400</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>The tech-focused <a href="https://www.fool.com/terms/n/nasdaq-100/"><strong>Nasdaq-100</strong></a> is home to some of the most innovative and fastest-growing companies around. As of May 14, most of the stocks in the index are up year to date. But some of them still offer attractive long-term growth prospects and are trading well off their recent highs, including <strong>Datadog</strong> <span class="ticker">(NASDAQ: DDOG)</span> and <strong>The Trade Desk</strong> <span class="ticker">(NASDAQ: TTD)</span>.</p><p>Datadog shares are currently down 17% year to date, while The Trade Desk shares are down 34.5%. However, these growth stocks jumped off their recent lows following strong earnings reports. Is it time to buy them?</p><p class="caption">Image source: Getty Images.</p><p><a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/should-you-buy-these-beaten-down-nasdaq-100-stocks/?source=iedfolrf0000001">Continue reading</a></p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/is-sofi-technologies-stock-a-millionaire-maker/</id>
            <title>Is SoFi Technologies Stock a Millionaire Maker?</title>
            <link>https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/is-sofi-technologies-stock-a-millionaire-maker/?source=iedfolrf0000001</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/is-sofi-technologies-stock-a-millionaire-maker/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 05:18:00 -0400</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p><span>Shares of </span><strong><span>SoFi Technologies</span></strong><span> <span class="ticker">(NASDAQ: SOFI)</span> are on fire right now. As of May 14, they have surged 47% higher just in the past five or so weeks. This mimics the bullish fever that has taken over the investment community since early April, supported by easing trade tensions and solid financial updates from important businesses.</span></p><p><span>The momentum can definitely create an exciting environment for shareholders. But is this </span><a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/stock-market/market-sectors/financials/fintech-stocks/"><span>fintech stock</span></a><span> a millionaire maker? Here's what investors need to know about SoFi.</span></p><p class="caption">Image source: SoFi.</p><p><a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/2025/05/18/is-sofi-technologies-stock-a-millionaire-maker/?source=iedfolrf0000001">Continue reading</a></p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>