<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <channel>
        <title>TechViral</title>
        <link>https://techviral.net/</link>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://techviral.net/?p=204218</id>
            <title>qBittorrent Getting Deleted or Uninstalled Automatically? Here’s how to fix</title>
            <link>https://techviral.net/qbittorrent-getting-deleted-uninstalled/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://techviral.net/?p=204218</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 13:55:19 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>After installing the qBittorrent 5.0, many torrent users have encountered an unusual problem. Users have claimed that the qBittorrent client is uninstalled automatically after a restart. Some even said the qBittorrent.exe file is deleted soon after the download. If you&#8217;re experiencing the same or a similar problem, here&#8217;s what you should do. Why is qBittorrent [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://techviral.net/qbittorrent-getting-deleted-uninstalled/">qBittorrent Getting Deleted or Uninstalled Automatically? Here&#8217;s how to fix</a> appeared first on <a href="https://techviral.net">TechViral</a>.</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://techviral.net/?p=151152</id>
            <title>5 Ways to Install Audio/Sound Driver in Windows 11</title>
            <link>https://techviral.net/install-audio-driver-windows-11/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://techviral.net/?p=151152</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 13:05:22 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>Windows 11 automatically installs the latest version of device drivers during Windows updates, but sometimes it can fail. If the audio drivers are not installed during the system updates, you will face lots of issues. This article will share a few of the best ways to install the Audio/Sound driver in Windows 11. 1. Install [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://techviral.net/install-audio-driver-windows-11/">5 Ways to Install Audio/Sound Driver in Windows 11</a> appeared first on <a href="https://techviral.net">TechViral</a>.</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://techviral.net/?p=173890</id>
            <title>How to Fix ‘Your Device Isn’t Compatible with this version’ Play Store Error</title>
            <link>https://techviral.net/your-device-isnt-compatible-with-this-version/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://techviral.net/?p=173890</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 09:05:44 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>While downloading apps from the Play Store, you may often see an error message saying, &#8216;Your device isn&#8217;t compatible with this version&#8217;. When this error appears, you won&#8217;t have the Install button, preventing installation. But why does this error appear on the Google Play Store, and how can it be fixed? Why &#8216;Your Device Isn&#8217;t [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://techviral.net/your-device-isnt-compatible-with-this-version/">How to Fix &#8216;Your Device Isn&#8217;t Compatible with this version&#8217; Play Store Error</a> appeared first on <a href="https://techviral.net">TechViral</a>.</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://techviral.net/?p=174718</id>
            <title>9 Ways to Fix File Explorer Not Responding on Windows 11</title>
            <link>https://techviral.net/file-explorer-not-responding-windows-11/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://techviral.net/?p=174718</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 08:05:38 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>Many users have reported that File Explorer is not responding on Windows 11. This is a common problem, especially if you&#8217;ve just installed Windows 11. If you have been facing the same problem, here&#8217;s what you can do to fix it. 1. Restart the Windows 11 File Explorer If you cannot access the file explorer [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://techviral.net/file-explorer-not-responding-windows-11/">9 Ways to Fix File Explorer Not Responding on Windows 11</a> appeared first on <a href="https://techviral.net">TechViral</a>.</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://techviral.net/?p=202300</id>
            <title>Can’t Add .Torrent files to qBittorrent? 6 Best Fixes</title>
            <link>https://techviral.net/cant-add-torrent-files-to-qbittorrent/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://techviral.net/?p=202300</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sat, 17 May 2025 11:55:34 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>qBittorrent is great in many ways. It offers better downloading speed, amazing features, and a torrent search engine. However, one common issue that many new users face while using qBittorrent is being unable to add new torrent files. Can&#8217;t Add New Torrents on qBittorrent? This is a very unusual problem, and it may be related [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://techviral.net/cant-add-torrent-files-to-qbittorrent/">Can&#8217;t Add .Torrent files to qBittorrent? 6 Best Fixes</a> appeared first on <a href="https://techviral.net">TechViral</a>.</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://techviral.net/?p=201749</id>
            <title>BitTorrent Classic Not Opening on Windows 11? 6 Ways to Fix it</title>
            <link>https://techviral.net/bittorrent-classic-not-opening-windows-11/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://techviral.net/?p=201749</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sat, 17 May 2025 10:05:03 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>BitTorrent Classic is great for downloading torrent content from the web. However, recently, a few users were found to be facing problems with it, like the client isn&#8217;t opening after installing the latest Windows 11 update. If you&#8217;re a BitTorrent classic user and experiencing the same problem, here&#8217;s what you can do to fix it. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://techviral.net/bittorrent-classic-not-opening-windows-11/">BitTorrent Classic Not Opening on Windows 11? 6 Ways to Fix it</a> appeared first on <a href="https://techviral.net">TechViral</a>.</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://techviral.net/?p=202890</id>
            <title>Windows Update Error 0x800703e6? Here’s how you can fix it</title>
            <link>https://techviral.net/windows-update-error-0x800703e6/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://techviral.net/?p=202890</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sat, 17 May 2025 09:05:12 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>The error 0x800703e6 generally appears while attempting to install the KB4023057, KB5003214, and KB5003173 updates on Windows 10 versions 1903, 1909, 2004, and 20H2. The error can appear if the drive is at fault, there are missing registry entries, an antivirus/firewall is preventing the Windows Update tool from downloading the update, and so on. Since [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://techviral.net/windows-update-error-0x800703e6/">Windows Update Error 0x800703e6? Here&#8217;s how you can fix it</a> appeared first on <a href="https://techviral.net">TechViral</a>.</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://techviral.net/?p=202724</id>
            <title>What is True Tone on iPhone? How to Enable &amp; Disable it</title>
            <link>https://techviral.net/true-tone-on-iphone/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://techviral.net/?p=202724</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sat, 17 May 2025 08:05:51 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>True Tone is one of the great personalization feature of iPhone, but it often goes unnoticed. The feature is enabled on the new iPhone, but what is it and what does it do? Let&#8217;s know about it in details. What is True Tone on iPhone?  Apple True Tone uses advanced sensors to adjust the color [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://techviral.net/true-tone-on-iphone/">What is True Tone on iPhone? How to Enable &#038; Disable it</a> appeared first on <a href="https://techviral.net">TechViral</a>.</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://techviral.net/?p=81111</id>
            <title>How To Fix Spotify Error Code 18: Unable To Install [Solved]</title>
            <link>https://techviral.net/spotify-error-code-18/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://techviral.net/?p=81111</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Mon, 12 May 2025 11:05:29 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>Many users have reported getting Spotify error code 18 while installing the Spotify app on the desktop. The entire error message reads &#8211; &#8220;The installer is unable to install Spotify because the files to write are in use by another process. Please make sure Spotify is not running and retry. Spotify Error Code 18 So, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://techviral.net/spotify-error-code-18/">How To Fix Spotify Error Code 18: Unable To Install [Solved]</a> appeared first on <a href="https://techviral.net">TechViral</a>.</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://techviral.net/?p=89243</id>
            <title>How To Fix Windows Was Unable To Complete The Format Error</title>
            <link>https://techviral.net/fix-windows-was-unable-to-complete-the-format/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://techviral.net/?p=89243</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Mon, 12 May 2025 09:05:18 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>The &#8216;Windows was unable to format PenDrive&#8217; error mainly occurs when users try to format the pen drive. This is a standard error, and almost all Windows users might have faced it already. In this article, we will share some of the best methods to fix the &#8216;Windows was unable to format the pen drive&#8217; [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://techviral.net/fix-windows-was-unable-to-complete-the-format/">How To Fix Windows Was Unable To Complete The Format Error</a> appeared first on <a href="https://techviral.net">TechViral</a>.</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>