<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <channel>
        <title>Steve Blank</title>
        <link>https://steveblank.com</link>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://steveblank.com/?p=32376</id>
            <title>How the United States Gave Up Being a Science Superpower</title>
            <link>https://steveblank.com/2025/05/13/how-the-united-states-became-a-science-superpower-and-how-quickly-it-could-crumble/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://steveblank.com/?p=32376</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Tue, 13 May 2025 13:00:50 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    This article previously appeared in Nature. US global dominance in science was no accident, but a product of a far-seeing partnership between public and private sectors to boost innovation and economic growth. Since 20 January, US science has been upended by severe cutbacks from the administration of US President Donald Trump. A series of dramatic [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://steveblank.com/?p=32246</id>
            <title>How the U.S. Became A Science Superpower</title>
            <link>https://steveblank.com/2025/04/15/how-the-u-s-became-a-science-superpower/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://steveblank.com/?p=32246</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 13:00:52 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    Prior to WWII the U.S was a distant second in science and engineering. By the time the war was over, U.S. science and engineering had blown past the British, and led the world for 85 years. It happened because two very different people were the science advisors to their nation’s leaders. Each had radically different [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://steveblank.com/?p=31705</id>
            <title>Quantum Computing – An Update</title>
            <link>https://steveblank.com/2024/10/22/quantum-computing-an-update/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://steveblank.com/?p=31705</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 13:00:16 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    In March 2022 I wrote a description of the Quantum Technology Ecosystem. I thought this would be a good time to check in on the progress of building a quantum computer and explain more of the basics. Just as a reminder, Quantum technologies are used in three very different and distinct markets: Quantum Computing, Quantum [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://steveblank.com/?p=31578</id>
            <title>How Saboteurs Threaten Innovation–and What to Do About It</title>
            <link>https://steveblank.com/2024/10/08/how-saboteurs-threaten-innovation-and-what-to-do-about-it/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://steveblank.com/?p=31578</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 14:25:00 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    This article first appeared in First Round Review. “Only the Paranoid Survive” Andy Grove – Intel CEO 1987-1998 I just had an urgent “can we meet today?” coffee with Rohan, an ex-student. His three-year-old startup had been slapped with a notice of patent infringement from a Fortune 500 company. “My lawyers said defending this suit could [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://steveblank.com/?p=31652</id>
            <title>What Does Product Market Fit Sound Like? This.</title>
            <link>https://steveblank.com/2024/10/05/what-does-product-market-fit-sound-like-this/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://steveblank.com/?p=31652</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 18:44:35 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    I got a call from an ex-student asking me &#8220;how do you know when you found product market fit?&#8221; There&#8217;s been lots of words written about it, but no actual recordings of the moment. I remembered I had saved this 90 second, 26 year-old audio file because this is when I knew we had found [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://steveblank.com/?p=31481</id>
            <title>How To Find Your Customer In the Dept of Defense – The Directory of DoD Program Executive Offices</title>
            <link>https://steveblank.com/2024/09/17/the-directory-of-dod-program-executive-offices-and-officers-peos/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://steveblank.com/?p=31481</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 13:00:59 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    Finding a customer for your product in the Department of Defense is hard: Who should you talk to? How do you get their attention? How do you know if they have money to spend on your product? It almost always starts with a Program Executive Office. The Department of Defense (DoD) no longer owns all [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://steveblank.com/?p=31397</id>
            <title>Security Clearances at the Speed of Startups</title>
            <link>https://steveblank.com/2024/08/13/security-clearances-at-the-speed-of-startups/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://steveblank.com/?p=31397</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 13:00:40 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    Imagine you got a job offer from a company but weren’t allowed to start work – or get paid &#8211; for almost a year. And if you can’t pass a security clearance your offer is rescinded. Or you get offered an internship but can’t work on the most interesting part of the project. Sounds like [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://steveblank.com/?p=31262</id>
            <title>Why Large Organizations Struggle With Disruption, and What to Do About It</title>
            <link>https://steveblank.com/2024/07/30/why-large-organizations-struggle-with-disruption-and-what-to-do-about-it/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://steveblank.com/?p=31262</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 13:00:59 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    Seemingly overnight, disruption has allowed challengers to threaten the dominance of companies and government agencies as many of their existing systems have now been leapfrogged. How an organization reacts to this type of disruption determines whether they adapt or die. I’ve been working with a large organization whose very existence is being challenged by an [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://steveblank.com/?p=31068</id>
            <title>Lean LaunchPad @Stanford 2024 – 8 Teams In, 8 Companies Out</title>
            <link>https://steveblank.com/2024/06/27/lean-launchpad-stanford-2024-8-teams-in-8-companies-out/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://steveblank.com/?p=31068</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 13:00:52 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    This post previously appeared in Poets and Quants. We just finished the 14th annual Lean LaunchPad class at Stanford. The class had gotten so popular that in 2021 we started teaching it in both the winter and spring sessions. During the quarter the eight teams spoke to 919 potential customers, beneficiaries and regulators. Most students spent [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://steveblank.com/?p=31004</id>
            <title>Hacking for Defense @ Stanford 2024 – Lessons Learned Presentations</title>
            <link>https://steveblank.com/2024/06/24/hacking-for-defense-stanford-2024-lessons-learned-presentations/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://steveblank.com/?p=31004</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 13:00:41 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    We just finished our 9th annual Hacking for Defense class at Stanford. What a year. Hacking for Defense, now in 60 universities, has teams of students working to understand and help solve national security problems. At Stanford this quarter the 8 teams of 40 students collectively interviewed 968 beneficiaries, stakeholders, requirements writers, program managers, industry partners, [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://steveblank.com/?p=30966</id>
            <title>You’re Invited: Hacking for Defense and Lean LaunchPad Final Presentations</title>
            <link>https://steveblank.com/2024/06/03/youre-invited-hacking-for-defense-and-lean-launchpad-final-presentations/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://steveblank.com/?p=30966</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 13:00:35 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    Join us for the final presentations of our two Stanford classes this Tuesday June 4th and Wednesday June 5th. Tuesday = Hacking for Defense Wednesday = Lean Launchpad The presentations just get better every year.  Attend in person or via Zoom. This year AI seems to be part of almost every team. Zoom link and [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://steveblank.com/?p=30915</id>
            <title>Gordon Bell R.I.P.</title>
            <link>https://steveblank.com/2024/05/26/gordon-bell-r-i-p/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://steveblank.com/?p=30915</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 26 May 2024 13:00:37 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    Gordon Bell passed on this month. I was a latecomer in Gordon Bell’s life.  But he made a lasting impact on mine. The first time I laid eyes on Gordon Bell was in 1984 outside a restaurant in a Boston suburb when he pulled up in a Porsche. I was the head of Marketing for [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://steveblank.com/?p=30888</id>
            <title>The Venture Mindset – Worth A Read</title>
            <link>https://steveblank.com/2024/05/21/the-venture-mindset-worth-a-read/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://steveblank.com/?p=30888</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Tue, 21 May 2024 13:00:03 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    Ilya Strebulaev at the Stanford Graduate School of Business and Director of the Stanford Venture Capital Initiative just came out with a book that should be on your reading list – The Venture Mindset. The books premise is that Venture Capitalists (who were responsible for the launch of one-fifth of the 300 largest U.S. public [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://steveblank.com/?p=30827</id>
            <title>Secret History – When Kodak Went to War with Polaroid</title>
            <link>https://steveblank.com/2024/05/16/secret-history-when-kodak-went-to-war-with-polaroid/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://steveblank.com/?p=30827</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Thu, 16 May 2024 13:00:49 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    This part 2 of the Secret History of Polaroid and Edwin Land. Read part 1 for context. Kodak and Polaroid, the two most famous camera companies of the 20th century, had a great partnership for 20+ years. Then in an inexplicable turnabout Kodak decided to destroy Polaroid’s business. To this day, every story of why [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://steveblank.com/?p=30767</id>
            <title>The Secret History of Polaroid CEO Edwin Land</title>
            <link>https://steveblank.com/2024/04/30/the-secret-history-of-silicon-valley-the-secret-life-of-polaroid-ceo-edwin-land-part-1/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://steveblank.com/?p=30767</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 13:00:59 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    The connections between the world of national security and commercial companies still has surprises. December 1976 &#8211; Vandenberg Air Force Base, U.S. military space port on the coast of California As a Titan IIID rocket blasted off, it carried a spacecraft on top that would change everything about how intelligence from space was gathered. Heading [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://steveblank.com/?p=30742</id>
            <title>Founders Need to Be Ruthless When Chasing Deals</title>
            <link>https://steveblank.com/2024/04/16/founders-need-to-be-ruthless-when-chasing-deals/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://steveblank.com/?p=30742</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 13:00:20 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    One of the most exciting things a startup CEO in a business-to-business market can hear from a potential customer is, “We’re excited. When can you come back and show us a prototype?” This can be the beginning of a profitable customer relationship or a disappointing sinkhole of wasted time, money, resources, and a demoralized engineering [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://steveblank.com/?p=30677</id>
            <title>Is a $100 Million Enough?</title>
            <link>https://steveblank.com/2024/03/05/is-a-100-million-enough/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://steveblank.com/?p=30677</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 14:00:26 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    This article first appeared in Inc. Capitalism has been good to me. After serving in the military during Vietnam, I came home and had a career in eight startups. I got to retire when I was 45. Over the last quarter century, in my third career, I helped create the methods entrepreneurs use to build [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://steveblank.com/?p=30553</id>
            <title>Apple Vision Pro – Tech in the Search of a Market</title>
            <link>https://steveblank.com/2024/02/13/apple-vision-pro-tech-in-the-search-of-a-market/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://steveblank.com/?p=30553</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 14:00:16 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    A version of this article previously appeared in Fortune. If you haven’t been paying attention Apple has started shipping its Apple Vision Pro, its take on a headset that combines Virtual Reality (VR) and Augmented Reality (AR). The product is an amazing technical tour de force. But the product/market fit of this first iteration is [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://steveblank.com/?p=30431</id>
            <title>Technology, Innovation, and Great Power Competition – 2023 Wrap Up</title>
            <link>https://steveblank.com/2024/02/06/technology-innovation-and-great-power-competition-2023-wrap-up/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://steveblank.com/?p=30431</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 14:00:02 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    We just wrapped up the third year of our Technology, Innovation, and Great Power Competition class –part of Stanford’s Gordian Knot Center for National Security Innovation. Joe Felter, Mike Brown and I teach the class to: Give our students an appreciation of the challenges and opportunities for the United States in its enduring strategic competition [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://steveblank.com/?p=30379</id>
            <title>The Department of Defense Is Getting Its Innovation Act Together – But More Can Be Done</title>
            <link>https://steveblank.com/2024/01/15/the-department-of-defense-is-getting-its-innovation-act-together/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://steveblank.com/?p=30379</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 14:00:54 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    This post previously appeared in Defense News  and C4SIR. Despite the clear and present danger of threats from China and elsewhere, there’s no agreement on what types of adversaries we’ll face; how we&#8217;ll fight, organize, and train; and what weapons or systems we&#8217;ll need for future fights. Instead, developing a new doctrine to deal with these [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>