<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <channel>
        <title>Futurism</title>
        <link>https://futurism.com</link>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://futurism.com/?p=351477</id>
            <title>Benevolent Orca Pods Are Adopting Baby Pilot Whales in an Apparent Effort to Clean Up the Species' Image</title>
            <link>https://futurism.com/orca-pod-adopts-baby-pilot-whale</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://futurism.com/?p=351477</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 12:00:33 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>Baby Bump As so-called "killer whales" have made news over the past few years for violent boat attacks in European waters, marine biologists have noticed a far sweeter behavior in Iceland's frigid waves: the adoption of a baby whale from an entirely different species. In interviews with Scientific American, scientists described their shock at observing, over a period of years, a pilot whale calf that traveled with an Icelandic pod of orcas. One of those researchers, Chérine Baumgartner, said she and her colleagues at the Icelandic Orca Project initially couldn't believe their eyes. "At first, we were like, 'Oh my god, […]</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://futurism.com/?p=351460</id>
            <title>Something Wild Happens When You Try to Take a Video of a Car's Sensors</title>
            <link>https://futurism.com/video-lidar-damage-smartphone</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://futurism.com/?p=351460</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 11:30:58 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>Public service announcement: don't point your phone camera directly at a lidar sensor. On Reddit, a user named Jeguetelli recently shared a video demonstrating why.  As the camera zooms in on the sensor affixed to the top of a Volvo EX90, a whole galaxy of colorful dots are burned into the image, forming over the exact spot that the flashing light inside the lidar device can be seen. What you're witnessing isn't lens flare or a digital glitch — it's real, physical damage to the lens. And it's permanent. "Lidar lasers burn your camera," the user warned.  Lidar is short […]</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://futurism.com/?p=351353</id>
            <title>Engineers Reveal Robot That Takes Care of Old People So You Don’t Have to</title>
            <link>https://futurism.com/engineers-elderly-robot-assistant</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://futurism.com/?p=351353</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 11:00:27 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>[debating whether this falls under advanced humans or robotics] The United States is not a great place for old people, to put it lightly. Though the elderly population is at its highest number in history, the elderly still face TK, TK, and increasing levels of eldercare abuse. That's not to mention the prospect of growing old in a society where your wellbeing is directly tied to your wage — as that same society devises ever-more powerful AI models that can scam you out of your 401K at anytime. Luckily, some crafty American engineers are using some good old techno-solutionism to […]</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://futurism.com/?p=351451</id>
            <title>Elon Musk Is Doing Business With Actual Terrorists, Nonprofit Finds</title>
            <link>https://futurism.com/elon-musk-twitter-subscription-terrorists</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://futurism.com/?p=351451</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 10:30:05 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>Who's paying for a blue checkmark on X-formerly-Twitter these days? According to a new report from the Tech Transparency Project (TTP), the answer is: a bunch of terrorists. The TTP investigation found that more than 200 X users including individuals who appear to be affiliated with Al-Qaeda, Hezbollah, Hamas, the Houthis, and Syrian and Iraqi militia groups — all deemed foreign terrorist organizations, or FTOs, by the US government — are paying for subscriptions to X, the social media site owned by Elon Musk, the world's richest man and leader of the so-called Department of Government Efficiency (DOGE). These paid […]</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://futurism.com/?p=351323</id>
            <title>Startup Claims Its "Superwood" Is Stronger Than Steel</title>
            <link>https://futurism.com/startup-superwood-steel</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://futurism.com/?p=351323</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 10:00:24 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>TK A new startup is making the bold claim that it can mass-produce "Superwood," which it says is stronger and lighter than steel, with 90 percent lower carbon emissions compared to steel. If that sounds wild, it's because it is. InventWood, the company behind the material, claims its new product "has the capacity to substitute up to 80 percent of steel used globally," and "reduce greenhouse gas emissions by over 2 gigatons." On its website, InventWood claims that Superwood has up to 50 percent more strength compared to steel, has "minimal expansion and contraction," and a Class A fire rating […]</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://futurism.com/?p=351295</id>
            <title>Watch a 98-Year-Old World War II Vet Absolutely Demolish a Tesla With a Tank</title>
            <link>https://futurism.com/the-byte/ww2-vet-tesla-tank</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://futurism.com/?p=351295</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 09:30:35 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>Crushing Fascism A 98-year-old World War II veteran, who served in the British Army, absolutely destroyed a Tesla vehicle with the license plate "FASCIM" in a recently shared YouTube video. As first spotted by Gizmodo, veteran Ken Turner used a Sherman tank, one of the most widely used tanks used by the US and its western allies against the Nazis in World War II, to turn a navy blue Tesla into a pancake. The video was uploaded by the British political group Led by Donkeys to send a clear message. "Elon Musk, the richest man in the world, is using […]</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://futurism.com/?p=351285</id>
            <title>AI Chatbots Are Becoming Even Worse At Summarizing Data</title>
            <link>https://futurism.com/ai-chatbots-summarizing-research</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://futurism.com/?p=351285</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 09:00:29 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>Ask the CEO of any AI startup, and you'll probably get an earful about the tech's potential to "transform work," or "revolutionize the way we access knowledge." Really, there's no shortage of promises that AI is only getting smarter — which we're told will speed up the rate of scientific breakthroughs, streamline medical testing, and breed a new kind of scholarship. But according to a new study published in the Royal Society, as many as 73 percent of seemingly reliable factual answers from AI chatbots could actually be inaccurate. The collaborative research paper looked at nearly 5,000 large language model (LLM) […]</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://futurism.com/?p=351622</id>
            <title>World Leaders Shown AI Baby Versions of Themselves at European Summit</title>
            <link>https://futurism.com/the-byte/ai-baby-world-leaders-summit</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://futurism.com/?p=351622</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sat, 17 May 2025 12:30:01 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>Baby Erdoğan's Mustache It's called diplomacy, guys. This year's European Political Community, an annual forum for European leaders founded in 2022 following the Russian invasion of Ukraine, kicked off on Friday in Tirana, Albania. Europe's leaders were greeted with a ten-ish minute presentation that celebrated Europe's commitment to sovereignty and shared triumphs over evil. There were flashing lights and dance performances, and a few different video sequences. And to close out the show, as Politico reports, the Albanian government landed on the obvious editorial choice: a montage of the summit's leaders pictured as AI-generated babies, who each said "Welcome to Albania" […]</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://futurism.com/?p=351330</id>
            <title>Star Wars' Showcase of AI Special Effects Was a Complete Disaster</title>
            <link>https://futurism.com/star-wars-showcase-ai-special-effects-disaster</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://futurism.com/?p=351330</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sat, 17 May 2025 12:00:43 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>If Disney leadership has it their way, we'll all be drooling over endless Star Wars reboots, sequels, and spinoffs until the Sun explodes. And what better way to keep the slop machine humming than using good old generative AI? Unfortunately, as highlighted by 404 Media, we just got a preview of what that'd look like. This month, Industrial Light and Magic, the legendary visual effects studio behind nearly every "Star Wars" movie, released a new demo showcasing how AI could supercharge depictions of the sci-fi universe. And unsurprisingly, it looks absolutely, flabbergastingly awful. The demo, called "Star Wars: Field Guide," […]</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://futurism.com/?p=351046</id>
            <title>Scientists Tweaked LSD’s Molecular Structure and Created a Wild New Brain Drug</title>
            <link>https://futurism.com/neoscope/dna-lsd-changes-schizophrenia</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://futurism.com/?p=351046</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sat, 17 May 2025 11:30:07 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>A team of researchers at the University of California, Davis, made small tweaks to the DNA structure of lysergic acid diethylamide (LSD) to see if it could be turned into an effective brain-healing treatment for patients that suffer from conditions like schizophrenia — without risking a potentially disastrous acid trip. As detailed in a new paper published in the journal Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences last month, the researchers created a new compound, dubbed JRT, by altering the position of just two atoms of the psychedelic's molecular structure. With the two atoms flipped, the new drug could still […]</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://futurism.com/?p=351082</id>
            <title>The Hot New AI Tool in Law Enforcement Is a Workaround for Places Where Facial Recognition Is Banned</title>
            <link>https://futurism.com/track-facial-recognition-ai-tool</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://futurism.com/?p=351082</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sat, 17 May 2025 11:00:37 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>At the end of 2024, fifteen U.S. states had laws banning some version of facial recognition. Usually, these laws were written on the basis that the technology is a nightmare-level privacy invasion that's also too shoddy to be relied upon. Now, a new company aims to solve that problem — though maybe not in the way you'd imagine (or like). Per a report in the MIT Technology Review, a new AI tool called Track is being used not to improve facial recognition technology, nor as a way to make it less invasive of your personal civil liberties, but as a […]</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://futurism.com/?p=351513</id>
            <title>Brazilian "Supercows" Reportedly Close to Achieving World Domination</title>
            <link>https://futurism.com/the-byte/brazilian-supercows-world-domination</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://futurism.com/?p=351513</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sat, 17 May 2025 10:30:23 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>More Cowbell In southeastern Brazil, bovine beauty pageants help determine the most genetically-desirable cows in the world — and these "supercows" are changing the meat farming as we know it. As The Economist reports, the drapey-necked "zebu" cows who compete in Brazil's ExpoZebu gala originally hailed from India, but have been proliferating in the South American country since the 19th century — initially thanks to a natural resistance to heat and parasites that European breeds lacked, and later thanks to genetic modification and cloning. In Brazil's Minas Gerais, cattle farming took the region from poverty to plenty — and zebu, […]</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://futurism.com/?p=351094</id>
            <title>What Are Alien Dyson Spheres, Why Are They So Janky, and Why Are They Doomed to Go Undetected?</title>
            <link>https://futurism.com/alien-megastructures-self-destruct</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://futurism.com/?p=351094</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sat, 17 May 2025 10:00:50 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>In the 1960s, physicist Freeman Dyson proposed that advanced alien civilizations could be building out enormous megastructures around a star to harness much of its energy. These shells, dubbed Dyson spheres, could be giving off distinct technosignatures, astronomers have suggested, allowing us to glimpse them from many light-years away. Yet, despite our best efforts, we have yet to make first contact, let alone with a megastructure siphoning off the energy released by a star. And, as New Scientist reports, there could be a good reason for that. According to Brian Lacki, a scientist involved with the Breakthrough Listen Initiative, which […]</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://futurism.com/?p=351226</id>
            <title>Study: Living Near a Golf Course Could Lead to a Terrible Chronic Illness</title>
            <link>https://futurism.com/neoscope/golf-course-parkinsons-disease-pesticides</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://futurism.com/?p=351226</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sat, 17 May 2025 09:30:24 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>A controversial new study has found that those who live in close proximity to a golf course may face up to three times the odds of developing Parkinson's disease, a progressive neurological disorder that causes tremors and difficulty with balance. According to a new population-based case-control study published in the journal JAMA Network Open, environmental risks, including pesticide exposure and groundwater contamination, could be contributing to the risk of developing Parkinson's. In the United States, golf courses are treated with extremely high levels of pesticides, which could be hazardous to human health. The team examined medical records of over 5,000 […]</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://futurism.com/?p=351255</id>
            <title>General Motors Unveils Their "Groundbreaking" New EV Battery</title>
            <link>https://futurism.com/the-byte/general-motors-ev-battery</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://futurism.com/?p=351255</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sat, 17 May 2025 09:00:23 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>General Motors is a something of a silent warrior among electric vehicle giants. Though they weren't a hit with car buyers, the company's early efforts at EV development back in the 1990s paved the way for the Teslas and Rivians of today. As far back as 1990, GM engineers were pioneering many of the standard features found on electric vehicles two and a half decades later, like keyless ignition, tire-pressure sensors, heat-pump HVAC, and electric-defrosting windows. Even inductive charging traces its roots back to this work, a system GM called Magne Charge. Of course, it also makes EVs today, like […]</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://futurism.com/?p=351631</id>
            <title>Amazon’s Delivery Drones Are Crashing, and We Finally Know Why</title>
            <link>https://futurism.com/amazon-drones-crashing</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://futurism.com/?p=351631</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Fri, 16 May 2025 23:01:09 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>Amazon, the multi-trillion dollar e-commerce monolith, seemingly cheaped out on keeping a key feature installed on its delivery six-propeller drones. And predictably, this backfired almost immediately. On a rainy December day at the company's testing range in Oregon, not one but two Prime Air drones suddenly stopped spinning their propellers mid-flight and plummeted some 200 feet to the ground. The crashes, which destroyed both aircraft, happened within minutes of each other.  And now, Bloomberg reports, we know why. According to National Transportation Safety Board documents, bad readings from the drones' onboard lidar sensors led the drone to believe it had […]</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://futurism.com/?p=351568</id>
            <title>AI Is Helping Job Seekers Lie, Flood the Market, and Steal Jobs</title>
            <link>https://futurism.com/the-byte/lying-resume-ai-new-normal</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://futurism.com/?p=351568</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Fri, 16 May 2025 21:30:13 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>The advent of generative AI has fundamentally altered the job application process. Both recruiters and applicants are making ample use of the tech, making an already soul-sucking and tedious process even worse. And as TechRadar reports, applicants are going to extreme lengths to nail down a job. According to a recent campaign by insurer Hiscox, [lol] more than half of recent job applicants said they had used AI tools to write their resumes. A whopping 37 percent admitted they didn't bother correcting embellishments the AI chatbot made, like exaggerated experience and fabricated interests. The news highlights a worrying new normal, with […]</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://futurism.com/?p=351546</id>
            <title>In a World First, CRISPR Drug Tailored for One Baby Shows Life-Saving Promise</title>
            <link>https://futurism.com/neoscope/crispr-drug-baby-cps1</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://futurism.com/?p=351546</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Fri, 16 May 2025 20:34:09 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>Scientists used CRISPR tech to create a custom-made drug targeted at helping a newborn baby fight a rare genetic disorder. According to an extraordinary new paper published in The New England Journal of Medicine, the drug worked — marking the first time that a patient was successfully healed with a bespoke gene-hacked medicine, and a possible watershed moment for the field of genetic medicine. The baby, named KJ Muldoon, was born at the Children's Hospital of Philadelphia (CHOP) and at Penn Medicine with a rare genetic condition called CPS1 deficiency. According to the National Institutes of Health (NIH), the condition […]</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://futurism.com/?p=351530</id>
            <title>Anthropic Tried to Defend Itself With AI and It Backfired Horribly</title>
            <link>https://futurism.com/anthropic-chatbot-legal-music</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://futurism.com/?p=351530</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Fri, 16 May 2025 18:47:57 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>The advent of AI has already made a splash in the legal world, to say the least. In the past few months, we've watched as a tech entrepreneur gave testimony through an AI avatar, trial lawyers filed a massive brief riddled with AI hallucinations, and the MyPillow guy tried to exonerate himself in front of a federal judge with ChatGPT. By now, it ought to be a well-known fact that AI is an unreliable source of info for just about anything, let alone for something as intricate as a legal filing. One Stanford University study found that AI tools make […]</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://futurism.com/?p=351551</id>
            <title>NASA’s James Webb Telescope Just Found Frozen Water Around Another Star</title>
            <link>https://futurism.com/james-webb-water-ice-surrounding-star</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://futurism.com/?p=351551</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Fri, 16 May 2025 17:42:53 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>Water ice is a crucial building block of planetary systems. We've found plenty of it in our own Solar System, in places like Europa, Mars, and wayward comets, but we've never made a definitive detection of frozen water around other stars. Plenty of water vapor, yes, but no ice. But that just changed. Using NASA's James Webb Space Telescope, a team of astronomers have confirmed the presence of water ice in a debris disk encircling a young, Sun-like star just 155 light years away. And tantalizingly, it's the same kind of ice found in our own system. "Webb unambiguously detected […]</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>