<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <channel>
        <title>DZone Performance Zone</title>
        <link>https://dzone.com/performance</link>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://dzone.com/articles/3550842</id>
            <title>AI-Driven Root Cause Analysis in SRE: Enhancing Incident Resolution</title>
            <link>https://dzone.com/articles/ai-driven-root-cause-analysis-in-sre</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dzone.com/articles/3550842</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Fri, 16 May 2025 11:00:00 GMT</updated>
                
            <media:thumbnail url="https://dz2cdn1.dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=18400846&amp;w=600"/>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <h2 dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;">Introduction</h2>
<p dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;">Site Reliability Engineering (SRE) is one of the key pillars for organizations. SRE teams are responsible for maintaining the system's scalability and reliability. One of the key challenges SRE teams face is dealing with alert floods, parsing cryptic logs, and the pressure of SLA timers. These challenges make Root Cause Analysis (RCA) of an incident really tough. With the increasing complexity of distributed infrastructure, identifying RCA and resolving incidents become more difficult. Because conventional troubleshooting methods require manual log analysis and the review of multiple data sources, they are very time-consuming and demand a large employee workforce.</p>
<p dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;">In this article, we will examine how Artificial Intelligence (AI) is benefiting <a href="https://dzone.com/articles/root-cause-analysis-in-software-development-teams">Root Cause Analysis</a> (RCA) in incident management by automating processes, reducing resolution time, and improving overall system reliability. This article delves into the techniques used and challenges faced.</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://dzone.com/articles/3557265</id>
            <title>Vibe Coding With GitHub Copilot: Optimizing API Performance in Fintech Microservices</title>
            <link>https://dzone.com/articles/vibe-coding-github-copilot-fintech-apis</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dzone.com/articles/3557265</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Thu, 15 May 2025 15:00:00 GMT</updated>
                
            <media:thumbnail url="https://dz2cdn1.dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=18402427&amp;w=600"/>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p style="text-align: left;">In fintech, APIs power everything. Starting from payments to trading to real-time customer experiences, the API takes care of everything. Performance isn't optional, but it's critical for user trust and business success.&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">As a fintech API and cloud optimization expert, I constantly face the challenge of balancing quick development with high performance. When Microsoft announced GitHub Copilot for free, I asked myself a real-world question:<em>&nbsp;Can GitHub Copilot go beyond writing boilerplate code and help optimize fintech Microservice APIs?</em></p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://dzone.com/articles/3550773</id>
            <title>How To Develop a Truly Performant Mobile Application in 2025: A Case for Android</title>
            <link>https://dzone.com/articles/developing-high-perfomant-android-mobile-app</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dzone.com/articles/3550773</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Wed, 14 May 2025 16:00:00 GMT</updated>
                
            <media:thumbnail url="https://dz2cdn1.dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=18400654&amp;w=600"/>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>To develop a high-performance mobile application, you need functional code—<em>and</em> a responsive, intuitive user experience. As a mobile developer who has spent years working on Android, I’ve learned that performance optimization is both art and science. Balancing technical precision with user-centric design has become a key principle in my career.</p>
<h2>Performance is Key</h2>
<p>Today's users expect quick responses and seamless UIs as the standard, not the exception. Delays of even a few seconds often leads users to stop using the application altogether. I still remember, early on in my career, how milliseconds of latency hurt user engagement. That understanding formed my belief that performance optimization is not about technical metrics but rather about creating an experience that’s "invisible." This looks as if an app just works, without the user realizing the complexity underneath.</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://dzone.com/articles/3550714</id>
            <title>Beyond Code Coverage: A Risk-Driven Revolution in Software Testing With Machine Learning</title>
            <link>https://dzone.com/articles/software-testing-with-machine-learning</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dzone.com/articles/3550714</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Wed, 14 May 2025 15:00:00 GMT</updated>
                
            <media:thumbnail url="https://dz2cdn1.dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=18400615&amp;w=600"/>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p dir="ltr">Modern systems require more than high code coverage because they are complex and interconnected. Through machine learning development, companies can create advanced tools that link risk-based planning methods to enhance their software testing outcomes.&nbsp;</p>
<p dir="ltr">With the focus on the possibility of failure and its effects, risk-based testing provides both improved efficiency and better effectiveness. RBT selects its execution focus on core features and often modified code and components known for producing defects.&nbsp;</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://dzone.com/articles/3554872</id>
            <title>Scaling DevOps With NGINX Caching: Reducing Latency and Backend Load</title>
            <link>https://dzone.com/articles/scaling-devops-principles-for-reducing-web-latency</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dzone.com/articles/3554872</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Tue, 13 May 2025 15:00:03 GMT</updated>
                
            <media:thumbnail url="https://dz2cdn1.dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=18394428&amp;w=600"/>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>In large-scale companies with huge DevOps environments, caching isn’t just an optimization — it’s a survival strategy. Applications teams working with artifact repositories, container registries, and CI/CD pipelines often encounter performance issues that aren’t rooted in code inefficiencies, but rather in the overwhelming volume of metadata requests hammering artifact services or in short binary storage systems, which are key to the functioning of any application or batch.</p>
<blockquote>
 <p>"A well-architected caching strategy can mitigate these challenges by reducing unnecessary backend load and improving request efficiency."</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://dzone.com/articles/3540771</id>
            <title>Why High-Performance AI/ML Is Essential in Modern Cybersecurity</title>
            <link>https://dzone.com/articles/why-high-performance-aiml-is-essential-in-modern-c</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dzone.com/articles/3540771</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Mon, 12 May 2025 13:00:00 GMT</updated>
                
            <media:thumbnail url="https://dz2cdn1.dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=18391557&amp;w=600"/>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>Today, organizations thrive in a complex and evolving threat landscape, and cybersecurity has become pivotal for digital resilience. Various sophisticated attacks, such as supply chain breaches, ransomware, phishing via malicious email campaigns, and vulnerabilities in cloud and Internet of Things (IOT) environments, need advanced, performance-sensitive solutions that can detect in real time and also respond to and mitigate these attacks.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Artificial intelligence and machine learning (ML) play a frontal role in these transformations, providing the necessary capabilities to secure digital systems effectively.</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://dzone.com/articles/3563563</id>
            <title>The Human Side of Logs: What Unstructured Data Is Trying to Tell You</title>
            <link>https://dzone.com/articles/human-side-of-logs-unstructured-data-insights</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dzone.com/articles/3563563</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Fri, 09 May 2025 17:00:00 GMT</updated>
                
            <media:thumbnail url="https://dz2cdn1.dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=18387646&amp;w=600"/>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p dir="ltr">It’s Friday afternoon, and your dashboards look great. Charts are green. CPU usage is stable. Database query times are within your SLA. You’re feeling great and ready for the weekend.</p>
<p dir="ltr">But little do you know, there’s a significant issue being overlooked by all your metrics — and it’s about to ruin your weekend.&nbsp;</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://dzone.com/articles/3546214</id>
            <title>Scalable System Design: Core Concepts for Building Reliable Software</title>
            <link>https://dzone.com/articles/software-system-design-concepts</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dzone.com/articles/3546214</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Thu, 08 May 2025 14:00:00 GMT</updated>
                
            <media:thumbnail url="https://dz2cdn1.dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=18384066&amp;w=600"/>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>System design refers to the process of defining and creating a high-level architecture that meets certain requirements related to performance, scalability, availability, maintainability, and more. Based on my learnings and experience so far as a senior software engineering leader, I have tried to summarize the key concepts of software system design. Here are some of the most important concepts you’ll encounter when designing large-scale systems:</p>
<h2>Scalability</h2>
<p>The ability of a system to handle an increasing workload (either by scaling up or scaling out) without sacrificing performance.</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://dzone.com/articles/3462094</id>
            <title>Top Book Picks for Site Reliability Engineers</title>
            <link>https://dzone.com/articles/must-read-books-for-site-reliability-engineers</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dzone.com/articles/3462094</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Wed, 07 May 2025 22:00:00 GMT</updated>
                
            <media:thumbnail url="https://dz2cdn1.dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=18374695&amp;w=600"/>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>I believe reading is fundamental. site reliability engineers (SREs) need to have deep knowledge in a wide range of subjects and topics such as coding, operating systems, computer networking, large-scale distributed systems, <a href="https://dzone.com/articles/site-reliability-and-engineering">SRE best practices</a>, and more to be successful at their job. In this article, I discuss a few books that will help SREs to become better at their job.</p>
<h2>1. <em>Site Reliability Engineering,</em> by the Google SRE team</h2>
<p>Google originally coined the term "Site Reliability Engineering." This book is a must read for anyone interested in site reliability engineering. It covers a wide range of topics that SREs focus on day to day such as SLOs, eliminating toil, monitoring distributed systems, release management, incident management, infrastructure, and more. This books gives an overview of the different elements that SREs work on. Although this book has many topics specific to Google, it provides a good framework and mental model about various SRE topics. The online version of this book is freely available, so there is no excuse not to read it. &nbsp;<a href="https://sre.google/sre-book/table-of-contents/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">The free online version of this book is available here</a>.</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://dzone.com/articles/3526498</id>
            <title>The Ultimate Chaos Testing Guide</title>
            <link>https://dzone.com/articles/ultimate-chaos-testing-guide</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dzone.com/articles/3526498</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Wed, 07 May 2025 19:00:00 GMT</updated>
                
            <media:thumbnail url="https://dz2cdn1.dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=18385595&amp;w=600"/>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <h2>Introduction</h2>
<p>Ensuring system resilience and dependability has become a top goal in the quickly evolving field of software development. The complex interdependencies and unforeseen failure scenarios that occur in production contexts are frequently missed by standard testing techniques, despite their importance. Organizations can proactively identify vulnerabilities and fix them before they cause major disruptions by using the revolutionary approach that chaos testing provides.</p>
<h2>Understanding the Chaos Testing Paradigm&nbsp;</h2>
<p>A systematic and purposeful approach to evaluating <a href="https://dzone.com/articles/microservices-architectures-what-is-fault-toleranc">fault tolerance</a> is chaos testing, which is an integral part of Chaos engineering and involves purposefully introducing controlled failures into a system in order to observe and monitor how it behaves. By purposefully interfering with the system's regular operations, engineers are able to find elusive defects, delicate code pathways, and hidden dependencies that conventional testing techniques can miss. &nbsp;By accepting the unpredictable nature of real-world situations, chaos testing gives businesses important information about the weaknesses in their systems, allowing them to create stronger and more resilient solutions.</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://dzone.com/articles/3535339</id>
            <title>Hybrid Cloud vs Multi-Cloud: Choosing the Right Strategy for AI Scalability and Security</title>
            <link>https://dzone.com/articles/hybrid-cloud-vs-multi-cloud</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dzone.com/articles/3535339</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Tue, 06 May 2025 15:00:05 GMT</updated>
                
            <media:thumbnail url="https://dz2cdn1.dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=18381411&amp;w=600"/>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p><span lang="EN-US">As enterprises accelerate AI adoption, their cloud strategy determines whether they can efficiently train models, scale workloads, and ensure compliance. Given the computational intensity and data sensitivity of AI, businesses must choose between hybrid cloud and multi-cloud architectures. While both hybrid cloud and multi-cloud approaches offer distinct advantages, understanding their nuances is crucial for organizations aiming to build robust AI infrastructure.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span lang="EN-US">This article explores the key differences between these strategies and provides practical guidance for enterprises preparing for AI adoption.</span><span>&nbsp;</span></p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://dzone.com/articles/3555701</id>
            <title>How Large Tech Companies Architect Resilient Systems for Millions of Users</title>
            <link>https://dzone.com/articles/resilient-systems-for-millions-tech-architecture</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dzone.com/articles/3555701</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Fri, 02 May 2025 21:00:00 GMT</updated>
                
            <media:thumbnail url="https://dz2cdn1.dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=18377750&amp;w=600"/>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>When you are serving millions of users, resilience cannot be something you add later. It has to be part of the design from the very beginning. Otherwise, with the way user expectations keep climbing and how global traffic patterns shift, your system simply won’t keep up.</p>
<p>What I want to walk you through today is how top companies think about resilience at scale. We will go through the strategies that work in the real world — not just theory — and look at how availability, cost, observability, scaling, and system design all come together.</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://dzone.com/articles/3555577</id>
            <title>Rust and WebAssembly: Unlocking High-Performance Web Apps</title>
            <link>https://dzone.com/articles/rust-and-webassembly-for-web-apps</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dzone.com/articles/3555577</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Fri, 02 May 2025 18:00:00 GMT</updated>
                
            <media:thumbnail url="https://dz2cdn1.dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=18377705&amp;w=600"/>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>Information technology continues to transform at an accelerated pace because modern businesses seek faster, high-performance applications. JavaScript-based development solutions from the past tend to fall behind when performing complex computations, which produce performance issues along with ineffective execution.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Fast, efficient web applications emerge through a synergistic relationship between Rust and Wasm technology. WebAssembly offers developers a novel technology to achieve native-level execution speed in web applications alongside standard web platform benefits.&nbsp;</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://dzone.com/articles/3555509</id>
            <title>Docker Base Images Demystified: A Practical Guide</title>
            <link>https://dzone.com/articles/docker-base-images-demystified</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dzone.com/articles/3555509</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Fri, 02 May 2025 16:00:07 GMT</updated>
                
            <media:thumbnail url="https://dz2cdn1.dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=18377693&amp;w=600"/>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <h2>What Is a Docker Base Image?</h2>
<p>A Docker base image is the foundational layer from which containers are built. Think of it as the “starting point” for your application’s environment. It’s a minimal, preconfigured template containing an operating system, runtime tools, libraries, and dependencies. When you write a Dockerfile, the <code>FROM</code> command defines this base image, setting the stage for all subsequent layers.&nbsp;</p>
<p>For example, you might start with a lightweight Linux distribution like Alpine, a language-specific image like <a href="https://dzone.com/articles/python-tutorial-for-beginners-a-comprehensive-guid">Python</a> or <a href="https://dzone.com/articles/watch-a-writer-learn-nodejs-part-1">Node.js</a>, or even an empty "scratch" image for ultimate customization. These base images abstract away the underlying infrastructure, ensuring consistency across development, testing, and production environments. Choosing the right base image is critical, as it directly impacts your container’s security, size, performance, and maintainability. Whether optimizing for speed or ensuring compatibility, your base image shapes everything that follows.</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://dzone.com/articles/3556642</id>
            <title>Zero Trust for AWS NLBs: Why It Matters and How to Do It</title>
            <link>https://dzone.com/articles/zero-trust-for-aws-nlbs</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dzone.com/articles/3556642</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Thu, 01 May 2025 19:00:00 GMT</updated>
                
            <media:thumbnail url="https://dz2cdn1.dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=18373771&amp;w=600"/>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <h2>Introduction to AWS Network Load Balancer</h2>
<p>AWS has several critical services that drive the internet. If you have ever built any application on top of AWS and need a high throughput or volume of traffic, the chances are that you’ve leaned on an AWS Network Load Balancer at some point in the discussion. AWS NLB is nothing but a Layer 4 load balancer, and consistency helps with low-latency forwarding of massive amounts of TCP, UDP, and even TLS traffic. NLBs, being operational at Layer 4 of the OSI model, support a host of features. You get features like static IPs, support for long-lived connections out of the box, and can be configured to our requirements.&nbsp;</p>
<p>In my projects, I’ve used NLBs for use cases ranging from being the front end for low-latency database requests to hosting an entire backend of an application. NLB helps in all these use cases by giving us a consistent latency, and it holds up its end every time. There are alternatives for NLBs like the AWS Application Load Balancers, but they operate at a higher level of the OSI model and are not always the choice for developers looking for a high-throughput, no-nonsense load balancer.</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://dzone.com/articles/3553836</id>
            <title>Scaling Mobile App Performance: How We Cut Screen Load Time From 8s to 2s</title>
            <link>https://dzone.com/articles/cutting-screen-load-time</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dzone.com/articles/3553836</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 12:00:00 GMT</updated>
                
            <media:thumbnail url="https://dz2cdn1.dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=18368106&amp;w=600"/>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p dir="ltr">User experience is king in the crowd-sourced world of mobile app development, especially in the case of speed. If your app takes too long to load, those same users will bypass your app in favour of a speedy, seamless offering.&nbsp;</p>
<p dir="ltr">When we realized that our app was taking a frustrating 8 seconds to load some screens, this was a hard reality for us to accept. With the competition being fierce and users becoming more and more impatient, we knew something had to change. Read this article as we detail our path from an 8-second screen load time to under 2 seconds, all with a combined multi-sided attack on mobile optimization.</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://dzone.com/articles/3526018</id>
            <title>Debugging Core Dump Files on Linux - A Detailed Guide</title>
            <link>https://dzone.com/articles/debugging-core-dump-files-on-linux-a-detailed-guid</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dzone.com/articles/3526018</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 15:00:12 GMT</updated>
                
            <media:thumbnail url="https://dz2cdn1.dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=18366041&amp;w=600"/>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>Core dumps play a key role in debugging programs that exit abnormally. They preserve the state of a program at failure, and with them, programmers can view and identify the causes of failures.&nbsp;<span style="background-color: transparent;">In this article, a walkthrough is taken through a step-by-step exercise of enabling, creating, and checking out core dumps in Linux, and touches on high-end tools and techniques for&nbsp;</span><a href="https://dzone.com/articles/advanced-linux-troubleshooting-techniques-for-sres" target="_blank">debugging sophisticated failures,</a><span style="background-color: transparent;">&nbsp;enabling quick diagnoses and resolution.</span></p>
<h2><strong>1. Enabling Core Dumps in Linux</strong></h2>
<h3><strong>Check and Set ulimit</strong></h3>
<ol start="1">
 <li>
  <p>Check for current value for core dumps:</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://dzone.com/articles/3551911</id>
            <title>SQL Server Index Optimization Strategies: Best Practices with Ola Hallengren’s Scripts</title>
            <link>https://dzone.com/articles/sql-server-index-optimization-ola-hallengren</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dzone.com/articles/3551911</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 19:00:00 GMT</updated>
                
            <media:thumbnail url="https://dz2cdn1.dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=18361232&amp;w=600"/>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <div dir="ltr">
 <div>
  
   <div tabindex="0">
    <article>
     <p>Index maintenance is a critical component of database administration as it helps ensure the ongoing efficiency and performance of a <a href="https://dzone.com/articles/understanding-sql-server-query-store">Structured Query Language (SQL) Server</a> environment. Over time, as data is added, updated, and deleted, index fragmentation can occur, where the logical and physical ordering of index pages becomes misaligned. This fragmentation can lead to increased disk I/O, decreased query performance, and overall system inefficiency. Running index maintenance jobs, such as those provided by the Ola Hallengren SQL Server Maintenance Solution, allows DBAs to proactively address this fragmentation and optimize the indexes for better performance.</p>
    </article>
   </div>
  
 </div>
</div>
<p>By regularly monitoring index fragmentation levels and executing maintenance operations like index reorganizations and rebuilds, DBAs can keep their databases running at peak efficiency. This is especially important for large, mission-critical databases, where any degradation in performance can have a significant business impact. Maintaining optimal index health helps ensure fast, reliable data access, reduced resource consumption, and an overall improvement in the user experience. Consequently, implementing a well-designed index maintenance strategy is a crucial responsibility for any DBA managing a complex <a href="https://dzone.com/articles/sql-server-from-zero-to-advanced-level">SQL Server</a> environment.</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://dzone.com/articles/3552787</id>
            <title>Analyzing “java.lang.OutOfMemoryError: Failed to create a thread” Error</title>
            <link>https://dzone.com/articles/java-outofmemoryerror-failed-to-create-thread</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dzone.com/articles/3552787</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 15:00:00 GMT</updated>
                
            <media:thumbnail url="https://dz2cdn1.dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=18359945&amp;w=600"/>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <h2><strong>Understanding the Error &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;</strong></h2>
<p>The OutOfMemoryError thrown appears not because of insufficient heap memory but due to the following reasons:</p>
<h3><strong>Excessive Thread Creation</strong></h3>
<p>If the application creates too many threads, it may reach a limit where no more threads can be created. In such cases, it is crucial to investigate the stack trace thrown with the error and reduce the number of thread creations at the application code level.</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://dzone.com/articles/3554952</id>
            <title>Scalability 101: How to Build, Measure, and Improve It</title>
            <link>https://dzone.com/articles/build-measure-improve-scalability</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dzone.com/articles/3554952</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 11:00:00 GMT</updated>
                
            <media:thumbnail url="https://dz2cdn1.dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=18359874&amp;w=600"/>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <p>In this post, I'd like to talk a little about scalability from a system design perspective. In the following paragraphs, I'll cover multiple concepts related to <a href="https://dzone.com/articles/scaling-for-success-why-scalability-is-the-forefro">scalability</a>—from defining what it is, to the tools and approaches that help make the system more scalable, and finally, to the signs that show whether a system is scaling well or not.&nbsp;</p>
<h2 id="-what-is-scalability-"><strong>What Is Scalability?</strong></h2>
<p>First things first: I’m pretty sure you know what scalability is, but let’s have a brief look at the definition just to be safe.</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>