<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <channel>
        <title>GeekWire</title>
        <link>https://www.geekwire.com/</link>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.geekwire.com/2025/geekwire-weekly-roundup-2025-05-11/</id>
            <title>Week in Review: Most popular stories on GeekWire for the week of May 11, 2025</title>
            <link>https://www.geekwire.com/2025/geekwire-weekly-roundup-2025-05-11/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.geekwire.com/2025/geekwire-weekly-roundup-2025-05-11/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 18 May 2025 15:00:07 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <img alt="GeekWire Week in Review" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="630" src="https://cdn.geekwire.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/geekwire-week-in-review1.png" width="1200" /><br />See the technology stories that people were reading on GeekWire for the week of May 11, 2025.&#8230; <a href="https://www.geekwire.com/2025/geekwire-weekly-roundup-2025-05-11/">Read More</a>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.geekwire.com/?p=872608</id>
            <title>Spokane’s aerospace Tech Hub loses $48M federal grant, sparking regional outcry</title>
            <link>https://www.geekwire.com/2025/spokane-aerospace-tech-hub-loses-grant/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.geekwire.com/?p=872608</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sat, 17 May 2025 17:49:42 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <img alt="Proposed AAMMC facility in Spokane" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="709" src="https://cdn.geekwire.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/Facility-AAMMC-1260x709.jpg" width="1260" /><br />Commerce Secretary Howard Lutnick has blocked $48 million in federal funding for an advanced aerospace materials test bed in Spokane, triggering protests from lawmakers. The decision also affects five other Tech Hub projects around the country that were approved for federal support in the final days of the Biden administration. Lutnick had approved a $220 million loan from the Treasury Department as part of a plan to make funding available for the six projects &#8212; but in a statement released Friday, he said he was rescinding the grants. Lutnick said the process was &#8220;rushed, opaque and unfair,&#8221; and added that&#8230; <a href="https://www.geekwire.com/2025/spokane-aerospace-tech-hub-loses-grant/">Read More</a>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.geekwire.com/?p=872599</id>
            <title>GeekWire Podcast: Box CEO Aaron Levie on AI agents, enterprise data, and the future of work</title>
            <link>https://www.geekwire.com/2025/geekwire-podcast-box-ceo-aaron-levie-on-ai-agents-enterprise-data-and-the-future-of-work/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.geekwire.com/?p=872599</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sat, 17 May 2025 15:10:45 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="840" src="https://cdn.geekwire.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/aaron-levie-1260x840.jpg" width="1260" /><br />“I’m just finding more stuff to have the AI do — and then I end up doing more work as a result.” That’s how Box CEO Aaron Levie sums up the paradox of generative AI at work: it saves time, and uncovers infinitely more stuff to take on. On this week’s GeekWire Podcast, we catch up with Levie for our first in-depth conversation since GeekWire Startup Day in 2012. In some ways, it feels like a completely different world — and in others, not much has changed. Levie is still thinking about how technology reshapes work, how startups scale, and&#8230; <a href="https://www.geekwire.com/2025/geekwire-podcast-box-ceo-aaron-levie-on-ai-agents-enterprise-data-and-the-future-of-work/">Read More</a>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.geekwire.com/?p=872456</id>
            <title>Seattle’s Allen Institute launches ‘moonshot’ to create new approach to cell biology research</title>
            <link>https://www.geekwire.com/2025/seattles-allen-institute-launches-moonshot-to-create-new-approach-to-cell-biology-research/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.geekwire.com/?p=872456</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Fri, 16 May 2025 16:18:08 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="894" src="https://cdn.geekwire.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Scene24.png" width="1130" /><br />Human cells, like the people they create, are dynamic and complex. And while researchers can create images and videos of how they move, organize and change their properties, it&#8217;s hard to efficiently and accurately describe all that&#8217;s happening. So a 75-person team at Seattle nonprofit Allen Institute is embarking on a 10-year project called CellScapes to devise a new language using mathematics to capture these essential processes. &#8220;This is a new way of approaching very fundamental cell biology,&#8221; Ru Gunawardane, executive director and vice president of the Allen Institute for Cell Science, told GeekWire. &#8220;We want to combine math and&#8230; <a href="https://www.geekwire.com/2025/seattles-allen-institute-launches-moonshot-to-create-new-approach-to-cell-biology-research/">Read More</a>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.geekwire.com/?p=872474</id>
            <title>Surgical care center startup Oath Surgical comes out of stealth with $10M</title>
            <link>https://www.geekwire.com/2025/surgical-care-center-startup-oath-surgical-comes-out-of-stealth-with-10m/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.geekwire.com/?p=872474</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Fri, 16 May 2025 15:29:10 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="840" src="https://cdn.geekwire.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/oathwest-d47b045f-1260x840.png" width="1260" /><br />Oath Surgical, a new startup out of Portland, Ore., revealed more details about its outpatient surgical care business, touting the service as lower cost and higher quality compared to traditional hospital-based procedures.
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.geekwire.com/?p=871892</id>
            <title>Startup radar: Meet 4 early stage tech companies rising in Seattle</title>
            <link>https://www.geekwire.com/2025/startup-radar-meet-4-early-stage-tech-companies-rising-in-seattle/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.geekwire.com/?p=871892</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Fri, 16 May 2025 14:45:00 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="771" src="https://cdn.geekwire.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Screenshot-2025-05-15-at-11.27.59%E2%80%AFPM.png" width="771" /><br />Detecting theft, helping insurance agencies, improving lab work, and finding nail salons. We&#8217;re covering all the bases with our latest spotlight on early stage startups on the rise in the Seattle area. Read on to learn more about the companies, and check out past startup radar spotlights&#160;here. Email me at taylor@geekwire.com to flag other companies and startup news. Jinn Labs Founded: 2024 The business: Jinn Labs&#8217; uses computer vision tech and other AI-fueled software to help retailers detect theft in real-time. It&#8217;s targeting convenience stores, gas stations, and other retail businesses. The company has raised $775,000 and is working out&#8230; <a href="https://www.geekwire.com/2025/startup-radar-meet-4-early-stage-tech-companies-rising-in-seattle/">Read More</a>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.geekwire.com/?p=872458</id>
            <title>Report: Sustainable aviation startup ZeroAvia aims for $150M to stay airborne through 2028</title>
            <link>https://www.geekwire.com/2025/report-sustainable-aviations-zeroavia-aims-for-150m-round-to-stay-airborne-through-2028/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.geekwire.com/?p=872458</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Fri, 16 May 2025 14:44:21 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="945" src="https://cdn.geekwire.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/ZeroAvia-Q400-nose-1260x945.jpg" width="1260" /><br />ZeroAvia, a sustainable aviation company with R&#38;D and manufacturing operations in Everett, Wash., is trying to quickly raise a $150 million funding round that will keep it aloft through the end of 2028, CEO Val Miftakhov told Bloomberg. Earlier this week, ZeroAvia announced that RVL Aviation will retrofit Cessna Grand Caravan aircraft with the company&#8217;s hydrogen-electric ZA600 powertrain for its cargo operations in the United Kingdom.
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.geekwire.com/?p=872340</id>
            <title>Microsoft: No evidence Israeli military used its technology to harm civilians, reviews find</title>
            <link>https://www.geekwire.com/2025/microsoft-no-evidence-israeli-military-used-its-technology-to-harm-civilians-reviews-find/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.geekwire.com/?p=872340</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Fri, 16 May 2025 00:46:15 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="945" src="https://cdn.geekwire.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/20250404_111450-1260x945.jpg" width="1260" /><br />[Updated below with comments from the employee group No Azure for Apartheid.] Microsoft said Thursday that it found no evidence its technologies were used by the Israeli military to harm civilians in Gaza, following internal and external reviews into allegations that the company was complicit in human rights abuses. The company acknowledged limits as to what it could verify, citing a lack of visibility into how its technology is used on private servers, and systems outside its cloud. The blog post reporting the results of the reviews follows months of protests by Microsoft employees and other tech workers. It comes&#8230; <a href="https://www.geekwire.com/2025/microsoft-no-evidence-israeli-military-used-its-technology-to-harm-civilians-reviews-find/">Read More</a>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.geekwire.com/?p=872282</id>
            <title>Freight company DAT acquires Seattle fintech startup Outgo</title>
            <link>https://www.geekwire.com/2025/freight-company-dat-acquires-seattle-fintech-startup-outgo/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.geekwire.com/?p=872282</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Thu, 15 May 2025 20:44:40 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="714" src="https://cdn.geekwire.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/Outgo_Cofounders_1-1.png" width="1000" /><br />DAT Freight &#38; Analytics, a Beaverton, Ore.-based freight company, announced the acquisition of Outgo, a Seattle startup that sells banking services to freight carriers. Terms of the deal were not disclosed. Outgo raised more than $19 million since launching in 2022. Its finance software helps trucking companies manage invoice processing and payment collection in one place, without requiring annual contracts. Outgo will continue operating out of Seattle as a distinct service within DAT, which operates the largest truckload freight marketplace in North America. Founded in 1978, DAT is a business unit of publicly traded industrial conglomerate Roper Technologies. Outgo is&#8230; <a href="https://www.geekwire.com/2025/freight-company-dat-acquires-seattle-fintech-startup-outgo/">Read More</a>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.geekwire.com/?p=872228</id>
            <title>Tech Moves: Typeface hires CMO; Microsoft adds CVP; WellSaid names new CEO; Expedia’s new CISO</title>
            <link>https://www.geekwire.com/2025/tech-moves-typeface-hires-first-cmo-microsoft-adds-cvp-wellsaid-names-new-ceo/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.geekwire.com/?p=872228</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Thu, 15 May 2025 19:04:16 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="840" src="https://cdn.geekwire.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Ben_Headshot_Final-1260x840.jpg" width="1260" /><br />Benjamin Dorr is the new CEO at Seattle-area AI voice technology startup WellSaid Labs. Dorr, who joined the company last year as CFO, replaces Brian Cook, who was CEO since January 2024. &#8220;We&#8217;re going to continue to work toward AI voice technology that empowers people and protects intellectual property,&#8221; Dorr said on LinkedIn. &#8220;There&#8217;s so much growth ahead.&#8221; Dorr previously was COO at enterprise marketing company Cordial. Originally spun out of Seattle’s AI2 Incubator, WellSaid&#160;raised&#160;a $10 million Series A round in 2021. The company focuses on the enterprise AI voice market. —&#160;Jennifer Weitzel joined Microsoft as corporate vice president of&#8230; <a href="https://www.geekwire.com/2025/tech-moves-typeface-hires-first-cmo-microsoft-adds-cvp-wellsaid-names-new-ceo/">Read More</a>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.geekwire.com/?p=872203</id>
            <title>Seahawks unbox action-packed schedule release video as NFL teams vie for social media supremacy</title>
            <link>https://www.geekwire.com/2025/seahawks-unbox-action-packed-schedule-release-video-as-nfl-teams-vie-for-social-media-supremacy/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.geekwire.com/?p=872203</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Thu, 15 May 2025 16:22:43 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="688" src="https://cdn.geekwire.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/hawkssked.png" width="937" /><br />It&#8217;s not enough anymore for NFL teams to simply release a schedule of who they&#8217;ll be playing in the upcoming season — the hype has been turned way up, and schedule release video production is a serious social media affair in 2025. The Seattle Seahawks are among the teams getting in on the fun, with a schedule &#8220;unboxing&#8221; video that plays off vintage toy action figure commercials. Current Seahawks star cornerback Devon Witherspoon is the star of the video, but he&#8217;s joined by &#8220;an all-pro squad of action-packed legends,&#8221; including Seahawks greats Steve Largent, Walter Jones, Kam Chancellor and Marshawn&#8230; <a href="https://www.geekwire.com/2025/seahawks-unbox-action-packed-schedule-release-video-as-nfl-teams-vie-for-social-media-supremacy/">Read More</a>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.geekwire.com/?p=872170</id>
            <title>Seattle-area company VerAvanti lands $31.5M to develop scopes to prevent strokes, heart attacks</title>
            <link>https://www.geekwire.com/2025/seattle-area-company-veravanti-lands-31-5m-to-develop-scopes-to-prevent-strokes-heart-attacks/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.geekwire.com/?p=872170</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Thu, 15 May 2025 16:14:36 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="490" src="https://cdn.geekwire.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/unnamed1.jpg" width="653" /><br />Medical technology company VerAvanti announced $31.5 million in funding to advance its work on ultra-thin imaging scopes that can be used in the prevention of strokes and heart attacks. The Bothell, Wash.-based business also shared that it has signed a lease on a manufacturing facility near its headquarters. The company has raised $40 million, including today&#8217;s Series A round, from friends, family and other &#8220;high-net worth individuals,&#8221; according to a spokesperson. It has not taken any venture capital funding. The investment allows the business &#8220;to move from ‘research’ into ‘development and manufacturing’ mode,&#8221; said CEO Gerald McMorrow, in statement. The&#8230; <a href="https://www.geekwire.com/2025/seattle-area-company-veravanti-lands-31-5m-to-develop-scopes-to-prevent-strokes-heart-attacks/">Read More</a>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.geekwire.com/?p=871466</id>
            <title>Bill Gates’ pledge to give 99% of wealth to global health foundation could leave climate in the cold</title>
            <link>https://www.geekwire.com/2025/bill-gates-pledge-to-give-99-of-wealth-to-global-health-foundation-could-leave-climate-in-the-cold/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.geekwire.com/?p=871466</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Thu, 15 May 2025 15:16:36 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="945" src="https://cdn.geekwire.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Bill-Gates-BE-edit.jpg" width="1260" /><br />Bill Gates&#8217; announcement last week that he would give 99% of his wealth to the Gates Foundation was a shot in the arm to the philanthropy&#8217;s focal areas of global health, educational access and agriculture. But to some proponents of climate action, it felt like a slap in the face. For the past decade, the Microsoft co-founder has been publicly championing climate issues. He published the book “How to Avoid a Climate Disaster.” He led the creation of Breakthrough Energy Ventures, a climate tech investment fund that coalesced support from ultra-wealthy investors worldwide. That effort grew into the Seattle-based Breakthrough&#8230; <a href="https://www.geekwire.com/2025/bill-gates-pledge-to-give-99-of-wealth-to-global-health-foundation-could-leave-climate-in-the-cold/">Read More</a>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.geekwire.com/?p=872172</id>
            <title>Box tightens Microsoft ties with new Copilot integration, builds out its own suite of AI agents</title>
            <link>https://www.geekwire.com/2025/box-tightens-microsoft-ties-with-new-copilot-integration-builds-out-its-own-suite-of-ai-agents/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.geekwire.com/?p=872172</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Thu, 15 May 2025 15:10:07 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1229" src="https://cdn.geekwire.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/aaron-levie.jpeg" width="1246" /><br />Box is deepening its connection to Microsoft’s productivity platform through a new AI agent that works with Microsoft 365 Copilot, while introducing new AI agents of its own to analyze documents, automate tasks, and dig up insights from enterprise data.&#160; The new technologies, announced Thursday morning, build on the Redwood City, Calif., company’s longtime role as a hub for secure file storage and collaboration, while continuing its push into what Box describes as intelligent content management.  Microsoft 365 Copilot is Microsoft’s AI assistant for business, integrated with its widely used productivity apps. The new Box AI agent will let users&#8230; <a href="https://www.geekwire.com/2025/box-tightens-microsoft-ties-with-new-copilot-integration-builds-out-its-own-suite-of-ai-agents/">Read More</a>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.geekwire.com/?p=871819</id>
            <title>Irrigation tech startup Verdi raises $4.7M to help farmers monitor and control water flow</title>
            <link>https://www.geekwire.com/2025/b-c-startup-verdi-secures-4-7m-for-irrigation-technology-amidst-ag-tech-funding-slowdown/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.geekwire.com/?p=871819</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Thu, 15 May 2025 12:00:00 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="625" src="https://cdn.geekwire.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/verdi_customer_vineyard_installation.jpg" width="833" /><br />Agriculture tech startup Verdi raised a $4.7 million seed round to expand its technology for smarter irrigation of crops including wine grapes, berries, nuts, tree fruits, vegetables and other produce. The Vancouver, B.C., company is building devices that integrate with existing irrigation systems, allowing farmers to monitor watering and remotely control valves to turn the flow of water off and on. “We’re adding a layer of intelligence to what is already there,” said Verdi co-founder and CEO Arthur Chen. Chen and CTO Roman Kozak met as engineering students at the University of British Columbia. Both came from families who had&#8230; <a href="https://www.geekwire.com/2025/b-c-startup-verdi-secures-4-7m-for-irrigation-technology-amidst-ag-tech-funding-slowdown/">Read More</a>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.geekwire.com/?p=872091</id>
            <title>Amazon lays off 100 in Devices &amp; Services group amid ongoing tech industry cuts</title>
            <link>https://www.geekwire.com/2025/amazon-lays-off-100-in-devices-services-group-amid-ongoing-tech-industry-cuts/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.geekwire.com/?p=872091</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Thu, 15 May 2025 03:13:54 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="945" src="https://cdn.geekwire.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/amazon-sign-1260x945.jpg" width="1260" /><br />Amazon is cutting about 100 jobs in its Devices &#38; Services division, the part of the company that includes its Alexa voice assistant, Echo smart speakers, Zoox robo-taxis and Project Kuiper satellite internet venture. It&#8217;s part of a broader industry trend of reducing headcount in the name of efficiency, although the size is much smaller than recent cuts at some of Amazon&#8217;s peers.&#160; The company says it&#8217;s still hiring in Devices &#38; Services, with hundreds of open roles. “As part of our ongoing work to make our teams and programs operate more efficiently, and to better align with our product&#8230; <a href="https://www.geekwire.com/2025/amazon-lays-off-100-in-devices-services-group-amid-ongoing-tech-industry-cuts/">Read More</a>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.geekwire.com/?p=872006</id>
            <title>Exclusive: Former Apple leaders raise $16M for stealthy Seattle startup building AI inference tech</title>
            <link>https://www.geekwire.com/2025/exclusive-former-apple-leaders-raise-16m-for-stealthy-seattle-startup-building-ai-inference-tech/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.geekwire.com/?p=872006</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Wed, 14 May 2025 22:20:54 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="623" src="https://cdn.geekwire.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Screenshot-2025-05-14-at-2.02.47%E2%80%AFPM-1260x623.png" width="1260" /><br />A new Seattle startup led by veteran engineers is building technology to tackle one of the biggest drivers of cost and complexity in large language model deployment. Founded just a few months ago, ElastixAI is developing an AI inference platform designed to optimize how large language models are run. The company just raised $16 million of a larger round led by Bellevue-based venture capital firm FUSE, GeekWire has learned. As AI demand skyrockets, inference — how trained large language models &#8220;think&#8221; and produce answers — is one of the hottest areas of AI infrastructure. ElastixAI is aiming to improve the&#8230; <a href="https://www.geekwire.com/2025/exclusive-former-apple-leaders-raise-16m-for-stealthy-seattle-startup-building-ai-inference-tech/">Read More</a>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.geekwire.com/?p=872003</id>
            <title>Zeno Power raises $50M in funding to fuel  development of next-gen nuclear batteries</title>
            <link>https://www.geekwire.com/2025/zeno-power-50m-nuclear-batteries/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.geekwire.com/?p=872003</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Wed, 14 May 2025 20:22:50 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <img alt="Illustration: Lunar rover powered by nuclear battery" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="737" src="https://cdn.geekwire.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/250514-zeno2-1260x737.jpg" width="1260" /><br />Zeno Power, a startup that&#8217;s headquartered in Seattle as well as Washington, D.C., today announced the completion of a $50 million funding round to boost the development of nuclear batteries for maritime and space applications. The Series B round was led by Hanaco Ventures, with participation from Seraphim, Balerion Space Ventures, JAWS, Vanderbilt University, RiverPark Ventures, Stage 1 Ventures, 7i Capital, Beyond Earth Ventures and others. The fresh funding follows a $20 million Series A round in 2022 and brings total investment to $70 million. Zeno got its start at Vanderbilt in 2018 with the goal of creating new types&#8230; <a href="https://www.geekwire.com/2025/zeno-power-50m-nuclear-batteries/">Read More</a>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.geekwire.com/?p=871980</id>
            <title>HashiCorp co-founder donates $3M to alma mater, University of Washington computer science school</title>
            <link>https://www.geekwire.com/2025/hashicorp-co-founder-donates-3m-to-alma-mater-university-of-washington-computer-science-school/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.geekwire.com/?p=871980</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Wed, 14 May 2025 17:58:00 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="650" src="https://cdn.geekwire.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/dadgar-kalla-hero-cropped.jpg" width="867" /><br />Armon Dadgar, co-founder of HashiCorp and a University of Washington graduate, and his partner, Joshua Kalla, are giving $3 million to the UW&#8217;s Paul G. Allen School of Computer Science &#38; Engineering. Dadgar launched HashiCorp in 2012 with co-founder Mitchell Hashimoto, shortly after the two graduated from the UW with computer science degrees. The San Francisco-based HashiCorp reached unicorn status in 2018 with a $1.9 billion valuation. In February, IBM acquired the cloud company for $6.4 billion. Dadgar and Kalla, who live in Seattle, are directing their gift to two efforts: “Education has always been an incredible driver of economic&#8230; <a href="https://www.geekwire.com/2025/hashicorp-co-founder-donates-3m-to-alma-mater-university-of-washington-computer-science-school/">Read More</a>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.geekwire.com/?p=871929</id>
            <title>‘Cruel optimism’: Mass layoffs take the shine off careers in the tech sector, UW research finds</title>
            <link>https://www.geekwire.com/2025/cruel-optimism-mass-layoffs-take-the-shine-off-careers-in-the-tech-sector-uw-research-finds/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.geekwire.com/?p=871929</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Wed, 14 May 2025 16:48:05 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="945" src="https://cdn.geekwire.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/50848797993_36cfebd652_k-1260x945.jpg" width="1260" /><br />Jobs in tech have been revered as well-paid, exciting, secure roles benefiting the greater good. But with 500,000 tech layoffs since 2022 &#8212; including 6,000 employees let go this week from Microsoft &#8212; and increasing worries about the societal impacts of artificial intelligence, that rosy outlook is dimming among technology employees. That&#8217;s the conclusion of new research from the University of Washington, based on a five-week study with 29 current or former tech workers who were laid off during a year-long stretch starting in November 2022. The paper, titled &#8220;The Cruel Optimism of Tech Work: Tech Workers&#8217; Affective Attachments in&#8230; <a href="https://www.geekwire.com/2025/cruel-optimism-mass-layoffs-take-the-shine-off-careers-in-the-tech-sector-uw-research-finds/">Read More</a>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.geekwire.com/?p=871953</id>
            <title>Amazon vets land $4M for Seattle data security startup Tensor9</title>
            <link>https://www.geekwire.com/2025/amazon-vets-land-4m-for-seattle-data-security-startup-tensor9/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.geekwire.com/?p=871953</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Wed, 14 May 2025 16:28:41 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="890" src="https://cdn.geekwire.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Screenshot-2025-05-14-at-9.13.43%E2%80%AFAM.png" width="1198" /><br />Tensor9, a Seattle-based security and privacy startup, announced a $4 million seed round. Founded in 2023 by veterans of Amazon, Meta, and Epic Games, the company helps software vendors deploy applications directly within customer cloud environments. The idea is to &#8220;unlock&#8221; customers that deal with sensitive data and strict security policies. &#8220;Public cloud enables simplicity, scalability, and efficiency, but also introduces security issues and data movement costs,&#8221; Tensor9 CEO Michael Ten-Pow wrote in a blog post. &#8220;There is a clear trend towards a more hybrid model, where software runs where it needs to in the right environment. And that’s the&#8230; <a href="https://www.geekwire.com/2025/amazon-vets-land-4m-for-seattle-data-security-startup-tensor9/">Read More</a>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.geekwire.com/?p=871894</id>
            <title>MacKenzie Scott, Jeff Bezos, and other billionaires who could buy the Blazers</title>
            <link>https://www.geekwire.com/2025/mackenzie-scott-jeff-bezos-and-2-other-billionaires-that-could-buy-the-blazers/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.geekwire.com/?p=871894</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Wed, 14 May 2025 15:31:18 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="691" src="https://cdn.geekwire.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Screenshot-2025-05-13-at-11.36.21%E2%80%AFPM-e1747236721879.png" width="843" /><br />No way. Bonkers. A real stretch. That&#8217;s the response I got in our Slack thread after floating MacKenzie Scott as a potential buyer of the Portland Trail Blazers. The NBA franchise is up for sale. The estate of late Microsoft co-founder Paul Allen made the announcement Tuesday, following a directive from Allen, who bought the team for $70 million in 1988. The buyer will need some serious dough. The Boston Celtics are being sold for a reported $6.1 billion. The average NBA team valuation is around $4.6 billion. Scott, the billionaire Seattle philanthropist, could afford it. Sure, she doesn&#8217;t appear&#8230; <a href="https://www.geekwire.com/2025/mackenzie-scott-jeff-bezos-and-2-other-billionaires-that-could-buy-the-blazers/">Read More</a>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.geekwire.com/?p=871840</id>
            <title>B.C. climate tech startup veritree raises $6.5M and lines up pledges to plant 100 million trees globally</title>
            <link>https://www.geekwire.com/2025/b-c-climate-tech-startup-veritree-raises-6-5m-and-lines-up-pledges-to-plant-100-million-trees-globally/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.geekwire.com/?p=871840</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Wed, 14 May 2025 00:27:59 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="840" src="https://cdn.geekwire.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Mangrove-nursery-veritree-1260x840.jpg" width="1260" /><br />Veritree, a Vancouver, B.C.-based climate tech startup supporting reforestation, announced $6.5 million in new funding on Tuesday. The company also hit a milestone of lining up commitments to fund the planting of 100 million trees worldwide within five years. The startup&#8217;s projects are being done at sites including areas damaged by wildfires, mangroves and terrestrial forests, marine kelp beds, and agroforestry initiatives that include crop production. Current planting projects are underway with locally-based partners in Canada, Haiti, Senegal, Kenya, Brazil, the United Kingdom and multiple U.S. states. Veritree uses blockchain technology to provide a public ledger documenting tree planting and&#8230; <a href="https://www.geekwire.com/2025/b-c-climate-tech-startup-veritree-raises-6-5m-and-lines-up-pledges-to-plant-100-million-trees-globally/">Read More</a>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.geekwire.com/?p=871801</id>
            <title>Microsoft will cut nearly 2,000 jobs in Washington state as part of broader layoffs</title>
            <link>https://www.geekwire.com/2025/microsoft-will-cut-nearly-2000-jobs-in-washington-state-as-part-of-broader-layoffs/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.geekwire.com/?p=871801</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Tue, 13 May 2025 19:14:00 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="945" src="https://cdn.geekwire.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/microsoft-logo-night-1260x945.jpg" width="1260" /><br />Microsoft will lay off 1,985 workers in Washington state effective July 12, part of its broader global workforce reduction announced Tuesday, according to a new filing with the state Employment Security Department. The total includes 1,510 employees based in Microsoft offices and 475 remote workers, the WARN (Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification) filing shows. The company employed around 54,000 people in the Seattle region as of last month. It marks the most significant round of layoffs for Microsoft in its home state since 2023, when the company cut nearly 3,200 jobs across multiple rounds amid a broader wave of tech&#8230; <a href="https://www.geekwire.com/2025/microsoft-will-cut-nearly-2000-jobs-in-washington-state-as-part-of-broader-layoffs/">Read More</a>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.geekwire.com/?p=871763</id>
            <title>Who will buy the Blazers? Microsoft co-founder Paul Allen’s estate plans to sell NBA franchise</title>
            <link>https://www.geekwire.com/2025/who-will-buy-the-blazers-microsoft-co-founder-paul-allens-estate-plans-to-sell-nba-franchise/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.geekwire.com/?p=871763</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Tue, 13 May 2025 17:51:59 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="741" src="https://cdn.geekwire.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/moda-blazers-1260x741.png" width="1260" /><br />The estate of late Microsoft co-founder Paul Allen announced Tuesday morning that it has begun the process of selling the NBA’s Portland Trail Blazers, which would be a major milestone in fulfilling Allen’s directive to sell his sports holdings and direct the proceeds to philanthropy. Allen’s estate said the announcement does not impact its ownership of the Seattle Seahawks NFL franchise, or its 25% stake in the Seattle Sounders MLS team, which are not for sale.&#160; Who will buy the franchise? The news will no doubt spark months of speculation — and plenty of tech leaders with Seattle or Pacific&#8230; <a href="https://www.geekwire.com/2025/who-will-buy-the-blazers-microsoft-co-founder-paul-allens-estate-plans-to-sell-nba-franchise/">Read More</a>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.geekwire.com/?p=871709</id>
            <title>Seattle-area company lands FDA clearance for drug-free treatment to address teen anxiety and trauma</title>
            <link>https://www.geekwire.com/2025/seattle-area-company-lands-fda-approval-for-drug-free-treatment-to-address-teen-anxiety/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.geekwire.com/?p=871709</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Tue, 13 May 2025 17:48:56 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="945" src="https://cdn.geekwire.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/freespira_stills_09-21-1260x945.jpg" width="1260" /><br />Teens suffering from anxiety, panic attacks and trauma have a new, drug-free option for addressing their mental health. The Seattle-area company Freespira announced that it received U.S. Food and Drug Administration clearance for treating adolescents ages 13-17 with a technology that provides breathing training and video-based coaching. Youth mental health remains an urgent issue. More than one-in-five teens surveyed said they felt anxious in the past two weeks, according to U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention research in recent years. And 48% of U.S. high school students surveyed said that anxiety, stress or depression impeded their learning, according to&#8230; <a href="https://www.geekwire.com/2025/seattle-area-company-lands-fda-approval-for-drug-free-treatment-to-address-teen-anxiety/">Read More</a>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.geekwire.com/?p=871631</id>
            <title>AI startup led by UW computer science whiz enables ‘superhuman hearing capabilities’</title>
            <link>https://www.geekwire.com/2025/ai-startup-led-by-uw-computer-science-whiz-enables-superhuman-hearing-capabilities/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.geekwire.com/?p=871631</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Tue, 13 May 2025 16:35:00 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="800" src="https://cdn.geekwire.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/shyam-gollakota-1.jpg" width="650" /><br />A new stealthy Seattle startup is taking sound technology to a whole new dimension. Hearvana was just founded by University of Washington computer science researchers. Shyam Gollakota, co-founder of Hearvana, told GeekWire that the company is &#8220;creating AI breakthroughs that are&#160;shaping the future of sound.&#8221; &#8220;Our AI algorithms enable on-device superhuman hearing capabilities and will be part of billions of earbuds, hearing aids and smartphones,&#8221; he said. &#8220;It is an exciting time.&#8221; Gollakota, a renowned tech inventor and researcher, said the company wants to help people seamlessly choose what they want to hear in real-time. It&#8217;s taking on a big&#8230; <a href="https://www.geekwire.com/2025/ai-startup-led-by-uw-computer-science-whiz-enables-superhuman-hearing-capabilities/">Read More</a>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.geekwire.com/?p=871570</id>
            <title>Seattle studio led by Big Fish founder raises more cash for mobile battler ‘Mutant Forge’</title>
            <link>https://www.geekwire.com/2025/seattle-studio-reflection-games-raises-more-cash-for-mobile-battler-mutant-forge/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.geekwire.com/?p=871570</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Tue, 13 May 2025 16:31:21 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="204" src="https://cdn.geekwire.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Screenshot-2025-05-12-at-3.24.14%E2%80%AFPM.png" width="209" /><br />Reflection Games, an independent studio founded in 2021 by several veterans of Seattle’s Big Fish Games, is raising more cash. A new SEC filing reveals that the company raised $1.1 million in a new investment. We reached out to Reflection for more details. The company&#8217;s debut project is Mutant Forge, a free-to-play “strategy battler,” soft-launched out of beta in September for iOS and Android. Reflection’s CEO, Paul Thelen, is the founder and former chairman at Big Fish Games, which was acquired in 2014 by Churchill Downs Inc. Other Big Fish veterans at Reflection include chief operating officer Patrick Wylie, senior&#8230; <a href="https://www.geekwire.com/2025/seattle-studio-reflection-games-raises-more-cash-for-mobile-battler-mutant-forge/">Read More</a>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.geekwire.com/?p=871675</id>
            <title>Microsoft cuts nearly 3% of global workforce, about 6,000 jobs, in latest push for efficiency</title>
            <link>https://www.geekwire.com/2025/microsoft-cuts-nearly-3-of-global-workforce-about-6000-jobs-in-latest-push-for-efficiency/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.geekwire.com/?p=871675</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Tue, 13 May 2025 14:31:07 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="945" src="https://cdn.geekwire.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/microsoft-logo-1260x945.jpg" width="1260" /><br />Microsoft began issuing layoff notices to thousands of employees Tuesday morning, two weeks after hinting at plans to streamline its workforce by cutting layers of management and making teams more agile. Fewer than 3% of Microsoft’s global workforce is expected to be impacted. That would equate to roughly 6,000 people, based on the company’s most recent employee count of 228,000 as of June 2024, also taking into account performance-based job cuts by the company earlier this year. The company did not say whether efficiencies from artificial intelligence are playing a role in the latest reductions. “We continue to implement organizational&#8230; <a href="https://www.geekwire.com/2025/microsoft-cuts-nearly-3-of-global-workforce-about-6000-jobs-in-latest-push-for-efficiency/">Read More</a>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.geekwire.com/?p=871537</id>
            <title>Battery company OneD reportedly closes Washington manufacturing site, citing tariff impacts</title>
            <link>https://www.geekwire.com/2025/next-gen-battery-company-oned-shutters-pilot-manufacturing-site-in-wash-citing-tariff-impacts/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.geekwire.com/?p=871537</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Mon, 12 May 2025 22:06:24 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="650" src="https://cdn.geekwire.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/SINANODE-Pilot-Bldgs-1260x650.png" width="1260" /><br />OneD Battery Sciences has shut down its pilot manufacturing facility in the Eastern Washington town of Moses Lake, according to The Information. Former OneD employees are also sharing &#8220;open to work&#8221; posts on LinkedIn. Just nine months ago, the California battery company announced it had successfully completed and commissioned the site, which was producing SINANODE, a silicon anode product for next gen batteries. &#8220;This milestone marks an important step forward in scaling up the production of OneD&#8217;s SINANODE materials for the global battery market,&#8221; the company proclaimed in August 2024. OneD invested somewhere between $15 million and $20 million in&#8230; <a href="https://www.geekwire.com/2025/next-gen-battery-company-oned-shutters-pilot-manufacturing-site-in-wash-citing-tariff-impacts/">Read More</a>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.geekwire.com/?p=871490</id>
            <title>‘We lit a fire’: Spencer Rascoff’s Match Group overhaul reflects broader tech reckoning</title>
            <link>https://www.geekwire.com/2025/we-lit-a-fire-spencer-rascoffs-match-group-overhaul-reflects-broader-tech-reckoning/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.geekwire.com/?p=871490</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Mon, 12 May 2025 17:04:32 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="840" src="https://cdn.geekwire.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/20211004_GeekWire_Summit_414-2-1260x840.jpg" width="1260" /><br />A familiar name pops up at the end of a Wall Street Journal article today about the new balance of power between tech companies and workers in the age of artificial intelligence: Spencer Rascoff. The former CEO of Seattle-based Zillow Group now leads Match Group, the parent company of Tinder, Hinge, and OkCupid. Last week, he announced plans to cut 13% of the workforce — 325 jobs — while touting a leaner structure, faster product cycles, and a growing role for AI in the dating experience. Rascoff’s comments to investors about the cuts will sound familiar to anyone tracking Andy&#8230; <a href="https://www.geekwire.com/2025/we-lit-a-fire-spencer-rascoffs-match-group-overhaul-reflects-broader-tech-reckoning/">Read More</a>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.geekwire.com/?p=871458</id>
            <title>Bezos shifts from passive owner to active shaper at Washington Post amid its ‘identity crisis’</title>
            <link>https://www.geekwire.com/2025/bezos-shifts-from-passive-owner-to-active-shaper-at-washington-post-amid-its-identity-crisis/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.geekwire.com/?p=871458</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Mon, 12 May 2025 16:08:25 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="664" src="https://cdn.geekwire.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/bezos-climate.png" width="1072" /><br />A detailed report from The New Yorker reveals how Jeff Bezos has evolved since buying the The Washington Post — which is going through an &#8220;identity crisis&#8221; as the Amazon founder gets more involved with the storied newspaper. The article details the cultural, editorial, and strategic upheaval at the Post under the ownership of Bezos, who bought the paper for $250 million in 2013. The billionaire&#8217;s recent leadership appointments, including tapping Will Lewis as publisher, has caused newsroom unrest. Dozens of staffers — including Pulitzer Prize winners — have since left the Post. Bezos was initially a distant but supportive&#8230; <a href="https://www.geekwire.com/2025/bezos-shifts-from-passive-owner-to-active-shaper-at-washington-post-amid-its-identity-crisis/">Read More</a>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.geekwire.com/?p=870648</id>
            <title>Appetite for invention: Seattle tech vets hatch a simple gadget to cook a tastier chicken</title>
            <link>https://www.geekwire.com/2025/appetite-for-invention-seattle-tech-vets-hatch-a-simple-gadget-to-cook-a-tastier-chicken/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.geekwire.com/?p=870648</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Mon, 12 May 2025 15:00:00 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="903" src="https://cdn.geekwire.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/poultree1-1260x903.jpeg" width="1260" /><br />Not satisfied with what they considered overly complicated methods for cooking unsatisfactory chicken, Dave Atchison and Tony Smith jumped out of the frying pan and into the startup fire. The two tech veterans and longtime friends —&#160;experienced in Seattle&#8217;s e-commerce and high-tech cooking scenes — are the co-founders of PoulTree, an idea so simple it should make your mouth water, whether you&#8217;re an inventor at heart or you just love the taste of a perfectly roasted bird. PoulTree is a precisely bent rod made from 3/8-inch marine-grade stainless steel. It&#8217;s designed to fit into the hole in the handle of&#8230; <a href="https://www.geekwire.com/2025/appetite-for-invention-seattle-tech-vets-hatch-a-simple-gadget-to-cook-a-tastier-chicken/">Read More</a>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.geekwire.com/?p=871392</id>
            <title>OpenAI and Microsoft reportedly renegotiating partnership to allow for potential IPO</title>
            <link>https://www.geekwire.com/2025/openai-and-microsoft-reportedly-renegotiating-partnership-to-allow-for-potential-ipo/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.geekwire.com/?p=871392</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 11 May 2025 17:28:53 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="846" src="https://cdn.geekwire.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/nadella-altman-4b-1260x846.jpg" width="1260" /><br />The news: OpenAI and Microsoft are reworking the terms of their multibillion-dollar partnership, according to a report from the Financial Times. Background: OpenAI announced last week that it is moving forward with a restructuring plan to create a for-profit public benefit corporation, controlled by its nonprofit parent. OpenAI needs sign-off from Microsoft — which has invested more than $13 billion in the ChatGPT maker since 2019 — to proceed with the plan. What&#8217;s new: The Financial Times reported that Microsoft could take a smaller equity stake in the new entity in exchange for extended access to OpenAI&#8217;s technology beyond the&#8230; <a href="https://www.geekwire.com/2025/openai-and-microsoft-reportedly-renegotiating-partnership-to-allow-for-potential-ipo/">Read More</a>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://www.geekwire.com/2025/geekwire-weekly-roundup-2025-05-04/</id>
            <title>Week in Review: Most popular stories on GeekWire for the week of May 4, 2025</title>
            <link>https://www.geekwire.com/2025/geekwire-weekly-roundup-2025-05-04/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.geekwire.com/2025/geekwire-weekly-roundup-2025-05-04/</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 11 May 2025 15:00:07 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <img alt="GeekWire Week in Review" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="630" src="https://cdn.geekwire.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/geekwire-week-in-review1.png" width="1200" /><br />See the technology stories that people were reading on GeekWire for the week of May 4, 2025.&#8230; <a href="https://www.geekwire.com/2025/geekwire-weekly-roundup-2025-05-04/">Read More</a>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>