<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <channel>
        <title>The Next Web</title>
        <link>https://thenextweb.com</link>
        
        <item>
            <id>TheNextWeb=1413666</id>
            <title>Exclusive: Swiss startup picks Rotterdam for green aviation fuel plant</title>
            <link>https://thenextweb.com/news/metafuels-swiss-startup-rotterdam-green-aviation-fuel-plant</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">TheNextWeb=1413666</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Fri, 16 May 2025 07:00:11 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <img height="417" src="https://img-cdn.tnwcdn.com/image?fit=796%2C417&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fcdn0.tnwcdn.com%2Fwp-content%2Fblogs.dir%2F1%2Ffiles%2F2025%2F05%2Fsustainable-aviation-fuel-metafuels.jpg&amp;signature=81766868cc33bdafa66acd6252f9b2d0" width="796" /><br />Swiss tech startup Metafuels has unveiled plans to open its first commercial-scale sustainable aviation fuel (SAF) plant in the Port of Rotterdam.  Metafuels’ CEO Saurabh Kapoor told TNW that Turbe represents a “major step forward” toward ramping up SAF production. The startup also announced plans to build a similar facility in Denmark last year. “Europe has ambitious decarbonisation targets, but without scalable and affordable SAF production, aviation will struggle to keep up,” said Kapoor.  The facility, dubbed Turbe, will be built in collaboration with liquid energy storage provider Evos. Turbe will be integrated into Evos’ existing Rotterdam terminal, which offers&#8230;<br /><br /><a href="https://thenextweb.com/news/metafuels-swiss-startup-rotterdam-green-aviation-fuel-plant?utm_source=social&#038;utm_medium=feed&#038;utm_campaign=profeed">This story continues</a> at The Next Web
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>TheNextWeb=1413676</id>
            <title>Gaming billionaire named UK’s richest person under 40 in tech-heavy wealth list</title>
            <link>https://thenextweb.com/news/gaming-billionaire-named-uk-richest-person-under-40</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">TheNextWeb=1413676</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Fri, 16 May 2025 05:30:34 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <img height="417" src="https://img-cdn.tnwcdn.com/image?fit=796%2C417&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fcdn0.tnwcdn.com%2Fwp-content%2Fblogs.dir%2F1%2Ffiles%2F2025%2F05%2FUntitled-design-44.jpg&amp;signature=9b8e61c8892763d2fe5f88ef2d9b6ac5" width="796" /><br />A Russian-born gaming mogul has been named the UK’s richest person under 40 — in a ranking dominated by tech entrepreneurs. Dmitry Bukhman, 39, built his fortune after founding mobile gaming giant Playrix. His estimated wealth of £12.54bn tops The Sunday Times 40 Under 40 Rich List — and makes up over a third of its £36.2bn combined total. His net worth has nearly doubled since last year. As a child in post-Soviet Russia, Bukman taught himself to code. Alongside his older brother Igor, he built his first game with an old Pentium PC given to them by their grandfather.&#8230;<br /><br /><a href="https://thenextweb.com/news/gaming-billionaire-named-uk-richest-person-under-40?utm_source=social&#038;utm_medium=feed&#038;utm_campaign=profeed">This story continues</a> at The Next Web
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>TheNextWeb=1413663</id>
            <title>Bunq CEO warns closed minds are pushing Dutch entrepreneurs away</title>
            <link>https://thenextweb.com/news/bunq-ceo-ali-niknam-warns-dutch-entrepreneurs-leaving</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">TheNextWeb=1413663</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Thu, 15 May 2025 15:37:46 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <img height="417" src="https://img-cdn.tnwcdn.com/image?fit=796%2C417&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fcdn0.tnwcdn.com%2Fwp-content%2Fblogs.dir%2F1%2Ffiles%2F2023%2F12%2F448077-Ali_BU21-6836b8-original-1666105179-e1702991112445.jpeg&amp;signature=26e50dbf23a1b6f26d958e71ccba649e" width="796" /><br />Ali Niknam has built Dutch fintech Bunq into one of Europe’s biggest neobanks. But he fears the Netherlands is now driving entrepreneurs away. The Bunq founder and CEO is alarmed by the country’s business mindset. He believes risk-aversion, growing insularity, and hostility to ambition are pushing talent overseas. “Many of the best entrepreneurs I know have either left or are considering leaving,” Niknam tells TNW. Surveys back him up. A poll last year found that almost one in five Dutch entrepreneurs were considering relocating — up from nearly one in eight in 2023. Another study found that 24% of large&#8230;<br /><br /><a href="https://thenextweb.com/news/bunq-ceo-ali-niknam-warns-dutch-entrepreneurs-leaving?utm_source=social&#038;utm_medium=feed&#038;utm_campaign=profeed">This story continues</a> at The Next Web
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>TheNextWeb=1413647</id>
            <title>Nuclear waste could power Europe for decades. This startup plans to prove it</title>
            <link>https://thenextweb.com/news/nuclear-waste-thorizon-power-europe-for-decades-startup</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">TheNextWeb=1413647</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Thu, 15 May 2025 15:24:29 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <img height="417" src="https://img-cdn.tnwcdn.com/image?fit=796%2C417&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fcdn0.tnwcdn.com%2Fwp-content%2Fblogs.dir%2F1%2Ffiles%2F2019%2F04%2FRadioactive-Waste.jpg&amp;signature=d447a26d757dcf38ca70eedd63698d0c" width="796" /><br />Europe has been turning uranium into energy for over half a century. In the process, the continent has amassed vast stockpiles of nuclear waste. This radioactive material can take millions of years to become safe, and no one really knows what to do with it. Thorizon, a Franco-Dutch startup, has an idea: reuse the nuclear waste to generate new energy. The company is developing a small modular molten salt reactor (MSR) that runs on a mix of spent nuclear fuel and thorium, a radioactive metal with untapped potential.  Thorizon aims to begin construction of its first reactor, Thorizon One, within&#8230;<br /><br /><a href="https://thenextweb.com/news/nuclear-waste-thorizon-power-europe-for-decades-startup?utm_source=social&#038;utm_medium=feed&#038;utm_campaign=profeed">This story continues</a> at The Next Web
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>TheNextWeb=1413643</id>
            <title>Europe must ‘get real’ on tech sovereignty and stay open, warns industry group</title>
            <link>https://thenextweb.com/news/europe-must-get-real-on-tech-sovereignty-and-stay-open-warns-industry-group</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">TheNextWeb=1413643</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Wed, 14 May 2025 16:32:48 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <img height="417" src="https://img-cdn.tnwcdn.com/image?fit=796%2C417&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fcdn0.tnwcdn.com%2Fwp-content%2Fblogs.dir%2F1%2Ffiles%2F2023%2F09%2FUntitled-design-1-2.jpg&amp;signature=69913cdebe8fe550edb6f738ee58115a" width="796" /><br />As Europe pushes for tech sovereignty, one open-source advocate has a warning: don’t forget global cooperation. Amanda Brock, CEO of industry group OpenUK, told TNW that the EU must “get real” about the trade-offs of going it alone. Brock said tech policymakers must move beyond “tit-for-tat schoolyard politics” and instead “protect global collaboration whilst ensuring the needs of their citizens are met.”   Her comments follow a speech by Eva Maydell in Brussels yesterday, where the Bulgarian lawmaker urged Europe to “sober up” in its quest for tech independence.   “We need to have a very clear outline plan which, first and foremost,&#8230;<br /><br /><a href="https://thenextweb.com/news/europe-must-get-real-on-tech-sovereignty-and-stay-open-warns-industry-group?utm_source=social&#038;utm_medium=feed&#038;utm_campaign=profeed">This story continues</a> at The Next Web
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>TheNextWeb=1413639</id>
            <title>5 impressive feats of DeepMind’s new self-evolving AI coding agent</title>
            <link>https://thenextweb.com/news/5-feats-of-deepmind-ai-coding-agent-alphaevolve</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">TheNextWeb=1413639</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Wed, 14 May 2025 15:46:03 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <img height="417" src="https://img-cdn.tnwcdn.com/image?fit=796%2C417&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fcdn0.tnwcdn.com%2Fwp-content%2Fblogs.dir%2F1%2Ffiles%2F2025%2F05%2FAlphaEvolve-Ai-deepmind.jpg&amp;signature=cc4792d8285daf9a259b041fa0c31d05" width="796" /><br />Google DeepMind’s AI systems have taken big scientific strides in recent years — from predicting the 3D structures of almost every known protein in the universe to forecasting weather more accurately than ever before.  The UK-based lab today unveiled its latest advancement: AlphaEvolve, an AI coding agent that makes large language models (LLMs) like Gemini better at solving complex computing and mathematical problems.  AlphaEvolve is powered by the same models that it’s trying to improve. Using Gemini, the agent proposes programs — written in code — that try to solve a given problem. It runs each code snippet through automated&#8230;<br /><br /><a href="https://thenextweb.com/news/5-feats-of-deepmind-ai-coding-agent-alphaevolve?utm_source=social&#038;utm_medium=feed&#038;utm_campaign=profeed">This story continues</a> at The Next Web
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>TheNextWeb=1413621</id>
            <title>NATO backs Welsh startup building space factory for ‘supermaterials’</title>
            <link>https://thenextweb.com/news/nato-welsh-startup-space-forge-building-space-factory-supermaterials</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">TheNextWeb=1413621</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Wed, 14 May 2025 06:00:46 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <img height="417" src="https://img-cdn.tnwcdn.com/image?fit=796%2C417&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fcdn0.tnwcdn.com%2Fwp-content%2Fblogs.dir%2F1%2Ffiles%2F2025%2F05%2FForgeStar-1-.jpg&amp;signature=91f4c8a78f0e613cb7791e6523fb6e83" width="796" /><br />Welsh startup Space Forge has raised $30mn to advance its first commercial in-orbit manufacturing satellite, ForgeStar-2. The NATO Innovation Fund led the funding round, the largest Series A financing in UK space tech history. Space Forge’s demonstrator — the ForgeStar-1 — is set to launch from the US on a SpaceX rocket this year. The oven-sized satellite will then harness the conditions of space to produce “supermaterials” that are impossible to make on Earth. Joshua Western, Space Forge’s CEO and co-founder, compared the technology to a sourdough starter — a small but potent base for growing something much bigger. “Our&#8230;<br /><br /><a href="https://thenextweb.com/news/nato-welsh-startup-space-forge-building-space-factory-supermaterials?utm_source=social&#038;utm_medium=feed&#038;utm_campaign=profeed">This story continues</a> at The Next Web
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>TheNextWeb=1413587</id>
            <title>TNW Backstage goes Double Dutch on tech humour</title>
            <link>https://thenextweb.com/news/tnw-backstage-derek-mitchell-double-dutch-creator</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">TheNextWeb=1413587</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Wed, 14 May 2025 05:00:28 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <img height="417" src="https://img-cdn.tnwcdn.com/image?fit=796%2C417&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fcdn0.tnwcdn.com%2Fwp-content%2Fblogs.dir%2F1%2Ffiles%2F2025%2F05%2FUntitled-design-43.jpg&amp;signature=4cc76069fb6a58b520ceeefb76744127" width="796" /><br />TNW Backstage is going Double Dutch this week — in more ways than one. In the second episode of our new podcast, which goes behind the scenes of TNW Conference and the tech shaping our world, we’re joined by two special guests. Both of them are based in — you guessed it — the Netherlands. Together, they brew a distinctively orange blend of tech and humour, which has become a TNW trademark. One of them is content creator Derek Mitchell, the mind behind comedy brand Let’s Double Dutch. Mitchell’s viral videos exploring culture and identity in the Netherlands have earned global acclaim.&#8230;<br /><br /><a href="https://thenextweb.com/news/tnw-backstage-derek-mitchell-double-dutch-creator?utm_source=social&#038;utm_medium=feed&#038;utm_campaign=profeed">This story continues</a> at The Next Web
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>TheNextWeb=1413612</id>
            <title>Helsing’s AI submarine joins Europe’s growing ocean drone fleet</title>
            <link>https://thenextweb.com/news/helsings-ai-submarine-lura-europe-ocean-drone-defence</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">TheNextWeb=1413612</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Tue, 13 May 2025 13:31:57 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <img height="417" src="https://img-cdn.tnwcdn.com/image?fit=796%2C417&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fcdn0.tnwcdn.com%2Fwp-content%2Fblogs.dir%2F1%2Ffiles%2F2025%2F05%2FHelsing_lura-AI-submarine-ocean-drone.jpg&amp;signature=1c328eaf94d03cc2a3dbd4c8b1c507fd" width="796" /><br />Helsing, Europe’s best-funded defence tech startup, has unveiled its latest product — an autonomous mini-submarine for underwater reconnaissance.  Dubbed SG-1 Fathom, the sub is the latest addition to Europe’s growing fleet of ocean drones, which aim to better protect the continent’s ships and subsea infrastructure from surveillance, sabotage, and attacks.  The 1.95-metre Fathom is designed to slowly patrol the ocean for up to three months at a time. The vessel is powered by an AI platform called Lura. The system is a large acoustic model (LAM) — like a large language model (LLM) but for sound.  Lura is able to&#8230;<br /><br /><a href="https://thenextweb.com/news/helsings-ai-submarine-lura-europe-ocean-drone-defence?utm_source=social&#038;utm_medium=feed&#038;utm_campaign=profeed">This story continues</a> at The Next Web
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>TheNextWeb=1413595</id>
            <title>Neuralink rival Inbrain will ‘never’ take brain implants beyond healthcare</title>
            <link>https://thenextweb.com/news/neuralink-rival-inbrain-will-never-take-brain-implants-healthcare</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">TheNextWeb=1413595</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Mon, 12 May 2025 14:25:22 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    <img height="417" src="https://img-cdn.tnwcdn.com/image?fit=796%2C417&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fcdn0.tnwcdn.com%2Fwp-content%2Fblogs.dir%2F1%2Ffiles%2F2025%2F05%2FINBRAIN-neuralink-startup.jpg&amp;signature=1d876dd5a88fcd230bc136682c298815" width="796" /><br />Elon Musk has outlandish plans for Neuralink’s brain-computer interfaces, from giving people “superpowers” to downloading their memories. Spanish rival Inbrain Neuroelectronics has a simpler goal: improving our health — and nothing more. “I know Elon Musk might want to use Neuralink to drive a Tesla or something like that, but we will never go beyond therapeutic applications,” Carolina Aguilar, Inbrain’s CEO and co-founder, told TNW.   While Musk has captured headlines with futuristic ambitions for human enhancement, Inbrain has been steadily focused on developing its neural interfaces to treat neurological diseases. The company’s tech also stands apart. It’s built on the&#8230;<br /><br /><a href="https://thenextweb.com/news/neuralink-rival-inbrain-will-never-take-brain-implants-healthcare?utm_source=social&#038;utm_medium=feed&#038;utm_campaign=profeed">This story continues</a> at The Next Web
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>