<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <channel>
        <title>AVC</title>
        <link>https://avc.com/</link>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://avc.com/?p=20644</id>
            <title>I’ve Moved Onchain</title>
            <link>https://avc.com/2024/05/ive-moved-onchain/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://avc.com/?p=20644</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Thu, 02 May 2024 17:30:40 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    Over the last few years, I&#8217;ve moved my internet life from web2 to web3 and rarely use any web2 services anymore. So I am starting a series called &#8220;I&#8217;ve Moved Onchain&#8221; to explain this journey to everyone and today&#8217;s opening post is about blogging, naturally. I&#8217;ve blogged at AVC.com for a very long time. I [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://avc.com/?p=20638</id>
            <title>Transit Tech Lab</title>
            <link>https://avc.com/2024/01/transit-tech-lab/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://avc.com/?p=20638</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 13:49:57 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    The Partnership for NYC, alongside its partners at the MTA, the Port Authority of New York and New Jersey, NJ TRANSIT, and NYC Department of Transportation, launched a call for applications for the 6th annual Transit Tech Lab this week. To kick off this year’s program, the Transit Tech Lab is seeking early and growth-stage [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://avc.com/?p=20637</id>
            <title>Empire AI</title>
            <link>https://avc.com/2024/01/empire-ai/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://avc.com/?p=20637</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 15:05:06 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    Last summer I sat down with Tom Secunda, who co-founded Bloomberg LP with Mike Bloomberg, to talk about areas of shared philanthropic interest. Tom told me that academic institutions do not have access to the kind of AI/ML infrastructure that the top tech companies have and he wanted to fix that. His idea was a [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://avc.com/?p=20636</id>
            <title>Read Write Own</title>
            <link>https://avc.com/2024/01/read-write-own/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://avc.com/?p=20636</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 15:02:50 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    Chris Dixon, who leads the A16Z crypto fund, and has been an entrepreneur, VC, and friend of mine for over twenty years, has written a book called Read Write Own that is available for pre-order now and will start shipping at the end of the month. Chris gave me a copy right before the holidays [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://avc.com/?p=20633</id>
            <title>What Will Happen In 2024</title>
            <link>https://avc.com/2024/01/what-will-happen-in-2024/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://avc.com/?p=20633</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 15:31:06 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    As we enter 2024, the capital markets have found their footing and are moving higher. The Fed has taken interest rates as far as they want at this time and inflation has come down. It seems that a “soft landing” is likely. That is good news for the innovation economy because healthy capital markets are [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://avc.com/?p=20631</id>
            <title>What Happened In 2023</title>
            <link>https://avc.com/2023/12/what-happened-in-2023/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://avc.com/?p=20631</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 14:45:29 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    I like to bookend the New Year holiday with two posts, one looking back at the year that is ending (What Happened) and one looking forward to the year ahead (What Will Happen). This is the first of these two posts. The second one will run tomorrow. I ended my What Will Happen In 2023 [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://avc.com/?p=20627</id>
            <title>My Year-End Playlist</title>
            <link>https://avc.com/2023/12/my-year-end-playlist-2/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://avc.com/?p=20627</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 13:15:11 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    Every year I put together a playlist at the end of the year with some of the new music I found and got into. Most of these songs are under the radar which is my favorite kind of music. So I hope you find something new that you like in here.
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://avc.com/?p=20623</id>
            <title>Sleep</title>
            <link>https://avc.com/2023/10/sleep/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://avc.com/?p=20623</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 11:21:32 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    I got an Oura ring a couple of years ago and have been working on improving my sleep and sleep habits ever since. For much of my adult life, I have been a poor sleeper. I have always been able to fall asleep quickly, but I have been plagued by two sleep issues. The first [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://avc.com/?p=20618</id>
            <title>Open Office Hours at NYC Tech Week</title>
            <link>https://avc.com/2023/10/open-office-hours-at-nyc-tech-week/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://avc.com/?p=20618</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 10:21:05 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    NYC Tech Week is next week. It will be a week filled with events for the tech sector to engage and connect with each other. A particularly great part of tech week is VC Open Office Hours. There are over 100 VC investors signed up to participate next week. Here is how it works: 1/ [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://avc.com/?p=20614</id>
            <title>The Heist</title>
            <link>https://avc.com/2023/09/the-heist/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://avc.com/?p=20614</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 12:21:22 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    On Saturday, September 9th, the Gotham Gal and I arrived at JFK airport after an eight-hour flight from Paris. While waiting for our luggage, I got pushed a notification in my web3 wallet that there was an NFT drop underway that I could participate in. So I clicked on the link, signed the transaction, and [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>