<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <channel>
        <title>Startups | TechCrunch</title>
        <link>https://techcrunch.com/category/startups/</link>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://techcrunch.com/?p=3008397</id>
            <title>Y Combinator startup Firecrawl is ready to pay $1M to hire three AI agents as employees</title>
            <link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/05/17/y-combinator-startup-firecrawl-is-ready-to-pay-1m-to-hire-three-ai-agents-as-employees/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=3008397</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Sat, 17 May 2025 15:00:00 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    Y Combinator startup Firecrawl is back on the hunt for AI agent employees, after a previous attempt to hire one didn't go as planned.
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://techcrunch.com/?p=3008235</id>
            <title>AI startup Cohere acquires Ottogrid, a platform for conducting market research</title>
            <link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/05/16/ai-startup-cohere-acquires-ottogrid-a-platform-for-conducting-market-research/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=3008235</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Fri, 16 May 2025 19:57:53 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    AI startup Cohere has acquired Ottogrid, a Vancouver-based platform that develops enterprise tools for automating certain kinds of high-level market research. Sully Omar, one of the founders of Ottogrid, announced the deal Friday in a post on X. He didn&#8217;t disclose the terms. Ottogrid will sunset its product, according to Omar, but will give customers [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://techcrunch.com/?p=3008038</id>
            <title>The Nuclear Company raises $51M to develop massive reactor sites</title>
            <link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/05/16/the-nuclear-company-raises-51m-to-develop-massive-reactor-sites/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=3008038</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Fri, 16 May 2025 17:57:00 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    The funding round arrives as tech companies and utilities are struggling to secure power for data centers.
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://techcrunch.com/?p=3008057</id>
            <title>AI video startup Moonvalley lands $53M, according to filing</title>
            <link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/05/16/ai-video-startup-moonvalley-lands-53m-according-to-filing/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=3008057</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Fri, 16 May 2025 16:54:44 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    Roughly a month after Moonvalley, a Los Angeles-based startup developing AI tools for video creation, said it secured $43 million in new funding, the company has raised more, according to a filing with the SEC. The filing, submitted Thursday, reveals that Moonvalley actually landed (so far) around $53 million total from a group of 14 unnamed [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://techcrunch.com/?p=3003606</id>
            <title>TechCrunch and VivaTech partner for the VivaTech Innovation of the Year</title>
            <link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/05/16/techcrunch-and-vivatech-partner-for-the-vivatech-innovation-of-the-year/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=3003606</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Fri, 16 May 2025 16:00:00 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    TechCrunch is joining forces with VivaTech, Europe&#8217;s biggest startup and tech event, to select startups for the prestigious VivaTech Innovation of the Year at VivaTech 2025. This partnership will highlight exceptional creativity, technological ingenuity, and industry-transforming potential among exhibiting startups. The VivaTech Innovation of the Year Award acknowledges and celebrates exhibiting startups at VivaTech 2025 [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://techcrunch.com/?post_type=tc_podcast&p=3008106</id>
            <title>Is $1 billion a lot of money these days?</title>
            <link>https://techcrunch.com/podcast/is-1-billion-a-lot-of-money-these-days/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?post_type=tc_podcast&p=3008106</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Fri, 16 May 2025 15:13:29 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    Databricks just snatched up another AI company. This week, the data analytics giant announced a $1 billion acquisition of Neon, a startup building an open source alternative to AWS Aurora Postgres. It’s the latest in a spree of high-profile buys, joining MosaicML and Tabular, as Databricks positions itself as the place to build, deploy, and [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://techcrunch.com/?p=3007773</id>
            <title>Fake fired Twitter worker ‘Rahul Ligma’ is a real engineer with an AI data startup used by Harvard</title>
            <link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/05/15/fake-fired-twitter-worker-rahul-ligma-is-a-real-engineer-with-an-ai-data-startup-used-by-harvard/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=3007773</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Thu, 15 May 2025 21:35:07 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    The morning after Elon Musk&#8217;s 2022 acquisition of Twitter (now X), reporters encountered two men with boxes outside the company&#8217;s headquarters. One introduced himself as recently laid-off Twitter engineer &#8220;Rahul Ligma.&#8221;&#160; His real name is Rahul Sonwalkar but the prank went viral. While he never worked for X, he is actually very much a techy. [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://techcrunch.com/?p=3007568</id>
            <title>Sprinter Health raises $55M to expand its at-home healthcare service</title>
            <link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/05/15/sprinter-health-raises-55m-to-expand-its-at-home-healthcare-service/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=3007568</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Thu, 15 May 2025 20:40:48 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    The Series B was led by General Catalyst, with Andreessen Horowitz, Regents of the University of California, Google Ventures, and Accel also investing.
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://techcrunch.com/?p=3007061</id>
            <title>Startups Weekly: A brighter outlook, but don’t get carried away</title>
            <link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/05/15/startups-weekly-a-brighter-outlook-but-dont-get-carried-away/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=3007061</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Thu, 15 May 2025 18:29:03 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    Welcome to Startups Weekly — your weekly recap of everything you can’t miss from the world of startups. Want it in your inbox every Friday? Sign up here. Startup news this week was fairly routine — in a good way: Aside from a minor kerfuffle between Y Combinator and Google, there was no headline-grabbing drama. [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://techcrunch.com/?p=3007071</id>
            <title>Host a tailored Side Event at All Stage 2025 in Boston</title>
            <link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/05/15/host-a-tailored-side-event-at-all-stage-2025-in-boston/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=3007071</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Thu, 15 May 2025 15:00:00 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    Looking to make a splash at TechCrunch All Stage 2025? Our Side Events initiative is a fantastic opportunity to engage with Boston&#8217;s tech community in a dynamic and memorable manner. Plus, we&#8217;ll assist in promoting your event at no cost to you! Submit your event here by June 10. Throw your own Side Event at [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://techcrunch.com/?p=3007417</id>
            <title>Bain bets on Indian domestic work startup Pronto even as rivals face criticism</title>
            <link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/05/15/bain-bets-on-indian-domestic-work-startup-pronto-even-as-rivals-face-criticism/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=3007417</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Thu, 15 May 2025 15:00:00 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    Pronto, which provides cleaning, laundry and home services within 10 minutes, has raised $2M at a $12.5M valuation.
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://techcrunch.com/?p=3007173</id>
            <title>Acorns acquires family wealth and digital memory platform EarlyBird</title>
            <link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/05/15/acorns-acquires-family-wealth-and-digital-memory-platform-earlybird/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=3007173</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Thu, 15 May 2025 13:00:00 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    Savings and investing startup Acorns has acquired EarlyBird, an investment gifting platform for families, the company told TechCrunch exclusively. The financial terms of the deal were not disclosed. As part of the acquisition, EarlyBird will shut down, and all customer accounts will officially close on June 23. Customers&#8217; funds will be returned to the bank [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://techcrunch.com/?post_type=tc_podcast&p=3007320</id>
            <title>Unpacking Rippling vs Deel: corporate espionage and a $16.8B plot twist</title>
            <link>https://techcrunch.com/podcast/unpacking-rippling-vs-deel-corporate-espionage-and-a-16-8b-plot-twist/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?post_type=tc_podcast&p=3007320</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Wed, 14 May 2025 18:15:09 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    Despite courtroom chaos, Rippling is still going full steam ahead. The HR tech startup at the center of an increasingly dramatic legal battle with rival Deel just raised a fresh $450 million in funding at a $16.8 billion valuation, and launched a new “Startup Stack” to woo early-stage companies — winning over Y Combinator as [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://techcrunch.com/?p=3006976</id>
            <title>Tensor9 helps vendors deploy their software into any environment using digital twins</title>
            <link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/05/14/tensor9-helps-vendors-deploy-their-software-into-any-environment-using-digital-twins/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=3006976</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Wed, 14 May 2025 13:02:40 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    Enterprises want access to new software and AI tools but can&#8217;t risk sending their sensitive data out to a third-party software-as-a-service (SaaS) providers. Tensor9 looks to help software companies land more enterprise customers by helping them deploy their software directly into a customer&#8217;s tech stack. Tensor9 converts a software vendor&#8217;s code into the format needed [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://techcrunch.com/?p=3006912</id>
            <title>$25B-valued Chime files for an IPO, reveals $33M deal with Dallas Mavericks</title>
            <link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/05/13/25b-valued-chime-files-for-an-ipo-reveals-33m-deal-with-dallas-mavericks/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=3006912</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Tue, 13 May 2025 22:21:36 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    At long last, digital consumer bank Chime has moved forward with its IPO by filing its S-1 paperwork Tuesday. Chime had reportedly filed confidential S-1 paperwork back in December. S-1 filings typically reveal all kinds of information, covering financial, legal, and other risk factors. But Chime’s S-1 documents still have a lot of blank spaces. [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://techcrunch.com/?p=3006837</id>
            <title>Anthropic, Google score win by nabbing OpenAI-backed Harvey as a user</title>
            <link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/05/13/anthropic-google-score-win-by-nabbing-openai-backed-harvey-as-a-user/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=3006837</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Tue, 13 May 2025 20:30:42 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    Popular legal AI tool Harvey will now be using leading foundation models from Anthropic and Google, moving beyond strictly using OpenAI&#8217;s, Harvey announced in a blog post on Tuesday. This is noteworthy because Harvey is one of the OpenAI Startup Fund’s most successful early-backed portfolio companies. The OpenAI Startup Fund is an OpenAI-associated fund to [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://techcrunch.com/?p=3006811</id>
            <title>Y Combinator says Google is a ‘monopolist’ that has ‘stunted’ the startup ecosystem</title>
            <link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/05/13/y-combinator-says-google-is-a-monopolist-that-has-stunted-the-startup-ecosystem/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=3006811</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Tue, 13 May 2025 19:09:12 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    Fabled startup investor and accelerator Y Combinator has some choice words for Google in an amicus brief it just submitted in the U.S.&#8217;s monopoly case against the search giant. In the brief, YC charged that Google is a “monopolist” that has &#8220;stunted&#8221; the U.S. startup ecosystem by making VC firms like itself hesitate to fund [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://techcrunch.com/?p=3006504</id>
            <title>UP.Labs-Porsche’s newest startup wants to be the Plaid of automotive retail</title>
            <link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/05/13/up-labs-porsches-newest-startup-wants-to-be-the-plaid-of-automotive-retail/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=3006504</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Tue, 13 May 2025 17:08:18 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    As serial entrepreneur Joel Milne founded, scaled, and then successfully sold mobile auto repair service startup RepairSmith to AutoNation, he was plagued by a persistent problem.&#160; The automotive retail industry has a communication problem. And it&#8217;s an expensive one. Thousands of dealerships and mechanic shops — each one with an array of software systems — [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://techcrunch.com/?p=3006291</id>
            <title>At TechCrunch All Stage 2025, Rob Biederman will help founders rethink how to scale</title>
            <link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/05/13/at-techcrunch-all-stage-2025-rob-biederman-will-help-founders-rethink-how-to-scale/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=3006291</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Tue, 13 May 2025 14:06:00 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    If you’re a founder looking to grow your startup, chances are you’re wrestling with more than just product or capital. Talent, scale, and smart execution are the real battlegrounds. That’s exactly what TechCrunch All Stage 2025 is built to address on July 15 at Boston’s SoWa Power Station. See top startup leaders taking the stage [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <id>https://techcrunch.com/?p=3006251</id>
            <title>Insurtech Bestow lands $120M Series D from Goldman Sachs, Smith Point Capital</title>
            <link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/05/13/insurtech-bestow-lands-120m-series-d-from-goldman-sachs-smith-point-capital/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=3006251</guid>
            <pubDate></pubDate>
            <updated>Tue, 13 May 2025 12:45:00 +0000</updated>
                
                
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    
                    Melbourne O&#8217;Banion co-founded insurtech Bestow with Jonathan Abelmann in 2017 after struggling to secure his own life insurance policy. His goal was to make it easier for people to obtain life insurance and make the process more tech-enabled. Initially, Bestow operated as a direct-to-consumer insurance provider &#8212; selling, underwriting, and servicing life insurance policies. In [&#8230;]
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>